Hold your Down.
Good.
Hey everybody,
welcome to the
home theater.
thank you for
watching Backfire,
the Xcommunication story
of Tim Ballard.
A lot of
you know that
we put the
first three episodes
out already many
months ago that
was on purpose
and strategic so
that we could
do a sort
of A-B
testing and see
how people would
The people I
was targeting are
people who felt
to go into
the camp of
my enemy.
So we'd see
what they would
say so we
can defeat it
now and that's
what I'm going
to do to
start off with
this introduction.
People like Greg
Matsin of Zwik
and Hayden Paul
of the Stick
of Joseph,
they attempted this.
What they do
is they build
strong men arguments
against me.
If you don't
know what strong
men argument is,
that's when you
are dishonest and
you put words
in my mouth.
So I look
crazy or narcissist
or whatever they
want to say
and then they
knock it down
and think they
did their job.
Well I'm like
I let them
get away with
that and now
that I have
exposed them and
now I'm ready
to put out
all of it.
So let me
tell you what
the two main
strong men arguments
are.
these
to.
The first one
is that I
am just a
crazy liar,
mad,
vendetta,
and I'm spewing
lies about satanic
ritual abuse.
I've been very
clear in my
position.
I am the
first one to
defend those who
have been falsely
accused of satanic
ritual abuse.
While at the
same time acknowledging
that there are
many cases where
it's true,
the bottom line
is it doesn't
matter.
You'll hear me
talk about this.
All abuse of
children is satanic.
And that's what
I'm going to
talk about.
It's just that.
If you don't
think there have
been cover-ups,
if you don't
think there has
been efforts made
to silence people,
which means they
don't get the
care they need,
then you're just
not paying attention.
but stop with
the lies you're
putting in my
mouth.
I'm not gonna
stand for that.
Also,
the people that
did this to
me,
this is very
important.
This is not
a condemnation of
the church that
I love.
I'm more active
now than ever.
I believe in
the foundational scriptures
and the un
-luquormed version of
the gospel of
Jesus Christ more
than ever.
And my family
and I are
very,
very active still.
This is very
important.
This is not
about the church.
This is about
people inside who
did something.
And you're gonna
hear about the
process.
That's the main
point of this.
The process that
they decided deliberately
to utilize and
how they violated
just decency.
But more importantly,
the words of
Jesus Christ over
and over again.
You're gonna hear
me say throughout
this program
the phrase how
they did it
tells you why
they did it.
Okay,
because how they
did it,
when you're violating
everything and violating
the scriptures over
and over and
over again,
that means there's
a big why.
Now,
what is that
why?
I am not
going to attempt
to define that.
You can try
to decide why
not because this
was salad off,
very salad off.
I do not
blame the brethren.
I know for
a fact that
the brethren,
I'm talking about
the top 12
in brethren,
they were kept
in the dark.
I know that
for a fact.
So,
I am not
going to try
to attempt to
define the why
other than the
fact that there
is a why.
You don't do
these things for
nothing.
The why might
be different depending
on who in
the salad off
group was there
and what their
intentions were.
But according to
Alexander Hamilton,
this is very
important.
The moment he
says,
the moment we
launch into conjectures
about the secret
rules of the
heart as the
motives,
we shall find
ourselves lost in
the labyrinth of
unfounded and hasty
conclusions.
the
for you to
determine,
but clearly the
Y is significant
and disturbing.
You don't do
these things for
nothing.
The second strum
in argument that
these people who
stepped into the
camp of my
enemy put forth
is this is
some kind of
tantrum that I'm
just swinging back
because they didn't
do what I
wanted.
What do you
think I wanted?
They have nothing.
The people that
do this to
me have nothing
that I want.
Nothing.
They reduced my
membership into a
country club card.
And as a
country club I
would never join,
not with this
state president as
the Gulf Pro.
This will make
sense as you
watch.
So they took
nothing from me.
They couldn't touch
my covenants.
But the most
offensive thing that
they did.
Truly probably the
worst sin I've
ever seen and
coming from someone
like me who
sees and works
in what I
do is significant.
They,
the people who
pretend,
who claim to
be the ones
who are supposed
to be there
and
and service and
facilitate the covenants
you make with
your saviour,
those people deliberately
decided to take
my sacred covenants
with my Savior
Jesus Christ and
use them as
a political football,
as a poker
chip,
in some twisted
game from their
own interests.
And my response
to that has
not been a
tantrum.
In fact,
as a source
page for everything
you're going to
see in these
episodes,
I'm going to
attach the appeals
letter we sent
immediately,
and then you're
going to see
another letter from
March of 2025.
In that letter,
I told them
very clearly,
either you do
this quietly together
and we clean
this up together,
quietly,
or I'm going
to get loud.
I'm going to
get loud.
I don't think
they believed me,
but here we
are.
That was over
a year ago,
everybody.
This has been
measured.
deliberate.
I have given
them every opportunity
to be Matthew
18 compliant.
You hear me
say this a
lot.
Let me tell
you again what
this is.
This isn't something
that you can
just cast aside.
These are the
words of Jesus
Christ on the
the the the
mount of Beatitudes,
the Sermon on
the Mount.
He says,
you must go
to your brother.
You must go
to your brother
when allegations come
about.
These people never
went to me.
Ever from day
one to the
present.
They did this
all behind my
back.
And this is
me finally calling
them out.
It's fine.
going take it
to the world
then because I
know that I
am right.
And I know
that they are
wrong.
I tried to
be quiet.
If I wasn't
a tantrum state,
I would have
done this two
years ago.
I have to
be Matthew 18
compliant as well.
So I offered
them this opportunity,
this scriptural opportunity.
But Matthew 18
and Matthew 5
tell you that
if they refuse
the offer over
and over again.
At some point
you call them
heathens and publicans
and you shout
from the rooftop
what's going on
in Matthew 5
is very clear
that people could
end up losing
everything if they're
not Matthew 18
compliant,
including their own
freedom.
In some cases
that I think
will be the
result of this.
So this is
not some tantrum.
This is something
Catherine and I
prayed,
fasted,
cried over.
We didn't want
to do this,
but they started
this war.
Make no mistake.
I had no
issues with them.
I loved them.
I thought they
loved me.
This was out
of the blue.
Attack me with
lies and defamation.
Okay,
why?
You determined that.
But they did
that.
They came to
the battlefield and
I said,
I don't want
to come out.
Let's do this
quietly.
Let's talk.
Let's get Matthew
18 compliant.
They refused every
offer for over
two years.
Even after I
sent the final
letter in March
of 2025,
I gave them
a whole year
even after that.
And they still
refused to come
to the table
in violation of
the words of
Jesus Christ.
This is not
okay.
Another thing I
want to talk
about since we're
talking about Jesus
Christ.
Even if I
were guilty and
I want to
state unequivocally,
I am not
guilty of these
things.
Even though I'm
winning in court,
people could still
say,
but did you
do something?
No.
I did nothing
that would even
hit at the
necessity of having
a disciplinary counsel,
which there never
was one really,
as you'll see.
So I want
to make that
very clear.
My wife is
stood by me
this entire time
and she stands
by me today.
Okay,
so no of
that.
But let's talk
about Jesus since
we're talking about
Jesus and what
he said.
if I were
guilty.
Even if I
were guilty.
We have a
scriptural precedent for
situations like this.
Even if I
were guilty.
What did Jesus
do with the
woman of the
well?
Or the woman
who was about
to be stoned,
who had committed
crimes of adultery?
Can you imagine
a scenario where
our Lord and
Savior Jesus Christ
would have run
to the Jerusalem
press after speaking
and
publicly for it.
Even if I
were guilty,
there is no
excuse for this,
unless these people
don't believe in
Jesus Christ,
or they don't
read the scriptures,
or perhaps they
read them and
don't understand them.
These are pretty
difficult things not
to understand.
They're almost impossible
to misinterpret these
mandates from Jesus.
And yet that's
what they did.
These people,
these infiltrators within.
That's what they
did.
That is not
okay.
That's even if
I were guilty.
But the truth
is I was
never guilty,
which makes it
about a million
times worse.
So,
we will not
let these straw
men argument stand.
There's no tantrum.
This is measured,
deliberate,
prayerful,
and giving an
abundance of time
for these people
to do the
right thing.
and they have
chosen not to.
so now they
will face the
consequence that I
told them I
would do,
which is to
go public now.
Why?
And then the
other one,
of course,
like I said,
the other strawman
is that this
is about me
and making up
lies about SRA.
has nothing to
do with this.
This has to
do with a
process that they
carried out in
contradiction of everything
Jesus Christ taught
us.
That's what this
is about.
I want to
also speak for
my wife,
Catherine.
She's been putting
out her own
interviews and posts
about her experience
here.
But for her,
I want to
say something,
because this is
important,
at no part
in this process
where we ever
treated by these
people,
not by the
church in general,
by these people,
not once where
we treated like
human beings,
far less like
children of God.
No,
we were just
objects,
ponds,
in these people's
hands,
ponds,
to be played
with,
names to be
manipulated for their
own purposes.
And when they
made the decision
to defame and
lie and violate
every word of
Jesus,
when they made
that decision,
they knew darn
well that this
was going to
hurt the efforts,
the honest legitimate
efforts to rescue
children.
They did it
on purpose.
They knew that
would be the
consequence and they
voted for it
anyway.
And that's one
reason we have
to come out
now.
I cannot go
before my maker
and said I
was afraid to
do this because
the lie which
you'll refer,
which I will
refer to as
the Doug Anderson
lie.
He's the PR
representative of the
church who put
his name on
this.
That lie has
been used by
traffickers and terrorists
even after we
filmed backfire.
After I warned
them what would
happen,
ISIS took the
Doug Anderson lie
to use it
to hurt our
efforts to rescue
the Jews and
Christians in Syria.
I'm going to
say that again,
ISIS and their
propagandists used the
Doug Anderson lie.
Enough is enough.
This is why
I'm going public.
If they're going
to keep their
lie out on
the internet like
they have chosen
to do,
then I will
combat it with
the truth.
So we no
longer give the
common enemy to
mankind,
traffickers and terrorists
any more fodder
with which to
attack our sacred
work.
And speaking of
sacred work,
I want to
say one more
thing.
It's not only
me and my
family and my
children who were
just treated as
nonhumans as objects
to be played
with,
but more importantly,
the personages of
Jesus Christ and
His suffering children
were also used
as non-entities,
as just something
to be manipulated,
something to be
cast aside,
and for that
reason,
and mostly that
we are giving
you backfire,
the excommunication of
Tim Ballard,
so that you
us
people that we
might restore the
integrity and the
words of Jesus
Christ apply them
accurately so that
we can under
his authority fix
this and rescue
God's children.
Thank you and
enjoy backfire.
People inside the
LDS church.
The church that
I was raised
in that I
gave everything to
betrayed me in
the worst way.
They also betrayed
my best friend,
President Emmerlund Bellard.
And all this
to cover up
what?
Child abuse?
Trafficking around the
world?
Find out what
they did because
how they did
it tells you
exactly why they
did it.
Today is October
1st,
2025.
It's the day
of atonement.
That's a very
significant day today
of repentance and
forgiveness.
And it's with
that spirit that
I hope to
come to you
today.
Not one of
vengeance,
forgiveness,
the spirit that
Jesus said on
the cross,
they know not
what they do
for,
forgive them,
father.
The day of
Atonement also significant,
it's the only
day in the
biblical law where
excommunications are forbidden.
I believe that
God still speaks
to us through
such symbolisms.
And on September
25th,
2023,
because the Jewish
calendar changes.
That was also
the day of
Atonement.
And it was
the day that
certain individuals dared
to lie,
to cheat,
to work with
tabloid magazines,
defame many people,
and excommunicate me.
People inside the
LDS Church tried
to excommunicate me
according to them
they have done
that.
On the day
of Atonement,
September 25th,
2023,
I'm not speaking,
however,
on my behalf,
I'm speaking on
behalf of those
who were hurt
by that decision.
My wife,
who was brutalized
by people through
this,
my children,
my sweet children,
who were told
to believe that
they no longer
will live together
forever with their
father,
so deal with
it.
but
that countless children
have not been
rescued because of
these lies.
Because of what
I will call
the order of
the Luke warms,
those who use
the name of
Jesus Christ,
his church,
to work evil.
I've said this
from the beginning
and I'll say
it again,
I would rather
be guilty of
those false accusations
than be guilty
of what he
and others did,
to use the
name of Jesus
Christ to violate
Scripture.
And we will
go over all
of this and
detailed the mental
gymnastics that these
people must play
now to justify
their evil acts,
really what they're
doing is asswaging
their own guilt.
The condemnation that
they have taken
upon themselves leads
me only with
hope for them
and true forgiveness.
I explain to
you in the
upper room,
last week in
Jerusalem,
truth
happening right now
because of these
evil Workings there
is a mass
conspiracy there are
criminal and civil
investigations at multiple
countries and it
all boils down
to what these
people these These
lukewarm watchmen on
the tower.
I don't mean
to be Demenium
when I say
lukewarm.
This is a
scriptural principle.
You cannot use
the name of
Jesus Christ to
hurt Jesus Christ
and While I
was speaking I
don't know how
they're dealing with
this right now
But they must
not like it
as I was
speaking in the
upper room and
I began to
explain the scriptural
principle Speaking through
the Church of
how the lukewarm
gets spit out
because they use
Jesus's name a
voice appeared a
heavenly voice appeared
That there's hot
and there's cold
You're that the
eyes and said
deliver the rights
In fact,
I didn't say
this but I'll
say it now
Isolate it the
videos there for
you isolate the
voice what he
actually said was
Tim Tim do
it deliver the
rights and I
intend to do
that and this
is phase one
in doing that
It's phase one
in the commencement
of what we
and many other
government
around the world
are calling Operation
Milestone.
They tried to
excommunicate me and
hurt children.
They knew they
were going to
do that.
But what they
didn't count on
with Jesus Christ,
ironically.
And I tell
you now that
what I will
say is in
the name of
Jesus Christ.
I want to
add a very
important disclaimer.
Though you will
learn through this
story that President
Nelson's name was
used in vain
by the state
president and by
others,
he did not
know this was
happening.
This happened behind
his back.
I sustain him
now and forever
as a prophet
of our Lord
and Savior Jesus
Christ.
And you will
learn that he
was appalled at
the workings of
the area president,
Kevin Pearson,
the state president,
and those involved,
the PR committee.
You will learn
the truth about
what really happened
and how so
many names were
used in vain.
But most severely
the name of
Jesus Christ.
Divine law is
dependable.
incontrovertible.
Please pay attention
very carefully to
what I'm going
to say.
I cannot lie
right now.
I cannot.
What I have,
what I'm going
to say,
I have said
or will say
under oath,
lawsuits are dropping.
I can't say
something that I
can't back up.
This is too
serious.
This is a
major conspiracy against
the United States
government,
against governments around
the world.
And when I
tell you the
facts,
you will know
that what I'm
saying is true.
Pray for the
souls of the
people who did
this.
It is a
long,
long road back
when you use
the name of
Jesus Christ to
hurt children.
What do they
say about this
voice in the
upper room?
I wonder.
I can guess
they're saying it's
the devil.
I hope they
are because that
makes it easier
to identify who
they are in
the scriptural account.
For the same
people and the
same spirit under
the lukewarm also
said that the
miracles accompanying our
were
devil.
So I welcome
them to say
it.
It'll be easier
to identify who
they are and
pray for them
that they may
humble their hearts
and not continue
to drink condemnation
to their souls.
This story begins
with a true
watchman on the
tower,
an amazing person,
a Christ-like
man,
Elder M.
Russell Ballard,
who died as
the president of
the Cormor of
the Twelve Apostles.
He was my
best friend.
He would tell
you that.
He was like
a grandpa to
me.
He would tell
you that as
well.
In October of
2016,
before many people
even knew who
I was.
In the presence
of a brother,
a fellow brother
and volunteer servant
to President Ballard,
I was given
a priesthood blessing.
Now this blessing
was repeated many
times by President
Ballard.
Many people in
our close circle
knew about this.
He said two
significant things.
In 2016,
he said within
10 years to
him,
you will be
a household name
and the gates
of hell will
open up against
you.
Who could have
predicted such a
thing at that
time?
Few people knew
who I was
in 2016,
but within 10
years,
certainly sound of
freedom came out.
Sound of Freedom
has become one
of the biggest
box office hits
of the year,
ranking in over
$140 million across
the US.
And Sound of
Freedom was a
blockbuster success,
as you know,
and it opened
the doors to
rescue so many
children.
And it happened.
In fact,
Elder Bellard was
calling me.
Weeks before people
in the church
would lie to
you and say
that he cut
me off.
He didn't cut
They lied.
They said in
their horrible,
horrible,
evil defamatory statement,
they said that
Elder Bellard cut
me off for
having used his
name to do
immoral things.
Isn't it funny
how the projection
manifests here?
That's exactly what
they did.
They used his
name,
the name of
an apostle of
Jesus Christ,
to do immoral
things against me
and children by
suggesting that he
would have done
something so devilish
as to cut
off his best
friend.
Not talk to
him.
Not say a
word to him.
Just cut him
off.
without
him,
he learns about
it for the
first time how
through a tabloid
magazine.
Yes,
Doug Anderson,
the PR voice,
the representative of
the church,
decided with representatives
of Jesus Christ
to lie about
Elder Ballard,
me,
and send it
to a tabloid
magazine that's pro
-patter file and
anti-mormon.
Tell me your
guilty without telling
me your guilty
with that act
alone.
Who are these
people?
Why would they
do this?
What effects has
it had?
Well,
let me tell
you the story.
Elder Ballard was
calling me in
August of 2023,
having not cut
me off.
Still my best
friend,
saying,
Tim,
do you remember
the prophecy that
I gave you
that you would
be a household
name?
A hundred million
people have seen
this film,
and we kind
of joked about
what the jaws
of hell are
going to look
like.
I don't think
either of us,
I don't from
the very church
that he represented,
from the very
who
be the voice
of Jesus Christ.
But sure enough,
it was.
As I explained
in the upper
room,
what was going
on in August
2023 was very
significant.
Sound of freedom
had made over
$250 million.
100 million people
had seen it.
I just met
with President Trump
at Betminster and
his people.
They asked me
to run for
the U.S.
Senate seat being
made available that
was going to
be in conjunction
with President Trump
running in the
2024 election.
Also,
and probably the
most significant part
of this was
that Kevin McCartney,
the speaker of
the House,
had come to
me and said,
what can we
do?
We saw the
film.
We want to
do something.
And I said,
let's propose this
sound of freedom
act,
which will give
moral authority to
start with,
to be able
to expose three
areas of deep,
deep sin against
children.
trafficking
the border to
child abuse,
which has his
base,
unfortunately,
in Utah,
and three,
the trafficking in
the foster care
system.
So let's do
it.
And President Trump
asked me to
run for Senate.
So I'll do
that.
We have the
sound of freedom
act.
We have the
moral authority coming
from sound of
freedom.
I went on
the Sean Spicer
show.
Instead,
I'm doing all
these things.
The next day
I received a
phone call saying
to him,
they're not gonna
let you run
for Senate.
They're not gonna
let you win.
let you implement
the sound of
freedom act.
There's too much
of state care.
And $10 million,
she said,
had been sent
to destroy my
life.
I said,
what will it
look like?
He says,
I don't know,
but it'll be
a bag of
bricks.
We will deliver
the rights.
And this video
is phase one
of Operation Milestone
and our efforts
to deliver the
rights.
Now,
where is the
story?
get to get
back to this.
It reflects an
idea present in
the Bible and
American legal philosophy
that God given
rights should be
protected and delivered
to everyone,
especially those that
magnetize,
I love Elder
Ballard.
He is a
true watchman.
He is my
brother.
friend.
He has been
with us in
miraculous ways these
last two years.
And I am
very much sticking
for him as
well as for
the Savior when
I tell the
truth about what
happened.
He did prophesy
and his prophecies
did come true.
And so in
preparation and expectation
of that prophecy
of Elder Ballard
being fulfilled,
we must ask
who shot the
first bullet?
The next day
I received a
phone call saying
Tim,
they not going
to let you
run for senate.
They not going
to let you
win.
They not going
to let you
implement this on
a freedom act.
There is too
much of a
stake here.
And $10 million,
he said,
had been sent
to destroy my
life.
I said what
will it look
like?
He says I
don't know but
it will be
a bag of
bricks.
I have been
a satisplinder oath.
I know these
things are true.
What I tell
you is documented.
How far did
it go?
Who's involved?
I'm going to
name names,
okay?
I have no
choice at this
point because I
would be under
condemnation from our
Savior if I
did not.
These people used
his name in
vain and hurt
children.
I can't imagine
anything that would
offend our Lord
and Savior Jesus
Christ more than
this,
but they did
it.
And they continue
to do it
to this day.
Everything I'm telling
you there,
you know.
And they've chosen
not to even
respond,
which is why
I have to
respond.
I'm looking around
where's it going
to come from,
what's going to
happen?
In the meantime,
I have to
go to Boston
because I am
there,
ironically,
to preach and
teach about the
Book of Mormon,
how it complements
American history and
the message of
the Covenants on
the world,
on the land
of the House
of Israel.
And I am
there in September
14th and I
get an email
from Vice Magazine
who has been
pounding me for
years.
And they sent
me this note.
It's a quote
from a man
named Doug Anderson,
a man who
I will sue
into oblivion.
I read this
lie.
dishonest.
it's laughable.
It says that
I used Elder
Ballard's name in
vain,
the man who
I just spoke
to weeks earlier,
that I used
his name in
vain to do
immoral things.
I want to
call President Ballard.
Friday,
on the Friday
afternoon,
just after that
statement came out.
So,
he picks up
and I just
talked to him
and I said,
I said Elder
Ballard,
we what is
the statement?
And he said,
what statement?
And I said,
there's this statement
out in the
news that the
church is against
him and that
you are against
him or,
you know,
I can't remember
the exact wording
and paraphrasing and
he said,
but I remember,
he said this,
well,
I know nothing
about that.
What are you
talking about?
Where is this?
And I said,
I think it's
everywhere.
That's what I'm
hearing.
It's like in
Deseret,
it's like everywhere.
And he said,
well,
I don't know
anything
about
And you said,
unfortunately,
it's Friday afternoon,
and everyone has
gone home for
the weekend.
But when I
go back to
the church office
buildings,
when I go
back to my
office,
I will look
into this and
I will figure
it out.
And he said,
keep your head
up.
We love you.
I'll figure this
out.
And that just,
that,
that was all
I needed to
hear.
It also said
that I never,
the Tim Ballard
never did any
projects associated with
the church.
They have made
about four million
dollars just in
books alone with
the church publication
arm desert book.
I spoke on
their stage.
I if you
read this book,
the book of
Mormon,
if there's a
couple things that
want you to
know,
is it angels
or real?
I worked with
Elder Rennlin and
he won't deny
this face to
face in Haiti,
helping him.
I worked with
Elder Rennlin on
consulting and charitable
giving.
along
Ubank.
I worked with
Elder Bednar.
He asked me
to come to
his office and
consult on writing
the dedicated prayer
for the Port
of Prince Hayley
Temple and then
invited me to
be there with
him.
I provided security
for him at
the request of
the Security Department
and Elder Bednar
and Elder Ballard.
I think these
are projects associated
with the church.
Don't you?
And to cover
up my association
and projects,
here is what
they did.
The Church of
Jesus Christ of
Latter-day Saints
has now removed
articles promoting Tim
Ballard and the
nonprofit he founded,
Operation Underground Railroad.
The articles were
removed on the
same day the
Church released a
statement citing betrayal
and condemning Ballard.
You know,
there's a hero
in this story.
Another hero named
Russell Brunson.
When he saw
the statement come
out,
he has a
lot of followers.
He has lots
of losers.
Active member of
the Church.
Click frontels.
He came out
right away and
said,
I know that
statement's a lie
because Elder Ballard
called me.
Russell Brunson to
come down and
a
a associated with
the church.
It's interesting because
the way that
I found out
about Tim Ballard
and Operation Organic
Road was actually
from Elder Ballard.
He personally called
me and asked
me to help
Tim Ballard in
Operation Organic Road.
I have literally
sat in the
rooms with Elder
Ballard and Tim
Ballard as we
discussed these things
and these ideas.
so I want
to start with,
again,
these are not
my stories to
tell,
but just to
let you know
that the accusations
that they're being
made on the
media are not
true.
And I've just
come from someone
who literally,
I've been in
the rooms with
him and Elder
Ballard talking about
these things,
okay?
I've been in
the rooms.
Elder Ballard is
one of your
leaders to me.
Tim never came
to me and
told me some
big story.
Elder Ballard and
I tried get
me in.
It was the
opposite way around.
Okay,
so fully unionic.
This is the
way it's actually
working.
This is the
actual truth.
Not some rogue
employee who got
fired because they
were about at
their job lying
behind between the
teeth.
what literally the
sources are.
If you look
at where they're
getting this stuff,
like it's ridiculous.
Did Matt Holland
and the others
on the PR
committee not know
about those projects?
I know they
did because I
hand in my
book one day
when he was
the president of
UVU.
I handed my
book to Matt
Holland.
He knew I
did project associate
with the church.
Did he approve
this message?
Did the other
apostles who say
don't that committee?
Did they approve
this message?
This lie to
go out to
a tabloid?
I don't know.
We'll find out
through deposition and
possibly through criminal
investigations as the
truth comes out.
This is not
a new cycle
that ends tomorrow,
guys.
This is a
new cycle that
will never end.
Lionsgate is doing
a docu-series,
sound of freedom
to the script
is being written.
Only see this
kid's faces.
Kevin Pearson,
the area of
present,
I'll get to
him,
the state president,
people like Matt
Holland,
people like Doug
Anderson,
they are literally
being casted right
now in the
film.
100 million people,
sound of freedom,
one.
I guess two
to 300 million
will watch this
one because of
the severe abuse
that happened by
these people.
And so back
at Boston,
I'm reading this
lie.
I know it's
It's ridiculous.
My wife is
telling me that
she were laughing.
Like this is,
they're trying to
bait me in
saying something bad
about the church.
and I'm not
gonna do it.
Ha ha ha.
But I just
thought to myself,
just in case
I'm gonna call
the person who
is the director
of reputational management
for the church,
because I know
that if someone
in the church,
some deep state
elements push this
out to the
public,
I knew the
disaster it would
be.
Reputationally,
once we have
this day,
once we're sitting
here on the
day of Atonement,
two years later
telling the story,
I knew it
would be a
disaster for them.
And so I
called him,
his name's Derek
Westre.
And I made
sure,
as I did
everything I talked
to you about,
I'm a criminal
investigator by trade.
Everything I say
is documented.
has witnesses.
Everything,
everything,
everything.
So just know
that.
So I had
a witness on
the phone with
me.
This was late
in the evening,
Eastern Standard Time,
Derek Westre gets
on the phone.
And he,
like me,
is kind of
laughing at this.
He says,
there's no way
this came from
the church to
him.
And he gave
me three reasons
why he knew.
One,
he said it's
lie,
and the church
would never lie
about one of
his members.
Two,
he said Elder
Ballard wouldn't just
betray you in
of
and decency.
And three,
he said,
Doug Anderson would
never defame a
member of church
without talking to
me because I
am the director
of Repetational Management.
And this would
be my mess
to clean up
someday.
I've read my
books in defense
of the gospel,
blood,
sweat,
and tears for
the gospel.
I've paid tithing
righteously,
continuously,
even till this
day I haven't
stopped.
Okay,
they can't stop
me from leaving
my covers with
a lie.
All right,
I still wear
my garments,
guys.
I take the
sacrament,
call the police
if you'd like.
It's not gonna
work.
I did not
commit these crimes.
commit these moral
accusations.
great Satan is
the accuser.
Eduardo Varastagi is
also suing the
producer of Senator
Freedom,
potentially the next
president of Mexico.
This will shake,
rather,
and roll the
world.
What they've done
to me,
because it wasn't
to me.
It looks like
the children of
the world.
Senator Freedom too
scripted.
it would have
been filmed by
now.
It would have
made at least
$20 million and
rescued countless lives.
But for Doug
Anderson,
but for the
PR committee,
State President.
Sound of freedom
activists destroyed.
The kids weren't
rescued to the
border.
The child abuse
wasn't uncovered.
I want to
say something about
that before I
turn back to
the story in
Boston.
This is very
important.
A member of
the Corps of
the Twelve Apostles
once came to
me sometime before
the excommunication and
said,
Tim,
don't go down
the rabbit hole.
This after I
presented him an
abundance of evidence
about child abuse.
In the church
ranks and being
covered up,
don't go down
to the rabbit
hole he said.
And I answered
to Jesus,
I answered no
man.
And I knew
that Jesus would
condemn me if
I didn't go
down this rabbit
hole.
So I continued,
they knew that.
They knew that
Senator Ballard would
expose that with
the power of
President Trump and
Sound of Freedom
behind me,
they knew that.
And from a
human traffic standpoint,
and we find
mostly women,
but children very
big also.
but it's women
and children.
Nobody's seen like,
I think I
can say this,
that nobody's ever
seen it like
it is today.
So they had
plenty of reason
to make sure
I couldn't win.
Now this is
a problem though.
It's a big,
big,
criminal problem.
I had already
announced I was
running for Senate
just weeks before
the Doug Anderson
lie came out.
I was running
for Senate.
Do you know
that such a
thing as federal
election law?
Do you know
what happens when
a 501C3 non
-profit medals in
an election?
That's criminal.
And that criminal
theory gets even
more pronounced and
more significant when
you consider the
fact that when
the lie came
out to Vice
Magazine,
it included that
Tim Ballard had
never done projects
associated with the
church.
Now the news
reported right away,
but they didn't
go,
you understand,
the church and
government controlled the
media.
So when they
came out,
the
the church had
deleted over 70
references to articles
about me as
a way to
punish me.
That's not what
they actually were
doing.
They were allegedly
committing crimes of
evidence tampering.
Can you imagine
how bad this
hit job was
performed by Doug
Anderson and his
crew,
whoever else was
involved?
Because what they
did was they
lied to you
about the fact
that I had
never done projects
associated with the
church.
And on the
very same day
they were caught
deleting references to
those very projects.
Same day.
They didn't wait
for a week
to give himself
a little plausible
than ability.
This is not
just a civil
liability they carry.
This is now
because it's conspiracy,
it's rico,
it's a conspiracy
against the United
States government and
the people of
the United States
who wanted this
under freedom act
to go forward.
It's now evidence
tampering,
criminal evidence tampering
and it will
be reviewed.
I am not
a bad man
for exposing people
who work evil
acts and lie
in the pursuit
of rescuing God's
children.
I am not
a bad man
for exposing people
who lie to
hurt children.
No matter who
they are or
what seat they
sit in,
I am a
bad man if
I do not.
And so I
will.
Under Jesus Christ,
I will.
I answer to
Him.
And so I
will do this.
I will expose
this.
The story gets
worse you see.
Because I am
masked,
Doug Anderson and
crew.
The minute Derek
Westward called back
and said,
I can't believe
this,
I was wrong.
I can't believe
this,
I was wrong.
It was them.
It was the
church.
They did it.
When I learned
that,
was sitting at
standing at the
monument for the
forefathers in Plymouth,
Massachusetts,
bearing testimony of
the Book of
Mormon.
See,
just like they
tried to hit
me on the
day of Atonement.
This is Jesus
punching back right
away,
defending his innocent
people,
defending his children.
He put me
there.
I could have
anywhere,
but I was
there,
testifying of him.
You know what
I did?
I knew it
was them,
but I said,
there's no way
it's them.
They would never
do something so
devilish.
They would never
violate what Jesus
taught us on
the sermon on
the mount to
not go to
your brother first.
Matthew 5,
Matthew 18,
the principles of
the Constitution even.
Innocent until Prudengilti.
They didn't whisper
a thing to
me.
And so I
set it on
camera and I
told the person,
and I said,
hold your phone
up and send
this to Fox
13.
I began to
unmask them in
the minutes.
After they tried
to scheme against
me.
So this is
destroyed.
This is wrecking
my family and
you can't believe
it.
My children are
being harassed right
now.
And what they
do,
I theorized that
the crew,
pen it.
They had to
go beyond vice.
make it more
credible.
So they sent
it to their
own media arm
to Deseret News,
to KSL,
who dutifully reported
under the order
of the lukewarm.
Now that was
a big,
big,
big mistake.
That's why I'm
suing Deseret Enterprises
because when they
read that statement,
knew it was
a lie.
The news agencies
can't report something
that we know
that they know
is a lie.
Now,
how do I
know that they
knew?
Because my projects
at Societre the
Church were with
them.
It was under
Sheri Dew.
Deseret News.
And they reported
on it over
and over and
over again.
Those were the
references they deleted
on September 15th.
Over 70 of
them.
Criminal evidence of
tampering possibly.
And so they
stand without excuse.
It was bad
enough that Deseret
News paraded what
they knew to
be a lie.
They knew I
did projects with
them.
They knew they'd
endorsed me.
So they knew
it was a
lie.
They knew I
did projects associated
with the Church.
But then something
else happens that
same day.
This is all
set up.
It will happen
on the same
day.
article where they
repeat the lie,
they say this,
listen carefully to
these words.
Deseret News independently
verified the legitimacy
of the statement
issued by the
Church of Jesus
Christ of Latter
-day Saints.
Let's think about
that for a
minute.
So if they
want to independently
verify the legitimacy
of this statement,
which they knew
is a lie,
okay.
Who would they
talk to?
They didn't talk
to me,
but apparently they
didn't talk to
themselves because from
the same desk
that they paraded
the lie,
they had 10
years of this
compulsory evidence.
They knew it
was a lie,
they published stories,
you can google
it,
they published stories
unless they've deleted
those as part
of the,
you know,
the attempt to
pretend it didn't
happen.
They knew they're
posing a lie
and then doubled
down with their
own lie.
How is this
okay with you
guys?
You covenant people
who are running
this.
How is this
okay?
Oh Tim,
they're going to
say this,
I know what
they're going to
say.
We were just
saying,
we were just
saying that the
statement did come
from the Church,
we weren't talking
about whether it
was true or
not.
Now any,
that's what they'll
say when they
get their lawyers,
know,
the Gat-Anne's
have their lawyers
and everything,
and we know
how that goes.
They knew when
they published this,
the vast majority
of readers would
read that as
to say,
we independently verified
the legitimacy of
the statement.
truth was of
It just keeps
getting worse and
it's going to
get worse.
It gets worse
and worse and
worse.
You know,
President Nelson,
who I sustained,
he gave a
talk about peacemakers.
Read his talk
about peacemakers and
see how his
own employees responded
immediately almost months
or so after.
Was there anything
peaceful about what
they did?
But it gets
even more interesting
because Governor Cox,
who you'll learn
later,
they told Governor
Cox that it
came from them,
they told their
switch squad it
didn't.
You'll get to
that.
It's interesting part
of the story.
But Governor Cox
said he heard
that.
It penetrated his
soul and then
he started this
thing called Disagree
Better.
And then Desirat
News paraded that.
There are several
articles where it
was.
Disagree Better,
Disagree Better.
They jumped on
that thing.
That's a different
story.
think that opens
the door to
lukewarmism,
because disagree better
apparently means just
accept all things,
which leads to
really bad things.
But disagree better
makes me think
the theme of
this.
What are they
going to do
next?
You're going to
find out.
It's not good.
What you'll get
to it.
Are they going
to repent better
for what they've
done?
It's been almost
three years now,
and there's no
signs of that.
In fact,
the signs are
the opposite.
They aren't going
to repent better.
They're going to
lie better.
And that's what
they're going to
say.
When we're in
court,
I can't wait
to get there
and watch them
try to do
this.
But they are
going to say,
we were just
talking about it
came from the
church.
But they knew
darn well that
everybody reading this,
even if they
make that up
later,
they were trying
to let you
know this is
a true statement.
And that is
sinful.
It's a woe
upon all of
you who participated
in it,
and those who
read it and
said nothing,
that's a woe
upon you as
well.
They
were putting forth
a lie,
but hey,
someone told me
to do it
that has a
red-seated conference.
That's not the
way this works,
guys.
You always have
a choice.
That's the plan
of salvation.
This isn't Satan's
plan.
You might think
it is,
they've tricked you
into thinking it
is,
because that's what
they like,
control.
Jesus gives agency.
You always have
a choice.
And you chose
poorly.
And not only
did you participate
in possibly criminal
activity in evidence
tampering,
and defamation,
business interference,
but also consider
the fact that
the parent company,
Doug Anderson,
PR committee,
sends a lie
to their media
arm.
The media arm,
oh,
that thing went
viral as you
wanted.
As you wanted.
They actually financially
gained on their
lie,
because they own
the media.
Do you see
how devastating this
is?
Do see how
bad this is?
The question is,
go 200 million
miles
outside of your
scripture and your
policy?
To do this
to me.
This isn't about
repentance.
This take presence
lying to you,
telling to me,
this is about
your soul,
so I'll get
to that later.
And I'll tell
you,
it wasn't about
that.
I didn't care
about my soul,
was about,
this is a
PR hit.
What are they
hiding?
Were they being
extorted?
These Lafayr warriors,
Rasmussen Mortensen,
they're going to
jail.
Okay,
we caught them.
They will be
going to jail
in multiple jurisdictions.
They extorted my
wife.
When my wife
came up publicly
and defended me,
boom,
she was sued
for sexual assault.
When that Cooper
refused,
the offer to
sue me by
the woman who
told me he
needs to do
it,
that woman,
we later sued
him for sexual
assault.
I believe they
extorted Ella Ballard.
I believe that
if they didn't
hit me,
that Ella Ballard
was going to
be sued as
well.
But we'll find
out through discovery,
through depositions and
through criminal investigations,
how far this
went and who
did what.
What are consequences
Hit job in
the beginning using
a tabloid magazine.
and
and defaming both
me and other
baller.
Now we find
out what they
do internally as
they call me
on September 25th,
2023,
into the Kangaroo
Court.
BELL RINGS I
often go undercover
as an excommunicated
Mormon and we
have to look
like we're saying
gross things because
you have to
create what's called
a legend.
You have to
create your backstory
who you are.
I'm a trafficker,
I'm a pedophile,
I'm whatever I
need to be
to get into
this network.
And sometimes they're
in training sessions
and you can
tell when I'm
training someone,
I say,
are you okay?
Stop,
Do you want
to keep going?
I'm laying next
to my wife
saying,
keep doing this
for a living.
So because I
work in this
dark and slimy
world and have
to do things
that are crazy
and could be
misinterpreted,
I met with
Sean Richards on
a standing interview
every Monday or
Tuesday morning when
I'm in town.
For months and
months and months,
not to confess,
but to talk,
to counsel.
When Kevin Pearson
first called Sean
Richards and told
him to have
a disciplinary counsel,
they said there
was key evidence
against Ballard.
Sean Richards called
me in.
He asked me
a few questions,
he felt my
spirit and he's
like,
I know you
so well,
you already told
me these things.
He calls back
to Pearson and
says,
I'm not gonna
do it.
So again,
who
days later,
Sean Richards gets
booted out,
incomes the other
guy.
I'm sure that's
not suspicious at
all.
The former state
president,
Sean Richards,
refused to discipline
me.
So they waited
just days later,
until the new
guy came in,
and he was
made to be
the Patsy.
So I get
called in on
September 25th,
2023,
me and my
wife,
the day of
the torment,
the one day
you cannot,
you're not permitted
to do this
in difficult law.
Oh,
but Tim,
we can do
it everyone.
Of course you
can do everyone.
We know that.
We know you
think you can
do whatever you
want.
The state president
sitting like this
in his chair.
The two counselors
are crying,
because they know
they're about to
do something illicit.
They lied from
day one.
I'll tell you
about that lie.
I walked in
there,
and I said,
you have the
authority to make
this decision about
a communication or
discipline,
right?
Yes.
Is this your
decision?
Because it needs
to be yours.
Yes,
absolutely our decision.
He says I
have text messages.
So show me
the text messages.
He went show
them to me,
attorney,
client,
privilege.
I guess that's
what Kevin Pearson
or someone told
me to say.
Those were out
the next week
when the lawsuits
came out.
They were in
public.
I saw them.
Guys,
go ahead and
look at all.
I can provide
you a hundred
more text messages
like this.
This is undercover
operations.
Those texts that
he was referring
to that he
had aren't even
the worst ones.
I have texts
where I'm sending
horrific images back
and forth.
Understand we go
undercover.
And oh,
I was talking
bad about the
church.
I certainly was.
I have to
have subjects to
talk about for
weeks on end
that aren't just
children.
I got to
be friends with
these guys.
So I pretend
to be an
ex-communicated woman
because of my
trafficking habits.
And then they
start talking about
the church and
I can say
every bad thing
I can about
the church.
In detail.
So you're gonna
find that manifested
in my undercover
operations.
Okay,
that's what they
had.
But they couldn't
show it to
me.
were expecting to
show it to
me because they
knew I could
probably defend myself.
Do you see
how
back.
Can you imagine
anybody,
any church,
you get called
in by your
ecclesiastical leader with
your spouse and
the ecclesiastical leader
is sitting there
like this sitting
back like in
that kind of
posture and then
proceeds to tell
you that your
spouse has had
penetrative sex with
a woman.
You know it's
false,
your wife can't
believe it and
he won't even
tell you who
the woman is.
The reason the
ecclesiastical leader wouldn't
tell me who
the woman is
is because she
doesn't exist in
the real world,
she doesn't exist.
I think she
is,
and I say
this not jokingly,
I think she
does exist in
another room,
I think she's
an angel from
hell that torments
these people,
keeps them up
at night because
she doesn't exist
and they need
her to exist
because if she
doesn't exist,
the condemnation upon
them,
it's a long
road.
here's the other
thing that's going
to agitate them.
even
I know the
timeframe that this
woman was supposed
to have existed.
It's in 2022.
And 2022 is
when I supposedly
had penetrative sex
with this unknown
woman.
But the thing
is about 2022
is that was
the year that
my life was
documented almost incisively.
I was with
people or cameras
everywhere I went.
So you get
to see exactly
what I was
doing in 2022
because we were
filming a massive
operation.
It's the operation
depicted in Hint
Warden.
Now let's get
to section 102
of doctorate in
Covenant.
This is very
easy.
In all cases
to avoid injustice,
to avoid injury,
to innocent people.
In all cases,
you must allow
the member to
decide to have
a council of
12 people.
If it's not
but
But this is
complex.
This is a
man who just
announced he's running
for a senator.
This is a
man who just
came off the
biggest move of
year.
Who just met
with President Trump.
You don't think
this sounds complex?
And he said
to me,
so I don't
want embarrass you.
I said,
embarrass me.
You'll be embarrassed
if we have
a council.
So let's go.
Nope.
I can override
that.
that because I
am your judging
issue.
I'm judging Israel.
But let me
tell you what
Joseph Smith actually
said about Section
102.
It was so
important to him.
This is Joseph
commenting on Section
102.
acts are recorded.
And at a
future day,
they will be
laid before us.
And if we
should fail to
judge right and
injure our fellow
beings,
countless fellow beings,
countless were injured.
This is like
the worst case
scenario of not
following the scriptures.
Okay.
They may,
there perhaps,
condemn us.
There they are
of great consequences.
And to me,
the consequences appear
force
force anything which
I'm able to
express.
think this is
serious.
I think this
is really serious.
Something else I
wanna address while
we're talking about
this is this
myth of infallibility.
Now,
this is a
subject that usually
is limited to
a dining room
table after church,
and everyone has
said it,
oh,
they're just men,
they're imperfect men,
but that is
not effectuated in
reality,
is it?
Because there's this
facade,
if we're honest
with ourselves,
I can be
honest,
because I don't
think you can
excommunicate someone twice.
I'm sure they've
thought about how
they could,
but I'm gonna
say what you're
all thinking.
We have to
stop this.
You know it,
this myth of
infallibility.
That's where the
problem begins,
and it gets
lying,
because to maintain
that falsehood,
you have to
lie.
Lie,
lie,
lie.
You,
what you allow
you become,
okay?
What you allow
you become,
and pretty soon
you don't even
know your lying.
You just call
it PR,
chalk it up
to that,
and think it's
okay.
does
about lying?
My gosh,
it's over the
top what he
says.
this whole thing
started,
the kangaroo court
started with that
myth completely just
being fused out
of the state
president.
The tabloid lie
which I could
have proven a
lie in three
seconds,
he wouldn't let
me.
You what he
said to me?
These are exact
words.
They don't make
mistakes up there.
Then he went
so far as
to say the
prophet wrote it
or endorsed it.
That's when the
lying begins.
See the lying
starts.
Got a lie
to keep up
the facade.
Okay,
it's self evident
the lie from
the tabloid magazine
from Dick Andersen and
the state president
wouldn't even let
me address it
because they don't
make mistakes up
there.
So what happens
is we all
lie for each
other because we
don't want to
admit a mistake.
We don't apologize
apparently.
I don't understand
that.
I don't think
Jesus would teach
that.
But stop with
the myth.
People like authenticity.
People like it.
If you said,
yeah,
we're imperfect.
We made a
mistake.
They like that.
We wouldn't be
standing here right
now.
This should have
been done the
first month that
happened.
You've got to
keep the myth.
The myth is
more dangerous.
No,
no.
What's more dangerous
in the myth
is having the
truth exposed.
That's the PR
nightmare.
And we're experiencing
it right now.
So what do
they do?
Well,
Nephi tells you
what you're going
to do.
Commenting on the
words of Isaiah
in 2nd Nephi
28.
Again,
watch my scriptural
analysis that will
be in conjunction
with a backfire.
Nephi says what
they're going to
do.
And stop with
the...
It's the Catholics,
it's these guys,
it's the Jews,
it's us.
Read it.
Literally the people
he's talking to
will give as
their excuse.
All is well
in Zion.
Zion prospereth all
as well.
He's talking to
those who seek
Zion,
the covenant community.
So obvious.
And what does
he say that
they will say?
He says they
will say fear
God.
Because we are
the covenant people.
Fear God.
But lie a
little.
It'll
Dig a pit
for your brother
because of his
words,
like undercover texts
or podcasters that
you don't agree
with.
Dig a pit
for your brother.
I don't think
I've ever seen
a more perfect
fulfillment of this
prophecy.
then he goes
on to say,
and then what
they will say,
how they'll justify
it.
And we'll think
a few stripes
and then we'll
be saved.
No,
keep reading.
You don't get
saved.
It's actually,
I'm not if
you're going to
say it.
It's so sad
what happens.
Like the worst
thing.
The worst thing
that can happen
to you is
what happens to
you when you
say this.
And that's what
you're saying.
You're literally saying
it all as
well as I
am.
This guy told
me to do
it,
I can do
it.
The myth of
infallibility that has
persisted way too
long.
Beats lies and
you fall in
the trap of
2nd Nephi 28.
He tell you
you're going to
do it and
you still do
it.
So then one
of the things
people are doing
right now,
I know this
because the first
counselor in the
state president,
he's a good
guy.
I forgive him,
I love him.
I don't trust
him because he
admitted that he
lied to me.
And so at
point,
negotiations end.
Okay,
that's how you
do that.
But he said
something to me,
which a lot
of people are
saying,
Tim,
for the greater
good,
even if you're
innocent.
Is that what
Jesus would do?
Live for the
greater good,
is that what
we're about?
Is that what
we want the
world to see,
it says?
And let me
tell you where
that road ends.
It ends in
a brick wall
because I had
the conversation with
the first counselor
in state presidency.
He said,
Tim,
I'm sure many
of have said
this,
why can't you
just go like
a lamb to
the slaughter?
Be like Jesus.
He was guilty,
he was innocent,
falsely accused.
He went like
a lamb to
the slaughter and
the brother next
to me in
the room said,
hey bro,
Tim's not effectuating
an atonement here.
He's trying to
rescue children.
Children's lives are
at stake here
with this defamation.
And I said,
yeah,
and by the
way,
I actually read
my Bible and
not only am
I not effectuating
an atonement,
but I will
be like Jesus
like he was
in the first
two thirds of
Testament,
where he's being
our exemplar,
and he picks
up a whip.
And toss tables.
And he exposes
people who are
hypocrites.
Isn't it scary
to think that
the Pharisees didn't
know they were
Pharisees?
They didn't.
Caiaphas went to
his grave thinking
he did the
right thing.
So the people
who are a
fair circle today,
they don't know
it.
They don't know
They just are
it.
I'm thinking to
this first counselor,
who are you
in this narrative
you just painted
for me?
You literally are
saying,
can you please
let us persecute
you?
Like we persecuted
Jesus?
I mean,
is he Caiaphas?
Is he pilot?
What's role that
he want?
Because that's what
happens when you
lie.
You run into
a brick wall.
And you end
up being the
bad guy in
the scripture story.
Don't do it.
What would you
want to do
it?
All right,
let's go on
with the story.
These are conspiring
men.
Do you understand
Mr.
State President?
I have to
say,
State President,
because the scripture
doesn't recognize priesthood
in this person.
DNC-121 makes
that very clear.
someone
power,
they will almost
always take it
too far.
And if you
exude unrighteous dominion
upon the souls
of men,
amen to the
priesthood.
I don't know
how you get
around it.
mental gymnastics,
these guys have
to do to
keep themselves sane,
but I don't
think they are
sane.
So what he's
doing is sitting
in the throne
of Jesus,
violating Jesus's words.
Oh,
he can think
about it himself.
Now,
right he is.
And what a
great judge in
Israel he is.
This is disgusting,
guys.
He would not
let me have
my Jesus ordained
promised rights.
Meet Christa Casey.
Remember her?
She's the one
who's lied to
the state president.
She went to
my friend Todd
Antiphany Tuller,
and we have
declarations about this.
And said,
I'm going to
go lie about
Tim Valor,
and she's crying,
it's like I
keep it up,
I'm gonna do
this.
But I believe
the other women,
and I want
to support them,
even though he
never did anything
to me.
No,
what she was
really saying was,
I want the
money they're promising
me,
okay?
So I guess
who I had
in the parking
lot?
I said,
I got Todd
Tuller in the
parking lot.
He's gonna come
tell you that
this woman lied
to you yesterday.
No witnesses.
I'm your judge
in Israel.
I won't let
this witness come
in and say.
He's in the
parking lot.
He is a
member of the
church.
He's a high
councilman.
I'm your judge
in Israel.
No witnesses.
Come on guys.
Are you serious?
And you want
me to believe
this?
What he's telling
me in my
wife,
you are no
longer married for
eternity.
Your covenants are
dead.
Your children no
longer have a
father who they
have for eternity
because I'm your
judge in Israel
and I can
override the words
of Jesus.
Everybody should just
go read just
as an exercise.
Everybody.
Go read doctrine
comes one or
two,
the commandment,
and then go
read doctrine comes
one,
twenty-one,
which is the
consequences.
Or don't read
it or pretend
it doesn't exist.
Or just delete
it because the
state president believes
he told me
he can delete
scripture.
If he can
delete this most
important one,
he can delete
any of them.
That's what he
told me.
That's what he's
saying.
implying strongly.
So but those
of us who
believe that you
can't do that,
okay?
canonized
this is real,
if you,
even in the
slightest it says,
exude unrighteous dominion
upon the souls
of men,
amen to his
priesthood.
That's what it
says.
I don't recognize
priesthood in this
person.
I can't.
I can't and
believe in Jesus.
I can't do
both of those.
One-twenty-one
is much more
extensive.
It starts off
by talking about
how most people,
he says,
you can get
the priesthood conferred
upon you.
That means nothing.
Joseph Smith said
that if you
don't actually have
the
spirit,
okay,
if you don't
actually have it,
it's all contingent
on obedience.
He said,
you don't have
the spirit,
you might as
well baptize a
bag of sand.
These ordinances don't
mean anything.
If you can't
back it up
with obedience to
his word,
not to the
precepts of men,
not to Kevin
Hamilton's policy.
One-twenty-one
says that most
people,
most men,
if given,
just because you
confer,
it doesn't mean
anything,
go read it
and most men
will violate that
and they'll unrighteous
to men upon
the souls of
men and the
kids think present
took him two
weeks and he
was on it.
So,
in May to
the priest,
says
think is very
interesting and important
if you read
the whole thing.
He says that
if you do
these things,
if you,
if you falsely
accuse the innocent,
especially the innocent,
who were doing
my work,
I declared to
you,
I was doing
Jesus's work even
though the state
president told me
that I'm a
covenant breaker in
the King Group
Court.
I'm a covenant
breaker by virtue
of the fact
that I would
go into brothels
and strip clubs.
I can tell
you that if
I didn't go
into those places
and rescue those
children,
I would be
violating my covenant.
So,
Dean C-121
is very clear.
If you falsely
accuse somebody who
was doing my
work,
he says,
you are the
children of sin.
That's what he
says.
And then he
says this,
and you shall
be cut off
from the ordinances
of my house.
Oh,
that's the Catholics.
That's the other
people,
the other Gentiles.
No,
no,
you can't be
cut off from
something you don't
have or something
you're not already
a part of.
He's talking about
those religious leaders
who
ordinance,
they cut themselves
off from the
ordinance as my
house.
That's what it
says.
When you do
that,
you're the servants
of sin.
And clearly that's
what these people
did.
Now what's interesting
about D&C
once you go
on,
it goes into
a different direction
that seems counterintuitive,
but fits my
case perfectly.
He says because,
because when you
did this thing,
you hurt my
little ones.
Isn't that interesting?
I'm reading him
like,
wow,
it's like almost
designed for this
case.
Because that was
the consequences.
Not just the
little ones who
are my children,
but countless little
ones who were
never rescued.
Because of this
lie.
And then he
doubles down,
Jesus doubles down,
and quotes from
Luke,
better than a
Milestone,
he says,
and Dr.
Counts wants anyone
in context to
all this unrighteous
dominion stuff.
If the consequence
is children getting
hurt,
he quotes from
Luke,
better than a
Milestone,
be hung about
your neck,
and then you
should hurt one
of these,
my little ones.
people on the
high council are
outraged.
They know that
policies,
it's not just
guys.
It's scriptures have
been violated.
There's one named
Paul P*** who
had the courage
of the Lord.
He went and
confronted the Stig
President.
It's like you
can't,
you're destroying this
family and you're
destroying their mission
and you violate
the scriptures.
And they've gotten
to it back
and forth and
Paul said,
look,
I will be
implicated in making
this horrible decision.
So therefore I
have no choice
but to resign
my position in
the high council.
And you know
what Stig President
did?
If that's the
case,
then give me
your temple recommend.
Paul P*** is
a gladly,
you can have
my temple recommend.
A picture of
Jesus comes crashing
down on the
floor.
The day of
the tonement,
the picture of
Jesus,
the voice in
the upper room,
I talk about
the lukewarm,
deliver the rights.
How many signs
do you need
before you know
you are being
vomited out?
As Revelation 36
indicates will happen
when you use
his name to
work evil acts
on the innocent.
And Paul P***
left the room
saying,
well,
I guess we
what
about this and
yet that they
present it move
forward undeterred.
I think they
hoped that at
the end of
their kangaroo court
everything would just
kind of disappear
and somehow normalizing
we all go
home and forget,
but we didn't.
There was a
very significant aftermath
through all this.
We went through
hell.
A hell I
can't even describe.
I suicidal ideations
like I didn't
think were possible.
What brought the
pain to me
was my church.
This is the
Church of Jesus
Christ of the
Latter-day Saints.
Not the one
I know.
I never heard
of such a
thing.
I went to
Convalesce in California
where I grew
up.
My mom's a
mess.
This destroyed the
Ballard family in
Southern California.
I had to
go put myself
in a place
to try to
get wrap my
head around this.
I had to
leave my family
alone.
The area president
of California is
a man named
Mark Bragg.
He showed up
to my parents'
house.
Grab my mom's
shoulders and melody.
Listen to me,
I will be
here for you.
Do you believe
me?
I will choose
to believe you.
He calls me
in the place
I'm convolessing.
I'm coming to
visit you.
You're in my
area.
We're gonna fix
this.
We're gonna figure
this out.
I am crying
in gratitude.
He didn't make
good on his
promise.
We'll find out
through deposition and
discovery.
Who told Mark
Bragg to stand
down and not
be like Jesus
like he was
trying to be.
The aftermath gets
even worse,
guys.
Santa Freedom 2
was already scripted.
It would have
been filmed by
now.
It would have
made at least
$20 million and
rescued countless lives.
But for Doug
Anderson.
But for the
PR committee.
State President.
So there we
are,
devastated.
At a side
to try to
do Matthew 18
compliant.
Okay,
we put in
a appeal letter.
It comes right
back,
turns around.
The State President
calls my wife,
braggadociously,
well,
suffering
he said,
they agree with
me.
Very arrogantly,
just breaks my
wife's heart.
They agree with
me.
This is about
him.
totally about him
and his own
insecurities and his
own pride.
And then what
we learned through
this process,
which everybody needs
to understand,
again,
lies begin,
lies,
you become what
you allow.
Okay,
the letter,
the appeals letter,
just went right
back.
President Pearson,
they went right
back to the
people who issued
the hit job.
It's all fake.
It's a fake
check and balance
system.
The first presidency
didn't know I
confirmed that.
How much of
that's going on?
That's taking people's
name in vain.
That's what it's
doing.
And then the
deep state gets
to have their
way with the
name of the
prophet.
No way,
no.
I go in
to see him
when I get
back.
I bring two
brothers with me
and I want
at least one
of them to
go in there
with me.
I walk in
there and this
is all documented.
Com is can
be,
a lot upset.
He says,
you can't bring
these guys in
here.
And the guy
with me,
one of the
brothers,
pulls up the
handbook and says
under rule,
think it's 1
.114 or something.
always allow a
member to have
someone in there
with you and
in any interview.
As the brothers
reading this,
they say,
President Craig,
stop,
stop.
I can override
that.
He shakes in
our presence.
Why?
And he's like,
Tim,
come in here.
I said,
I'm not going
to walk in
there with you.
I wouldn't walk
in a room
professionally,
it cleansed it,
has to go
with anybody who's
shaking like this.
I don't trust
you.
I'm not going
to go in
the office with
this guy,
because he has
proven to me
that he's willing
to lie.
And he's shaking
like a madman.
Also,
before he invited
me into his
office while his
hands were literally
shaking,
I'm not exaggerating.
I'm the goodest
hand.
was like,
what is wrong
with you?
This is not
a fruit of
the spirit.
Whatever it is,
ain't the spirit.
But before he
did that,
he looked at
the two brothers,
and I'm not
going to exaggerate
this either,
okay?
He said,
you two out
like that.
Like they're little
puppy dogs,
okay?
This is not
the fruit of
the spirit.
This whole thing
is clearly being
inspired by darkness.
They call it
a chemical download.
That's how they
excuse it.
Oh,
he has his
chemical downloads.
No,
this is the
spirit of the
devil.
That's what it
is.
You know it.
You know it,
you see it.
You look in
someone's eyes.
That's what it
is.
It's not a
chemical download.
It's somebody who
is loving to
make you lie,
to hurt children.
When the first
counselor later came
and said,
why don't you
go to his
office?
I said,
you guys are
willing to lie.
I said,
I could go
into his office.
into his office,
and he could
literally be instructed.
These people are
not to be
trusted at all.
Once you are
free,
you're going to
be a liar.
My gosh.
These guys lied.
They lie with
impunity.
So I said,
if I go
into the office
with the state
president at this
point for the
third time,
I have no
reason to believe
that he would
just say under
instruction,
Tim admitted something.
Oh,
he would never
do that.
He would never
He says,
literally saying that
to me,
seven seconds after
he himself had
just admitted to
me in the
hallway with Mark
Stockton Bishop,
saying,
I like you.
Like,
this life thing
is insane.
That's why it's
repeated so much
in the scriptures
as the thing
that condemns.
It's really bad
to lie.
All the tangled
webs we weave
when it first
repractes to deceive.
That's a real
thing.
You have proven
that you're willing
to override the
words of Jesus
Christ.
But that was
it.
That was my
last attempt to
go meet with
him.
But then something
happened.
There's two weapons
on a tower
throughout this whole
story.
Present Nelson's advisors
read the appeal
letter and they
say,
this is outrageous.
cannot believe this
take president did
all these things.
And so he
said,
you just sent
it to the
first presidency because
it's not getting
to us.
We use the
prophecy in the
vein.
Just like Doug
Anderson in the
PR committee used
out the baller's
name in vain.
Do you see
how this ugly
game works?
With those of
the order of
lukewarm,
truth is completely
relative.
And so in
March of this
year,
in an effort
to be Matthew
18 compliant,
my attorney Mark
Eisenhut,
one of the
best attorneys in
the land,
sent the entire
package to the
attorney assigned to
five
Five after we
have the packet
of information,
Mark Brad gets
released.
Kevin Pearson gets
sent to Europe.
But the thing
is,
is he's gonna
turn 70 in
a year and
a change.
It makes no
sense to send
a man who's
only four years
into his calling
in Yutza.
To finish out
his calling with
only a year
or so left,
they sent him
out there to
hide him because
of the crimes
he committed against
my family.
Have you ever
heard of an
area president being
called for just
a year in
a faraway land?
And the timing
of it?
For those of
you who don't
understand how church
government works,
when you turn
70,
you are automatically
retired.
So they're gonna
say what they're
gonna say.
Again,
lying's not a
problem for them,
so I expect
them to say
anything,
but I won't
believe it.
President Pearson is
four years into
his Yutza calling,
generally not always,
but generally those
callings last five
years.
And they're gonna
say,
oh,
it's conference time,
yeah,
but it was
after conference.
I sent the
letter before conference,
and they did
this after conference.
About five days
after they got
the letter,
they announced that
Mark Bragg is
released
released and Kevin
Pearson is being
moved to Europe.
They had to
get him out
of town because
he was the
mastermind behind this.
He had to
be the one
that was approving
all of this,
but we'll find
out through deposition.
We'll find out.
putting you somewhere
else.
Way,
somewhere else,
like way outside
so no one
can talk to
you.
But we can
talk to them
because we have
the internet and
phones and depositions
can cross the
ocean.
President brother Pearson,
I think it's
time you and
I have the
talk we should
have had in
private had you
chosen to live
your governance in
B-Mathlete 5
and Method 18
compliant,
G-C-1
-L-T compliant.
You invited the
public to this.
mean this is
face that you
you tried to
make millions of
people hate me
and you had
some success.
But uh,
since I'm gonna
have this talk
we're gonna have
an appointment.
I'm very confused
about what you
mean when you
tell the people
and you do
often.
Very aggressively sometimes.
We live our
covenants always,
always live our
covenants.
Once you said,
it's not about
personal preference.
So help us
understand this.
Help us understand
this.
The book is
literally called Doctrine
and Covenants.
I'm to spell
this out like
I'm talking to
children.
And say,
it's insane that
I have to
do this.
And you're still
not going to
believe me probably.
You're still going
to justify.
Like the scriptures
say,
you,
oh,
you're going to
fulfill the prophecy.
And on the
wrong side of
the divide.
The book is
called Doctrine and
Covenants.
I'm not mad
at you,
by the way.
I really am
not.
I,
this is not
of indeta.
This is a
learning moment.
You've decided to
make yourself that
guy in the
scripture story that
people need to
learn from.
Like all the
scriptures provide these
people.
The book is
called Doctrine and
because
of doctrine and
full of covenants.
Now I love
the scriptures.
I read the
doctor.
It's quite a
bit.
And in some
of the sections,
it's more doctrine
and other disparate
covenant.
Dr.
and Covenants 121,
that particular section,
is very much
covenant.
It's an if
-then.
It's the coming
piece.
These books actually
go,
as you know,
on the altars
of the temple.
So when we're
covering in the
temple,
we're to mean
him in any
degree,
in the least
amen to the
priesthood.
You and yours
did that thing
in the most
expansive,
the greatest degree.
So how do
you not receive
the consequences of
amen to the
priesthood?
How is that
possible?
One plus one
equals two.
Water is wet.
I'm literally making
an argument that
water is wet.
I can't believe
I have to
do that.
your actions have
and
this before and
I think it
bears repeating.
It's not just
that.
sever yourself from
the horns of
the house.
You can't sever
yourself from something
that you're not
a part of.
You just stop
blaming everybody else.
It's the Catholics,
it's the Jews,
it's someone else.
Anyone but us.
You can't sever
yourself from something
you're not part
of.
He's talking to
the religiously.
I've said it
before and I'll
say it again.
I'll say it
again and I'll
say it again.
He calls you
if you do
this thing.
The servants of
said the children
of his obedience.
This is all
a doctor goes
to 21.
He says most
of you are
going to do
this thing in
many are called
and but fewer
chosen.
Many are so
many will do
this.
Most of you
will do this.
So it's all
very very clear.
We're going to
talk and we
already have about
the consequences,
your violation of
covenant has had
on the whole
world,
world.
Magnum mistake.
Countless children were
hurt because you
chose to break
your covenant while
telling all of
us that we
should never make
preference.
understand it.
My daughter just
three days ago.
I came home.
I'm right now
in Dominican Republic.
I'll tell you
why.
I chose this
place.
But my daughter
just a few
days ago,
I came home
from Columbia and
she said,
Dad,
I had the
weirdest experience.
My daughter has
friends come over
to our house
occasionally in the
same group of
friends.
They were downstairs
and one of
these boys,
or kid,
I feel bad
for them.
They were trying
to pick a
movie to watch
and sound a
freedom came up.
And some of
the kids were
joking because they
know my daughter,
they know who
I am.
And one of
these kids who
didn't know,
for some reason,
somehow didn't know.
I'm literally sleeping
upstairs.
I just got
home.
And he says,
let's not watch
that movie.
This is an
LDS kid in
Utah.
Let's not watch
that movie.
that
pen of someone.
She was wearing
a watch that
monitors your heart
rate.
And when my
daughter said,
That's my dad.
And he's not
a pen of
fun.
That's what my
kids have to
deal with because
of your decision
to break your
cover.
It happens all
the time.
kids heart rate
sprung to the
point that is
watch out is
going ding ding
ding ding ding
ding ding Okay,
kind of a
funny moment.
But not so
funny.
Might show enough
dealt with this.
There's no excuse
for this.
Kevin Pearson.
There's no excuse
for this.
If you have
not cut yourself
off from the
orange of the
house,
then the doctrine
of covenants is
not true.
If you have
not lost your
priesthood for this
decision,
then the doctrine
of covenants is
not true.
Then one plus
one is not
equals to that.
And one plus
one is not
equal to water
is not wet.
The scriptures are
this whatever.
It's a smorgasbord.
It's a buffet
against you.
You get to
pick what you
want.
So when you
say live your
cover,
what are you
thinking?
Like don't drink
coffee and make
sure to go
to church.
But not the
ones that cause
damage to the
whole world.
It will never
make sense.
I hope that
there's someone in
your life that
you're not exuding
and righteous to
me in it,
but they can
talk to you
about this Maybe
I don't know
that the pride
to do this
is so great
that repentance becomes
very very difficult
and if you
choose that path
all of you
It's a long
road when you
use the name
of Jesus Christ
and that's what
you did Kevin
Pierce.
That's what you
did Doug Anderson
will talk about
him in a
second again.
He's a liar.
He's an absolute
liar
At least at
least he was
on the administrative
side.
You made the
decision to put
the name of
Jesus Christ on
it when you
took this lie
and crossed into
the ecclesiastical world
You put the
name of Jesus
Christ on it.
So if everything
happened after that
was done in
the name of
Jesus Christ This
is horrific Forific
But not surprising
Not surprising at
all
We have a
lot of end
time scriptures that
this looks a
lot like the
vineyard 2000 years
ago But isn't
it funny that
there's way more
prophecies about the
end time vineyard
than there was
about the 2000
year old video
Jesus had to
confront similar situations
So we're left
with without excuse
to a higher
degree here.
We all know
that Jeremiah,
we know that
Jeremiah is the
n times book
and I want
to say two
things.
The two hallmarks
of the n
time vineyard and
the n times
is lying and
persecuting with unrighteous
dominion,
the innocent and
even the righteous.
Easy one,
swiney one,
talks about if
you lift your
heel against those
who are doing
my will,
I was doing
the will of
Jesus by risk
of inshelbiners.
That's when you
get in trouble
and if children
got hurt in
this,
remember what it
says in the
books from Luke
1710,
better than a
millstone,
nothing much,
you're not getting
tested.
See,
I mean,
this is fear
stop.
This is an
infant.
This is a
covenant for broken,
broken.
And Jeremiah says,
is exactly what's
going to happen.
Let's see what
Jeremiah says.
He's n times,
okay,
Jeremiah 23 will
start with start
with 23.
Now,
again,
it tells you
it's n times
he's talking about
this great exodus
going to happen.
It's
even supersede the
miracles of the
Moses Exodus.
It says it
right here.
So we know
we're in the
end times,
the end of
the end times,
because there is
going to be
an interest to
this.
It's beautiful.
This is actually
all these scriptures
have good news
in it.
Fortunately,
I got to
focus on some
of the bad
news stuff.
I encourage everyone
to read it.
have to read
all of it.
Termites 23,
woe be unto
the pastors that
destroy and scatter
the sheep of
my pastor.
See,
they'll have so
poor the pastors
in the end
times.
Stop blaming other
people.
If you're the
chuvian who you
are,
which we are,
then it's talking
about you.
There's no other
candidate here.
candidate.
You have scattered
my flocks first
too,
and driven them
away,
and have not
visited them.
The older I
will visit upon
you.
The evil of
your doing say
to Lord,
and I will
gather the remnant
of my flock
out of the
country whether I've
driven them.
After we got
false action medicated,
you know
Lord didn't accept
it.
We'll talk later
about this.
didn't accept it.
You excommunicated yourself
when by doing
this.
You didn't touch
me.
My covenants are
intact more so
than ever.
But no one
came to visit
us.
I mean it's
like a careful
film and this
is happening all
over.
Don't nobody think
for a second
that this is
somehow on one
offer.
I've talked to
these people getting
excommunicated with the
violations of all
the covenants.
He wants 21
-1-1-2.
Matthew 5,
Matthew 8D and
blah blah blah
on and on.
Okay.
They don't visit
you afterwards.
My wife went
to the state
president and begged
her to visit
us.
Just so my
kids wouldn't lose
all faith in
the institution.
She's a better
person than me
because I don't
like I don't
want to be
in this every
time he's my
presence he goes
like this.
So I took
one in awkward
situation.
Fortunately I wasn't
there when he
came over the
one time.
But they never
came.
She would ask
them to come.
They wouldn't come.
Obviously fulfilled.
Let's go on.
For both profit
and priest.
This is verse
11.
For both profit
and priest are
profane.
Yay in my
house.
their
the Lord.
Their ways shall
be unto them
as a slippery
way.
And I'll bring
evil upon them.
There's lot of
curses I'm not
gonna talk about,
but they're gonna
happen.
You don't repent.
They're prophetically going
to happen.
I have seen
also in the
prophets a horrible
thing that commit
adultery,
to walk in
the lies,
and they strengthen
the hands of
evil doers.
They strengthen the
hands of evil.
You're doing it
right now,
everybody.
It's crazy.
It's like what
the court case
is,
it's like two
weeks ago in
Arizona.
So if you
guys don't know,
there's an LDS
guy who's a
pedophile,
raping little children,
goes to his
bishop and confesses.
The bishop decides
not what happens,
and don't let
them lie again
about this,
because I have
a personal experience
with them in
the case.
When you call
that hotline,
it goes to
the attorneys.
The attorneys encourage
you not to
call the police.
It happened to
me.
I can be,
I'm a personal
witness of this.
I won't talk
about that story,
but it's gonna
reveal itself soon.
So they don't
do anything.
The bishop is
instructed not to,
because the PR
is more important
than God.
Fear man,
not God.
I think like
four or five
years later,
the guy gets
arrested as LDS
member,
gets arrested by
the police.
Over that four
or five years,
many other children
were abused.
They wouldn't have
been abused.
Had you defended
the fatherless,
like you commanded
to do in
Matthew,
in Luke,
in Isaiah chapter
one amongst other
places,
defend the fatherless.
You're supposed to
do that.
I'll talk later
about Isaiah chapter
one.
We'll get into
that later.
And so the
church instead of
settling with the
victims,
the survivors,
they fight the
survivors.
They don't defend
the fatherless.
They fight the
fatherless.
And say we're
not to blame.
And what did
they say?
The first amendment
protects us.
In other words,
their argument was,
we are protected
under the first
amendment to not
defend the fatherless.
We don't have
to report these
things.
And they won.
The church won.
And I don't
disagree with the
decision.
I'm a proponent
of the big
proponent of the
first amendment.
And I can
met in the
court site.
Well,
congratulations,
I guess.
You do have
the first amendment
not to live
your covenants Congratulations.
I mean did
you call back
this all like
we won?
You don't have
to live our
covenants anymore We
don't have to
defend the fatherless.
I mean is
that that might
play out well
in the courts
of man It's
not gonna play
well in the
courts of Jesus.
He says it's
not going to
So you hide
in the first
amendment to violate
covenants because you
have covenanted those
scriptures wrongly onto
the old Testaments
there too Isaiah
chapter 1 verse
17 will go
over later
After he rich
you apart from
making covenants in
the temple and
they coming out
and not defending
the fatherless If
you want to
stay there make
that argument Can
you imagine Jesus
in court making
that argument?
I don't want
to defend the
fatherless better than
a millstone be
hung by their
neck sure Lessons
little suffer the
little children for
such with the
kingdom of God
sure,
but I Jesus
will not defend
the fatherless and
I have the
first amendment to
protect me.
No,
he would never
do that if
you represent him
you shouldn't either
Just go on
he's not done.
We're not even
close to being
done
Hearken not,
this is verse
16,
Hearken not into
the words of
the prophets,
the prophets I
have to you.
They make you
vain,
they speak a
vision of their
own heart and
not.
Found a mouthful
of the Now
I want to
say this.
I don't blame
the 12.
Because Isaiah 52
and other places
talk about the
good watchman.
There's good watchman
in the vineyard
that come out
of this.
Okay,
Dr.
Cummins 101 will
get the net
talks about that
as well.
The parable of
an open vineyard.
So just know
of it.
There's good ones
there.
Okay,
and I'm talking
about the good
ones there.
They're all through
this story as
well.
Story.
My story,
look at this
face of God
is using my
story to help
see it as
he uses stories
to to emphasize
prophecy and scriptures.
And that's why
I'm going to
say,
oh,
I want to
do this.
But here I
am.
I have to
do it.
do would be
whole verse 19.
A whirlwind of
the Lord has
gone forth in
fury,
even grievous,
whirlwind.
It shall fall
gravely on the
heads of the
wicked.
In the latter
days,
the next verse
20,
in the latter
days,
he shall consider
it perfectly.
Wardling both those
things.
In the latter
days,
Isaiah chapter 2,
verse 2,
also says latter
days.
The context is
latter days.
It's all latter
days.
And pay attention
to that word
of whirlwind.
We're going to
wardling that back
to doctrine count
as one-twelfth
in a second
here.
Okay,
Casey's talking about
the same thing.
Can't any hide
himself in secret
verse 24?
In secret places,
then I cannot
see them?
Say,
the Lord?
I have heard
what the prophet
said.
prophesied lies in
my name,
saying,
I have dreamed,
I have dreamed.
long shall this
be in the
heart of the
prophets that prophesied
lies?
Yeah,
they are prophets
of the deceit
of their own
hearts.
We also call
it the precepts
of men.
When you use
the precepts of
men over Jesus,
you worship the
works of your
own hand.
That's idolatry.
Isaiah talks about
Isaiah 44.
He talks about
idolatry constantly.
Don't think of
just like statute
for us.
We'll go to
anything of your
hands.
You worshiping yourselves.
And those of
us that you
persecute,
we're not scared
of.
We're going to
talk later about
Jason Morrison,
if we are
the people in
Latter-day Chad,
of Zion Media
and other places,
you're persecuting them.
You sent no
trespass orders done
because they've chosen
to help children
and expose it.
You need to
understand,
we don't think
of you like
you think of
yourselves.
We don't.
Okay,
we don't care
about kissing your
ring and sitting
in your pew.
So you think
you think Jason
pressed him,
but I'm not
working with him.
I can't vouch
for what he's
doing other than
I respect him.
He's giving voice
to children and
people who have
been hurt.
But he's not
scared of you.
All you're doing
is energizing the
base and bringing
more attention to
who you are
in the screen
for starring.
We only kiss
the ring,
which has come
with a broken
heart and a
contract spirit.
So you think
that we so
badly want to
get back in
that we'll even
what fly and
say we did
didn't
do is not
working.
Any organization or
government who has
ever utilized censorship
were never the
good guys in
history.
Just go back
in 20th century.
Starts with censorship
never becomes the
good guess.
But that's what
you're doing.
He talks more
about that later.
Behold,
he says,
I am against
the prophets of
the Lord that
steal my words
every one of
them from his
neighbor.
You know,
I am against
the prophets of
the Lord that
use their tongues
and say he
say,
you know,
I'm against them
that prophesy false
dreams say it
to the Lord.
I sent them
not nor commanded
them.
Therefore they shall
not be prophetess
people at all.
Say it to
the Lord,
that's verse 30
for 33.
You have perverted
the words of
the living God,
the Lord of
hosts.
Our God,
when you when
you violate and
contradict and turn
it over on
its head,
the words in
doctor comes once
21 and 102,
like the state
president is doing.
As God,
underneath the fraction
of people like
him,
a person.
That's exactly what
you're doing.
You're worshipping the
works of your
own hands and
yourselves.
Soaps.
And not kind
of.
That's why you're
not afraid of
God.
Right,
you're afraid of
man.
Because everything is
with man.
Ezekiel 34.
Let's talk about
Also,
end times,
these are all
end time profits.
You know that.
You teach that
at least.
But then you
don't want to
get into the
words.
And you get
rid of people
like me.
I'd excommunicated right
now.
I,
you know,
again.
But you can't
do it twice.
I'm freed from
the vineyard.
But I love
And Jesus was
a vineyard.
So I'm not
going to leave
it alone.
Because I love
it.
I'm doing it.
I love it.
Ezekiel 34.
And the word
of the Lord
came unto me
saying,
Son of man
prophesied against the
shepherds of Israel.
Who are the
shepherds of Israel
in the end
times?
prophesied and sent
to them.
Thus see it,
the Lord God
unto the shepherds.
Who will be
to the shepherds
of Israel?
they
themselves.
Should not the
shepherds feed the
flocks.
You kill them,
they're fed,
you feed not
the flocks.
How do you
feed yourselves?
can tell you,
my stake presence.
I know dopamine
hits when I
see them,
because I do
with that world
of addiction.
You feed yourself.
You confuse the
spirit,
I think,
with the dopamine
hits you get
from exuding or
righteous dominion.
You love it
in the moment,
and then you
start shaking and
fix it.
you start falling
off and you
don't know what
to do,
then you get
back to the
dopamine hit and
stop the spirit.
I love this
moment.
I'm in the
hands.
The disease,
have you not
strengthened,
neither have you
healed that which
was sick,
neither have you
bound up that
which was broken,
neither have you
brought,
again,
that which was
driven away,
neither have you
stopped that which
was lost,
but with force
and with cruelty,
have you ridd
them?
I testify to
you that me
and my family
and my extension,
many kids,
were in fact
ruled by force
and ruled by
cruelty.
There's nothing but
cruelty in this
whole story.
He's talking about
you guys.
Who is he?
He is talking
about you guys.
was
the face of
the earth and
dunded search or
seek after the
vessels.
So no shepherd
neither did my
shepherd search for
we've flown but
the shepherds fed
themselves.
I am against
the shepherd says
the Lord in
Ezekiel 3410.
I am against
the shepherds and
I will require
my flock at
their hand and
cause them to
cease from feeding
the flock.
Neither shall the
shepherd feed themselves.
Verse 11 thus
say the Lord
God behold I
even I will
search my sheep
and seek them
and I'm speaking
on behalf of
all those people
who have the
same story I
do and there
there's thousands of
them there's thousands.
Guys you are
protected you're safe.
Jesus comes for
you.
sends shepherds.
Look read the
scriptures the good
parts of all
these prophecies.
He will send
shepherds and watchmen
from the vineyard.
The good ones
watch for them.
They will come
out.
They all will
make themselves known.
Follow Jesus and
he will point
you in the
right direction.
But don't worry
you are not
if they violated
121 you are
not excommunicated.
They excommunicated themselves.
And I want
to just send
a warning and
an invitation to
repent of all
you.
state
who did remind
it and there's
a lot of
you.
Please repent.
You stand right
out.
Excuse me.
Just because a
guy above you
was corrupt.
He told you
to violate your
covenants and you
did it.
You can't put
it on them.
If you violated
one's 21,
if you didn't
have a council,
and Nancy wanted
to say that
you have to,
if you weren't
Matthew 5 and
Matthew 18 can
play it.
If you violated
one's 21,
all the attendant
consequences are upon
you.
I'm not going
to read them
again because it
breaks my heart.
Please repent and
go find those
people that you
hurt in the
name of Jesus.
While violating his
words,
please do that.
really need to.
The end times
are here.
Jesus is coming.
Okay.
But Tim,
we're still not
convinced.
We're still not
It's us.
It has to
be the Catholics.
has to be
somebody else.
The Jews,
whatever you say,
I've heard everything.
Okay,
let's keep reading
them because Isaiah
has a lot
to say about
this.
Let's go to
Isaiah.
Isaiah is.
Isaiah is the
900 pound gorilla
of the end
prophets.
That's why Jesus
commanded us in
1st Nephite 23,
1st 1,
this a commandment
I give unto
you,
study diligently the
words of Isaiah.
How many do
you think?
Huh?
The jokes that
we say in
Test of My
Meeting,
what,
I got to
Isaiah and I
got,
uh-huh.
You're not gonna
ha-ha and
very soon here.
It's life or
death.
The whole vision
is there.
The rest of
the story that
marvelous work in
a wonder is
there.
Before I start
getting into Isaiah,
and I'll talk
later about Isaiah.
I want to
give you my
personal experience with
Isaiah.
My personal journey.
So you know
I published a
bunch of books
with the church.
Those are the
projects of social
research I never
did.
But somehow I'm
still looking at
them all.
They're all a
lot of them
in front of
me.
Huh.
But I published
these books,
okay?
The American Covenant.
You can't-
it's all about
the Covenant.
It's all about
Okay?
What was I
writing about?
This is important.
This my journey
into Isaiah.
I wrote my
books up through
1st Nephi 13
and assimilated it
with history.
Proving that it's
real.
Proving the vineyard's
But my last
book,
the Pilgrim hypothesis,
was a full
analysis of 1st
Nephi 13.
Columbus.
That's Columbus's son's
house right behind
me.
He's tuned back
there.
can see it.
I'm in the
land of Columbus.
Ah,
and he sees
the Pilgrim.
He sees the
revolutionary and he
sees the restoration.
And he'll submit
people 1st Nephi
13.
But understand what
he says.
He says at
that point,
first came right
13,
much of my
gospel was revealed.
Not all of
it.
Much of my
gospel.
We confused this
and want to
pretend that everything
happened.
The vast majority
of the prophecies
around Joseph Smith
haven't been fulfilled.
Because only much
of my gospel,
including the book
of Mormon,
was there.
So that's and
it's beautiful.
It's wonderful.
It's the building
of the vineyard.
Okay.
And in Joseph
Smith said,
by the way,
the scripted sample
dedication,
we are those
10 tiles.
to
You have plenty
of wordlings and
proof in the
text,
except Joseph said
it.
Of course,
if we believe
this false thing,
people say that
the most important
prophet is the
living one and
not the old
ones.
That's not what
Jesus said.
The only prophet
I can think
of,
that Jesus and
Nephi and Jacob
and others said,
need to read
is the dead
one called Isaiah.
He's still alive.
He's alive and
out at all.
So people have
not communicated,
I know,
concasters and they
said,
I'm just teaching
with Joseph Smith,
while the prophet
and our chief
nut today.
But Jesus told
us to listen
to Isaiah.
Isaiah 48 says,
are you not
declaring the vision?
Why are you
not declaring the
vision of all
things?
The alphanel make
a vision.
And we're not.
There's few inserts
of the manuals
this year for
Isaiah.
That doesn't seem
like a trying
to fulfill the
commandments.
Just search diligently
the words of
Isaiah.
We're supposed to
do it and
sometimes
People are persecuted
for having Isaiah
groups.
I've seen them,
I've talked to
them.
Stop fulfilling the
prophecy on the
wrong side of
the divine.
So I write
my books,
all these books,
up through 1st
Nephi 13.
Okay,
now what happens?
In 1st Nephi
14,
now Nephi saw
the whole thing
starting in 1st
Nephi 11.
He saw the
Isaiah vision.
John also posted
to see the
vision.
Nephi goes pencils
down in 1st
Nephi 14.
He's like,
I can't tell
you the rest
of the story.
And then he
says,
but John,
the apostle John
will tell you
the rest of
the story in
his vision.
The little trick
there though is
that John's book
like Isaiah is
also sealed.
So there's no
way around it.
have to unseal
it.
That's the final
exam.
So then you
get in.
So the what
is Nephi do
is,
if I can't
tell you myself
what I'm saying,
you have to
do that by
yourself with Jesus
alone.
And if the
prophets increase,
aren't declaring the
vision,
like Isaiah 48
said,
they are.
to
your own.
And maybe they're
smart and wise
in not doing
it because they
know that people
have to do
on their own.
Yeah,
I'm very welcome
to these other
prophets and praise
the good ones
who doing it
the right thing.
You're supposed to
do it on
their own.
They're supposed to
be doing it
on their own
too.
It's the final
example.
In my books,
when I went
pencils down,
Nief,
I also went
pencils down.
Okay,
and I never
got the chance
to get into
the other stuff
because they rip
my book stuff
to shelf.
They've been checked
in everything that
I was trying
to do.
And then lied
about having never
published my books.
that's okay.
I'm writing another
book.
I'll probably read
in an ancient
and everlasting covenant
of peace where
I do assimilate
the Isaiah prophecies
with world history
because this is
a worldwide covenant
like that.
55.
Come or take
out the covenant.
Isaiah 44,
subscribe to it
on your arm.
all people is
it fifty uh
as they have
44 actually talks
about that is
a 56 says
all are invited
everybody to Gentile
and everybody else
even the lowest
of the low
are invited to
take full this
cover that's where
we're at right
now okay geez
what makes this
it's very difficult
to think that
the government's gonna
be exactly like
we think it
is what you
have walked in
like my state
prison sorry that
reminds me at
the end of
this little segment
I'm gonna tell
you about a
crucial conversation back
to back to
president Pearson for
a segment a
crucial conversation happened
in the fall
of 2023 between
elder Hugo Martinez
why things are
great man he
called me in
my life when
we sent the
appeals that are
everybody read the
appeals letter this
was Kevin Pearson's
moment and whoever
else was part
of this we'll
find out the
positions that one
more chance having
sinned against the
cabinet having or
the state president
do the things
he had another
chance with the
appeals lettering read
the appeals
read what he
read all the
violations of scripture
there was a
conversation where I'm
going to get
to it by
the end of
this little segment
okay I'm going
to end with
that segment so
stay tuned until
we get to
that part now
their Martinez is
a good man
that appointment wasn't
his decision take
but I believe
this combination happened
so what do
we do when
Nephi says I
can't pencil it
down I can't
talk about it
you got to
read
John revelation and
you have to
read Isaiah so
instead of giving
you the vision
what he did
was he started
inserting Isaiah so
you have the
seal version that
you were supposed
to then unseal
and when you
unseal it you
know Jesus I've
never read a
book of scripture
that brought me
closer to Jesus
then Isaiah then
I can say
the book of
Mormon since one
third of Isaiah
is in the
book of Mormon
the part we
all skip it
think it's funny
it's not funny
you get to
know Jesus to
over Messiah very
well you get
to him talking
through his name
he's talking I've
had experiences I
can't even talk
about
And
they do it.
Now let me
give you a
little scriptural hack.
I call it
a hack,
but it's not
hard.
It's supposed to
be hard to
unseal this.
supposed to be
hard.
But once you
unseal it,
the book is
the clearest book
of all.
It's like it's
like a primary
book.
Once you unseal
it,
he makes it
difficult enough that
you have to
come to him
and he'll open
your eyes.
I've got three
ways.
Beautiful.
That's why I
love the book
of Mormon.
I read from
this one mostly.
The first edition,
I'll be from
the first edition.
Why?
Because this was
direct real to
him.
And unfortunately,
the headers and
the footnotes are
misleading.
They're not canony
scripts.
The headers and
the footnotes are
not canony scripts,
but it's sold
to you as
if they are.
And in the
headers,
they they oftentimes,
especially around Isaiah,
they take you
off the path.
It's not canonyes.
If it is,
tell us.
Otherwise,
read this one.
And there's also
stuff in the
body that text
I have to
describe.
I'm like a
talk about as
personal,
but there's stuff
that was deleted,
that changes meanings.
I recommend everybody
go on this.
Nature copying read
this but so
Nephi puts in
a final exam
which is Isaiah
Nephi also said
greater than words
by Isaiah read
it how many
time do I
mean references Because
it tells you
everything is an
end time Road
map And it's
very detailed It's
not vague when
you start done
sealing it.
It's like a
layer that goes
deeper and deeper.
It's very detailed
So let's talk
about it because
if you if
you if you
listen to especially
Nephi Jacob and
Jesus
And know what
they're saying about
Isaiah the chapters
they both from
So a good
hack is to
say what didn't
you fight put
in first So
it leads you
to see on
your own the
vision of all
things So well
there's blocks There's
there's like three
blocks so have
two blocks and
a floater my
god two blocks
and a floater
The first
walk.
The Nephi begins
with second Nephi
is Isaiah 48,
49,
and then Jacob
comes in 50,
51.
Jesus comes in
51,
52.
So 40,
Those are the,
those,
that's that first
walk.
And you can
read about it
in second Nephi
and third Nephi.
And everything else,
and then when
you,
when you unseal
that,
and you put
it in to
the open word
context,
and then you
see with Jacob,
Nephi and Jesus
say about it,
I can testify
to you at
that point.
This book cannot
not be true.
It should not
And I,
you'll understand what
I'm saying if
you do this
thing,
but you have
to put in
the words to
do it.
Now there's another
block that comes
in a second
Nephi,
which is second
Isaiah through Isaiah
14.
Lots of gems
in there too,
but a lot
of that I'm
not going to
talk about.
It's the consequences.
The King of
Assyria,
especially in chapter
10.
The King of
Assyria's code word
for what's going
on right now.
Geopolitically
we
is.
I know what
that is.
But you know
what that is,
okay?
It's an alliance.
The formal alliance
is starting.
Genocide,
killing children,
antichrist.
It's political Islam
and the sick
alliance with political
Islam and socialism,
communism.
so that,
that way the
alliance can be
made in every
country.
They're using his
leftist communists and
they're coming together
making a pact.
They call that
covenant of death.
I think 20
talks about this.
And unfortunately,
some of the
Mormon Gentile leaders
are involved in
the covenant of
death.
Isaiah says that
what the governments
do,
the vineyard dance.
And I see
it happening.
Okay.
I propose to
you that this
Arizona case is
part of the
covenant of death.
You don't look
at the covenants,
but Jesus who
gets all about
how can I
figure this out
with man?
That fails.
It's a death.
It dies.
It leads to
nothing.
But destruction and
the king of
Syria and this
alliance has already
begun the genocide.
And they're hitting
the promised lands.
Of course,
I've been out
there.
I've been working
I'm trying to
rescue the Christians
and the Jews
and the Jews,
people or the
tropics are being
fulfilled.
So that's the
other block.
Second,
if I through,
I'm sorry,
second Isaiah,
through second through
14 Isaiah.
And then the
floater,
what's the float?
This is interesting.
And by the
way,
the hack I'm
teaching you,
how can you
have been taught
that before?
Because you're discouraged
by the institution
for studying Isaiah
because why?
It's obviously why?
Because the indictment
is on the
vineyard.
And so they
don't want you
to read it.
They're hiding.
And then many
scholars won't go
there very deeply
because their paycheck
is attached to
the vineyard.
Look for the
scholars whose paycheck
is not attached
to the vineyard
and they're more
free and more
open.
Unfortunately,
some of them
have been executed
for publishing their
books on this.
Sure stories.
Okay.
So the floater
is,
and it's kind
of it's kind
of laced throughout
a few chapters.
Isaiah 29.
The principles are
there.
And there's another
floater that's beautiful.
When it been
a recount Isaiah
53,
beautiful
beautiful chapter in
all of Isaiah
above our Savior
Jesus Christ the
prophecy that everything
would happen to
me he appears
to be arrested
he'd be killed.
Yeah it's beautiful
it's so deep
and layered so
those are the
floater so let's
talk about Isaiah
29 the floater
what is it
it's the indictment
it's another indictment
it's repeating the
themes of Ezekiel
and Jeremiah and
it's
absolutely okay so
let's start with
Isaiah 29 it's
like that in
the book of
Mormon Isaiah 29
what does it
say where for
the Lord said
for as much
as this people
he's talking about
in the end
time covenant leaders
for as much
let's go back
to 28 real
quick to make
sure you understand
that he is
talking about them
because that's the
first argument they're
to make it's
not us is
everybody else but
us
which kind of
28,
is the cup
with in my
opinion with the
idea 29.
Whoa to the
crown of pride.
Chapter one.
What the crown
of pride to
the trumpards of
E from.
But in time,
who's in time
E from?
It's the assimilated
Gentiles.
They're assimilated into
Israel.
But they're still
Gentiles,
the Josephus,
and as the
book won the
complaint,
there it points
out clearly.
Every time it's
like what the
Gentiles will be
cut off,
are they sent
against the gospel?
Again,
back to the
Prince Y just
taught from 121.
You can't be
cut off from
something or severed
from something you're
not a part
of.
So the Gentiles
will get cut
out like in
35,
16,
for example.
It's us.
The ones who
are cut off
do it.
Do a Google
search on where
it says cut
off.
And it's talking
about us and
Josephus said it
to Isaiah says
it to.
Whoa to the
crown of pride
to the trumpards
of E from.
His glorious beauty
is a fading
flower.
Why is it
a fading flower?
Because they're not
doing what the
pioneer to.
But Josephus Smith,
that generation,
did.
They're living off
the laurels of
them.
And
kind thing,
those stories.
While they're fulfilling
all the prophecies
and the end
times on the
wrong side of
the divide.
If you're proud
of Pride,
truncers of you
from not drunk
with wine,
drunk with...
This long,
tough,
emotional,
and idolatry with
pride.
And the glorious
beauty is on
the head of
the fat valley.
She'll be a
fading flower.
See?
The flowers fading.
That's just,
I'm sorry,
that's where we're
at.
The examples are
everywhere.
But they have
also aired through
wine and through
strong drink are
out of the
way,
priests and the
prophet.
Again,
who are the
priests and prophets
in the last
days?
He also used
the word seer
and drunk with
wine from.
On and on
and on.
They air and
vision,
they stumble and
judgment.
For they have
made lies or
refuge in utter
falsehoods,
help we hit
ourselves.
The theme of
this,
the title of
Backfire could have
been the Doug
Anderson line.
Let talk about
Doug Anderson real
quick.
I don't usually,
I try to
be careful.
I try be
very,
very careful my
judgment,
so people,
Doug Anderson is
liar.
Others chose to
lie.
Like a stick
president,
I wouldn't say
the liar.
But he did
value his covenants.
I got into
the liar.
And he put
his name on,
I've been thinking
he just screwed
me by now.
But so concerning
it's just like
last week,
I think they
kind of hit
him for a
while after I
bought that letter
out for March
of 2025 and
kind of disappeared.
He's back.
He just made
a comment on
the John Dehlin
case.
Okay.
When someone lies
this badly,
you have to
assume everything's lie.
He's either paid
liar.
Maybe you can
justify that way.
Like many attorneys
can be that
way too.
He's a liar.
And the fact
that they still
have them out
after the letter
two years after
the letter went
out tells me
that they are
completely underpented,
completely proud of
people who have
them in place.
And they want
a lie.
That all that
did,
by the way,
was in current,
I called the
production team.
We got to
go faster.
They're totally underpented
about this.
So he said
something like John
Dehlin.
He said,
it's not,
it's,
you know,
the church is
suing John Dehlin.
And people are
so
comes out and
what does he
say?
Oh,
has nothing to
do with censoring
people?
And that's to
do with people
getting confused with
branding and all
this stuff.
whatever.
Anything he says,
I have to
assume it's a
lie.
Because he's willing
to lie.
And if they
send him on
the camera,
have to assume
it's a lie.
This man could
very easily be
indicted for what
he did.
Because he led
the charge publicly
at in likely
violating federal election
law.
And I'll talk
later about Biko
conspiracy.
Okay,
but he's the
guy on the
camera.
And by the
way,
I'm no fan
of John Dehlin.
John Dehlin takes
punches at me
all the time.
Okay,
birds of a
feather.
Who's taking punches
at me?
Doug Anderson,
John Dehlin,
Traffickers,
ISIS.
Birds of a
feather.
Okay,
look what I'm
doing.
We're risking kids
all over the
world.
But your friends
use a no
-no.
But the fact
that he's still
could
very concerning to
everybody.
For we have
made lies our
refuge and our
falsies have we
hid ourselves.
Now we know
we're talking about
in chapter 29,
the floater block
in the book
of Mormon.
Wherefore,
verse 13,
chapter 29,
wherefore the Lord
said,
for as much
as this people
draw near me
with their mouth
and with their
lips to honor
me,
but have removed
their hearts far
from me.
And their fear
towards me is
taught by the
precepts of men.
And the precepts
of men rule
the dead.
Simply worship their
hands,
their idol tree,
which means they
worship themselves.
And they talk
about from this
time,
we'll spring the
marvelous work in
a wonder.
The most we're
going to wonder
hasn't happened yet.
Only much of
it has happened.
First day 513,
only much of
it has happened.
The rest is
about to help.
It's mostly good
news guys.
I'm sorry to
focus on the
bad news stuff,
but that's what
happened to you
right now to
rescue kids.
So I can
defeat these people
who lie.
Well,
into them.
This is verse
15 of Isaiah
29.
Well,
into them,
this seek to
hide their counsel
from the Lord.
works
the dark and
they say who
see us and
who know if
us.
Surely you're turning
of things upside
down.
She'll be as
deemed as the
potter's play.
For sure the
work say of
him that made
it.
He made me
not.
For sure the
thing frame say
of him that
framed it.
He had no
understanding.
I'm to give
it a real
life experience.
Example of it.
The first counselor
who I was
trying to talk
to in beginning
until he admitted
he liked me
and then I
stopped talking to
him.
I think he's
a good guy.
I like him
even trying his
hardest but he
thought his safety
wasn't following Kevin
Pearson to stick
president.
Let me tell
you what's going
on here.
Guys when you
worship the works
of your own
hands your precepts
have made it.
You functionally become
Jesus to be
like to take
president in first
counselor.
You functionally become
Jesus.
And so this
is why Isaiah
20 nice talking
about.
He didn't you
don't know me.
Who did you
know?
You knew you're
stuck president.
You knew you
knew it kept
in person.
And you think
that's Jesus but
it's not.
These are the
false checkers.
Stop it.
That's why you
don't know him.
You think if
you go in
and you're back
on the head
and say you're
fine because you
answer 15 questions
and
you're fine and
you're not fine.
Unfortunately,
Jesus is that,
that's why you
don't know them.
Because you just
think they're safety
and just doing
what they say.
There's not safety,
look,
I'm reading.
Look,
what's happening?
There's not safety
in that.
But this,
this,
this first counselor,
he knew I
was innocent.
Well,
he,
he's the one
who said,
just go like
a lamb little
slaughter and talk
about that already,
how that will
open his face,
second,
he fits 288.
He came to
our ward,
they visit our
ward,
they don't know
the state presence,
he visits sometimes
the ward and
he was visiting
the ward.
take the sacrament,
I've never not
taken the sacrament.
I never from
day one.
I'm not going
to stop leaving
my covenant because
they don't live
theirs.
Jesus is real
to me.
The book of
Mormon is real
to me.
Isaiah is real
to me,
okay?
So I'm taking
the sacrament because
I always do
because I refuse
to not leave
my covenant.
And I'll never
give you baptized.
That's also worshiping
a golden calf.
That would have
been offensive to
Jesus.
They would want
me to just
make it alive.
Others have done
this.
Just say you're
guilty of something
and so we
don't look bad.
is
fear of man
thing?
I will not
offend my savings.
So that's like
I have this
but the first
counselor The first
counselor came to
saw me take
the sacrifice and
Some of my
kids and other
said he's kind
of freaked out
He was like
he went like
What is Tim
doing even though
he knows I'm
in his This
what it is
talking about the
principal teaching right
now
If they did
it and it
had to have
a fence because
they are Amazing
with their ring
that we kiss
their kids He
couldn't believe he
couldn't fathom a
world Where Jesus
is looking at
me saying Tim
they screwed up,
I'm Jesus Jehovah
Don't worry about
it.
They didn't take
your priesthood away.
They lost their
priesthood Okay,
their world
Jesus
functionally,
they wouldn't say
this intellectually because
they don't think
that deeply,
which is the
whole problem here.
Because the script
is telling you
to search diligently
things like the
word of Isaiah.
That's called thinking.
They don't think
people have that's
the problem.
But in his
world,
Jesus is like
this little wallflower
that's like,
oh,
just think,
I don't care
if I'm Doug
Anderson,
they all lied.
And they took
a priesthood away
and there's nothing
I can do
because I'm just
a wallflower.
Jesus Christ is
King.
Jehovah.
You can't do
this to him.
He's not going
to.
There's a book.
There's a book
every member that
far outweighs the
book in the
state presence,
first officer in
the little system.
This is Tim's
six communicated.
That means nothing.
The book of
remembrance.
I made covenants
in April,
1999 in the
San Diego Temple.
Those are real
covenants.
They're going to
the veil.
Understand this.
We have to
separate membership and
covenants.
We shouldn't have
had to do
that,
but because of
the action we
have to.
that.
That's going through
the veil with
my wife and
me and my
family in Jesus.
What's not going
through the veil
is this cabal
of lies,
this dumpster fire
of lies from
Kevin Pearson,
Doug Anderson,
the state credit
and all in
everybody else.
Everybody else,
I know about
the email that
went out.
But the Pearson,
they send an
email out to
the general authorities
in the fall
of 2023.
Don't talk to
two.
In other words,
everybody sin against
Jesus.
Don't be Matthew
five.
Don't be that's
why Mark Bradwood
talks to me.
I'm not judging
Mark Brad or
people like the
Martinez.
I'm not.
But it wasn't
their decision.
But but but
that email went
out.
Okay.
This is so
cowardly by any
objective standard.
Wouldn't you agree,
President Pearson?
Wouldn't you agree
that's super cowardice,
but he did.
Loved lies over
the vineyard wall
at me and
then but not
the hatch closed
the doors,
poured up the
wall,
send emails out
to people.
Don't talk to
team
him and then
when you're caught
in March 25th,
you run off
to Europe.
That is so
cowardice,
so unmanly.
That's around this
time.
By any objective
standard,
that's just pure
cowards.
So that's why
I have to
have this talk
to public.
So I said,
29 says it
to you and
there's a word
link over there.
Remember the word
link from Jeremiah?
So if you
still don't believe
me,
that's who he's
describing the end
time leaders,
not all of
them.
Dr.
Incubinance 112 just
follow the word
links.
Follow the word
12 DNC 112
23,
very,
I say to
you,
darkness covered the
earth and gross
darkness the minds
of the people.
That's right out
of Isaiah.
Isaiah 60 verse
one through two
uses this language
in times and
times.
The old vengeance,
vengeance come at
speedly upon the
in the inhabitants
of the earth
a day of
wrath,
burning.
Balakai go look
at Balakai.
End time,
end time,
time.
Malachi 3-4.
This is the
burning,
right?
Before the Lord
comes.
I prefer the
Lord to come.
A day of
desolation,
a weeping of
mourning and of
limitation has a
whirlwind.
It shall come
upon all the
face of the
earth,
say the Lord.
Turn to March
23,
19,
remember?
The whirlwind,
whirlwind.
End times,
end times,
end And upon
my house,
shall it go
forth,
and from my
house to link
go forth,
say name earth.
upon my house,
it shall begin.
And from my
house,
it shall go
forth,
say it's Lord.
First among those,
here we are
again,
in fact two,
Isaiah 29,
repeating the same
words.
First among those
among you,
say the Lord,
who have professed
to know my
name,
and have not
known me,
and have blasphemed
against me in
of
say the Lord.
Who is he
talking about?
He's talking about
the vineyard.
And if you
need more,
before prison all
died,
back before I
I think he
was seeing very
clearly.
And he told
you,
he wanted his
last post to
be Dr.
Incoffinance 101.
That is the
parable of the
vineyard.
And the vineyard,
it's not Joseph
Smith going into
Missouri.
There might be
some foreshadow there,
but if it
was Joseph Smith
going into Missouri,
he didn't fulfill
anything.
He didn't do
The DNC 101
versus 44-366
tell you he's
gonna do.
Again,
it might be
a foreshadow.
But read it,
tell their home,
President,
I told you
to read it.
Identify the watchman,
the watchman,
the false shepherds,
that they're called
the watchman.
And they failed.
He says a
great evil is
found in the
vineyard.
That great evil
is persecuting people.
It's running cover
and hiding that
in First Amendment.
And not defending
the fatherless like
Isaiah,
chapter one,
and
other ages and
Luke 17 do
tell you to
do.
That's what it
is.
And then it
also says they
gave their money
to the exchangers
instead of building
the tower.
Do they need
what percentage of
the money tides
go to the
exchangers versus going
to do what
Jesus would do.
People dying everywhere
I go.
People I've never
received money.
I haven't asked
for any money.
But it's like
I Jesus would
be rescuing the
kids,
defending his fatherless.
But instead we
give the money
to the exchangers.
Yes,
we give great
checks to units
of millions and
all.
That's great.
But as a
comparison,
are they giving
money to the
exchangers?
That fit the
prophecy.
Read it.
Diennes,
you 101,
44,
36,
36.
it.
Read it all.
I'm going to
now end this
segment.
You know,
I'm here.
I want to
do this here.
Columbus.
Look at this.
This is a
great book.
If want want
to read a
really good book,
Columbus and the
quest for Jerusalem.
So on this,
it's been a
third and fourth
journeys.
He discovered this
island.
started going to
space up.
it
That's in the
book that I
never published with
the church.
One of the
topics the social
research I never
did,
it's called the
book of my
publicism,
or I talk
about clubs because
he's in 1st
-day 5th-13th.
He's the man
among the Gentiles
with the spirit
dates here.
So it's really
interesting because in
1st-day 5th
-13th much of
an explain leads
to 1st-day
5th,
14th and into
2nd-day 5th
and Isaiah gets
unsealed.
Christopher Columbus unsealed
Isaiah.
And he recognized,
but if I
said he would
recognize,
that he was
part of the
end-time movement,
even though he
knew he wasn't
going to live
for that part,
he said it
between his third
and fourth journey
and his humbling
experience after being
beat up and
destroyed by his
enemies.
So much might
I could relate
to the story.
He wrote a
book called El
Libro de las
Professives,
book of the
prophecies.
And he gave
it to the
queen and said,
preserved this.
It wasn't even
translated as Spanish
into 1984.
Five hundred years
later,
it wasn't translated
into English into
like 1992.
And then when
scholars got it,
just made some
of it,
they put fun
of it.
fun
is trying to
study idea,
the whole thing,
if read the
book,
having unsealed Isaiah,
you know what
he did.
He unsealed Isaiah,
and he made
certain references that
at least partial
fulfillment were happening.
If you go
into the tomb,
the tomb was
right behind me,
that's his tomb,
where arguably some
of his bones
or all of
his bones might
be,
or at least
some of them
at least,
Isaiah's all over
the walls.
He said all
I did by
finding the new
world was fulfill
the words of
Isaiah.
It's literally engraved
in the tomb.
And Isaiah 49,
verse one and
verse six,
he said he
was partly fulfilling
that by being
a messenger,
bringing Christ Christal
fed ends.
That's his name
on his journey.
He said that
means the Christ
bearer.
He brought Christ
here.
People love Jesus
here everywhere.
Because a man
amongst the Gentiles
brought it here.
Then he fulfills
the prophecy.
He unseals,
he follows Nephi's
instructions.
So no wonder
Nephi saw him.
hopeful
That's why I
love this place.
But I'm going
to tell you
about the crucial
conversation.
In the fall
of 2023,
Elder Hugo Martinez
called me in
my way for
a different position.
I remember exactly
where I was.
It's one of
those calls that
brought tears to
my eye.
I was suffering
so much.
And he called
me having read
the letter.
You all get
to read it.
I'm attaching it.
Read the appeals
that are read
what Hugo Martinez
read.
And I have
to believe gave
to Kevin Pearson.
Kevin Pearson,
who was likely
almost for sure
part of the
first day because
he ordered it.
We know that
he has one
more chance to
not break all
the cup of
it in one
in D2-1
-21 after 5
-15.
And all the
attendant consequences that
come up now
because he had
one more chance.
A crucial moment.
Brother Martinez called
me and he
said to me,
this is the
most compelling appeals
that are I
have ever read.
He then called
my wife wept
with her.
He wept with
her.
He says,
I'm going to
try to fix
this.
He's a good
man.
Unfortunately,
he didn't have
power.
over
So Kevin Pearson
read that appeals
letter and said
let's keep fulfilling
all the prophecies
on the wrong
side of the
divide.
Doubles down stamps
the name of
Jesus Christ on
this thing.
So all the
kids that got
hurt got hurt
because the name
of Jesus Christ
because of that
crucial conversation and
that moment to
violate again the
confidence.
Now do you
think it's any
surprise when I
tell you this?
In March of
2025 when that
then the second
letter okay the
appeals that are
was in in
the fall 23
the whole letter
that it's basically
the script of
everything I'm telling
you here.
I'll tell you
in a second
how they responded.
Not good.
When that letter
went out you
just heard in
the previous segment
Kevin Pearson with
only four years
goes off to
Europe.
Guess who else
took off?
Here you go.
Mark TNS.
Having only been
in the area
authority for three
years left was
here Senate out
of the out
of the area
of presidency.
The other counselor.
I think his
name was Elder
Smolts.
He timed out
the year before.
He turned 70.
So everybody ran
away.
How cowardice.
So the new
guys came in
and nobody would
know when we
were talking,
but guess what
we're all talking
about?
I'm bringing you
up back to
the table and
holding into a
count in the
name of Jesus
Christ for what
you did in
his name.
One more thing
I want to
say to you
guys.
To the state
presidents.
You need to
repent.
Kevin Pearson or
any area for
you told you
to violate your
company's and you
did.
I said it
before I'm going
to say it
again.
And go after
the flop that
you hurt.
You know the
ripple effect is
playing out worldwide
like my story,
but it's bad.
for
I hope you
repent.
The archetype for
this scenario,
just so you
know,
is the Nephi,
so all these
architects,
the Moses Exodus,
the Nephi,
the hike Exodus,
that's the archetype.
What did Laman
Alemius say?
They said what
likely President Pearson
and other go
say,
they don't repent.
Tritians of our
fathers,
they weren't not
religious,
they thought they
were religious,
let's go back
to Jerusalem.
We're keeping the
ordinances.
I'll talk about
that later when
Isaiah says about
ordinances,
in chapters one
in 66.
Let's go back,
let's go back,
let's go back.
And they beat
up the messengers.
The messengers end
up being the
remnant.
But they're gonna
come out,
you're redeemed.
Just repent,
don't be like
Laman and Laman,
and say all
as well as
I.
We have the
tritians of our
fathers,
please,
please don't do
it.
I love you
guys.
I know you
hate me for
saying this.
I'm beyond caring
about that.
I care about
what my maker
says,
but Jesus says,
I know he
wants me to
save this.
No,
he wants me
to save this.
In the meantime,
everybody.
It's hard when
I hear a
person talking about
COVID.
But I would
say listen to
his words.
That's what Jesus
said to the
people when he
was confronted by
the temple leaders
2,000 years
ago in that
period.
Listen to their
words,
don't follow their
actions.
Listen to their
words,
don't follow their
actions.
So listen to
the words of
Kevin Pearson that
he said,
one year after
allegedly leading his
entire mass a
year later,
he said this,
listen to his
words,
don't follow his
actions.
There is among
some a growing
sense of spiritual
apathy and casual
covenant keeping,
that is becoming
increasingly common among
those who should
know and do
better.
Covenant keeping has
nothing to do
with personal preference
and convenience and
everything to do
with commitment.
I am confident
sacred
better understood,
would be honored
and cherished above
all other commitments.
When I made
reference to how
Deseret News paraded
the Doug Anderson
lie and then
doubled down with
their own lie,
I presented a
question as to
whether these people
are going to
continue to try
to lie better
or repent better.
Now I'm going
to tell you
what they chose
to do.
They chose to
lie better or
deceive better because
I'm going to
now tell you
what a lot
of you are
asking,
how did the
church respond when
you sent the
letter in March
of 2025 that
explained all of
this?
How did they
respond to me
directly?
We know how
they responded by
moving people around
the world to
try to hide
them.
But how did
they respond to
me?
they sent it
representative.
This was their
response.
Now,
I'm sorry this
is disturbing what
I'm going to
tell you.
I've screened this
with good people,
bishops,
state presidents,
not mine of
course,
but others who
are just like,
this is the
part,
they were just
the hardest for
them and for
me too.
manifests
so fair,
so that it's
cool,
nothing else you
can say.
I asked from
Matthew T.
Compliance.
I asked for
a meeting with
other bed-narrer
with Elder Rennlin.
I asked to
meet with somebody
who could just
sit down and
have an honest
conversation.
When I heard
the response,
they sent a
representative outside the
Vineyard Walls will
say,
to come meet
me.
Here's what they
said to me.
But before I
tell you that,
before I tell
you that,
I'm to tell
you why I
am right now.
This is significant.
This is Ecuador.
Beautiful Ecuador.
Elder Ballard.
He personally told
us that he
set apart my
son,
my oldest son.
He personally chose
this mission for
my son.
We feel his
presence here.
It's a beautiful,
spiritual place.
It's funny.
I feel Elder
Ballard here a
lot.
I've thought about
what they're doing
now.
I imagine it's
gone through their
PR machine to
say,
let's double down.
Let's say that
Elder Ballard did
cut him off,
even though we
have a phone
call documenting that
he didn't.
But look what
they did.
This happens when
you lie.
Okay?
And lies begin
to lie.
and
and when you
deceive,
it just creates
further problems.
Oh,
the tangled webs
we weave when
it first,
we practice to
deceive.
If they were
to double down
on the elder
-bellared lie,
in their lie
narrative,
they painted elder
-bellared as a
covenant breaker,
as someone who
would just disregard
the words of
Jesus,
and Matthew 5,
Matthew 18,
they made him
that,
they'd have famed
him.
So they can't
really double down.
we kind of,
I don't know,
Jesus has them
quartered not me,
I'm not doing
this.
It wasn't that
hard,
but it's devastating.
And what's really
devastating is I'm
here in Ecuador,
and you know
why I'm here?
I'm dressed like
this because I
just met with
the first lady
of Ecuador.
And all of
our projects around
the world and
in Ecuador have
been stalled,
because of this
lie.
And so naturally,
and what I'm
going to tell
you is happening
all over the
world,
I'm working in
Europe,
Israel,
these competitions have
an everywhere in
Latin America,
because they have
to come to
me.
They have to
come to me,
and they have
to ask me,
why did the
LDS Church say
that you never
did projects with
them?
Are you lying
to them,
or are they
lying?
What do you
me to do,
guys?
Life for you?
is
you want me
to do?
And did you
do product with
the church?
Tim,
did you not
do product with
the church?
What's this extra
communication?
I got to
tell them the
process.
So literally to
get this,
and I clear
every vetting,
obviously you see
me around the
world.
You're losing these
debates.
They put me
on,
they meet with
me.
They put me
on their stages.
They're operating with
me.
Do understand the
damage it's causing
to you?
Because they now
realize that your
life's hurting their
children.
This wasn't just
a betrayal to
me and my
family into countless
children.
You're now betraying
the saints in
Ecuador.
And everywhere else.
I drove by
the temple.
It's a beautiful
temple in Kites.
I prayed there.
Outside,
I go outside.
I go to
church.
I'm active.
I don't talk
to them about
this.
I go because
I love being
there.
Now what are
you going to
do?
The heads of
states all see
this happening.
And they see
the multiple violations.
What example are
you setting?
Are you going
to ask your
members to lie
for you?
Like you asked
reportedly,
allegedly asked Israel
news to lie
for you?
How far you
let this go?
every day that
you don't talk
to me,
you violate Matthew
5 and Matthew
18 and Dean
C102 and the
entire spirit of
Jesus Christ.
So don't get
mad at me
because of the
consequences that you
came to the
battlefield.
Remember,
I am living
the gospel of
Jesus Christ by
being honest and
by rescuing his
children in Ecuador
and beyond.
You are not
living the gospel
of Jesus Christ.
You are lying
and every day
you keep your
lie out,
you are lying
again.
Every time somebody
higher up learns
about the lie
and does nothing,
you are part
of that too.
This is a
woe.
woe upon everybody.
I hope you
understand the damage
that you are
causing your people
and the embarrassment
that you are
causing the saints
in Ecuador and
all around the
world.
I don't,
I wouldn't put
it past you
based on what
I have seen
to ask them
to lie.
But let me
tell you,
I am going
to get more
into this in
a minute,
but I want
to tell you
how they respond
it to me.
Okay,
they send a
representative to talk
to me.
It's my attorney.
And we said,
we're going to
if
what I'm doing
right now.
Ha,
you're gonna embarrass
me.
But you already
started off with
multiple lies,
so all you
can do to
embarrass me further
is what lies
some more.
Lai,
lai,
lai.
This is so
embarrassing.
Aren't you embarrassed
by now?
I am.
But I'm more
embarrassed if I
don't listen to
my savior and
rescue his children
and you're getting
in my way.
You're getting in
his way.
So here we
are.
The said that
we are going
to embarrass Tim.
I think you
already tried that
and how's it
going for you?
Also,
a conversation ensued
and we learned
a lot of
things about the
fall of 2023.
And I'm gonna
tell you about
right now.
In the fall
of 2023,
the PR committee,
or whoever it
was,
will find out
through depositions,
ordered a fake
investigation into me.
This is very
important to understand
how this came
to be.
violation
Matthew 18,
Dean's,
you one or
two,
and everything else.
Basically,
what they ordered
is to take
president to do,
to not let
me talk,
me have any
kind of defense,
not bring witnesses
in.
That's exactly how
they handle this
investigation.
They call all
my enemies.
Many of them
are going to
jail.
Are those the
ones you're going
to embarrass me
with?
I mean,
you're going to
bring them into
court with their
prison garb on,
and they're going
to spew more
lies.
Is that your
plan to embarrass
me further?
So they invite
all my enemies
who have been
co-opted,
compromised.
They're under criminal
investigation now in
multiple countries.
Those are the
people they invite
in,
and they get
the dirt they
want.
It's so gross.
This is so
gross,
this process.
And they don't
call me.
Intentionally,
why would you
call Tim?
Jesus told you
you have to,
but we're above
Jesus,
apparently.
So we don't
have to talk
to Tim,
even though Jesus
commanded you to
do that.
So they don't
talk to me,
and they get
the dirty story
they want.
So they can
give it to
Doug Anderson.
So they can
put
say
then I'm begging
for them on
day one,
but let me
come talk to
you.
No,
no,
stay present.
Same thing,
no witnesses,
no counsel.
This is so
embarrassing.
And everybody knows
it.
The first lady
of Ecuador,
her staff,
talk to my
staff.
I have lawyers
in every continent
and they have
to go respond.
They have more
than I have
than I'm even
telling you right
now.
And they sit
down,
it doesn't take
long.
And take that
long,
guys,
because it's so
obvious.
And that's what's
happening.
And it's going
to continue to
happen as I
live the gospel
of Jesus Christ
and rescue children
and be honest.
And you have
all covenanted,
by the way,
to wield the
sword of truth
in righteousness,
no matter what.
So if you're
not doing that,
you're in violation
of your covenants.
I don't know
how you think
you get around
this.
Jesus is coming.
He's coming.
And then this
representative finally says,
well,
I figured the
state president would
take care of
getting Tim's side
of the story.
That's what he
said.
The state president
wasn't even called
after
after the deformation
went out.
Remember,
because the first
guy wouldn't do
it.
Okay,
so they waited
till the next
guy to come
in.
So the damage
had been done
completely over the
top done.
And then the
state president still
didn't even let
me have my
witnesses and refuse
to be a
math and 18
compliant.
The damage was
done,
that's the whole
point.
They go back
later,
see this is
all the tangled
webs we weave
when it first
we practice to
deceive.
You keep having
to lie about
your lie,
lie about your
lie.
And that's what
the state president
continues to do,
by the way.
People who come
to me to
get a math
and 18 compliant
with me,
they're awesome.
takes,
you know,
when I sit
down with them,
it takes some
effort.
I'm going to
tell you something,
every person to
a person who
got math and
18 compliant with
me,
who sat down
and I showed
them the documents.
Not only were
they in tears,
but they said,
how can I
help you?
But that's only
1% of
people around me,
these Christian covenant
nobody came to
me.
Even when I
begged them to
come to me,
they wouldn't come
to me.
As I was
driving into Ecuador
two days ago,
to get ready
for the meeting
with the first
lady,
we're meeting with
the president later.
And I saw
this beautiful temple,
and I love
it.
broke my heart
because I knew
something.
I knew that
before we got
there,
the president,
the vice president
and the first
lady's staff had
to come ask
us because they
vet everybody.
They had to
ask my team.
Why did the
Mormon Church denounce
Tim Bauer?
Why is the
Mormon Church basically
saying Tim's lying
by saying he
ever did projects
associated with them
because they said
they didn't,
he didn't do
that.
You understand I
have a whole
team of attorneys
in almost every
country for sure
every continent and
I'm talking about
the work I'm
doing in the
Middle East,
in Europe,
the United States.
Do understand what
you're doing to
yourselves?
I have to
respond with the
truth so I
can rest your
children and so
you look horrible
and now they
know the first
lady hurt,
they all know,
they all know
what you've been
up to.
We're going on
three years now.
This should have
been a couple
weeks of,
oh we caught
this mistake,
we can't do
anything about it
because you,
why?
Because you're a
man and not
God?
What God's saying
about this?
Don't blame me
for this,
you want to
blame me.
I'm
gospel of Jesus
Christ by rescuing
children and being
honest about what
you people did.
You're not.
You're lying and
then you double
down in your
lies and then
you lie again.
So my question
is,
what are you
going to do
when the saints
in Ecuador?
There's a new
temple being built.
They just found
out.
It's beautiful.
I'm happy.
What are you
going to do?
The press is
going to start
asking you questions.
And you're just
going to say,
what?
We don't apologize?
That's what I've
heard.
I've heard that.
You've heard it
too.
I'm sorry.
I don't care
who said that.
That is false
doctrine.
Are you suggesting
that because the
word apology itself
wasn't translated from
the Hebrew or
the Greek?
Because the entire
gospel of Jesus
Christ is about
forgiveness,
repentance,
restitution.
And you're telling
me that Jesus
made an exception
to that?
Rule?
Oh,
you have to
do all that
stuff,
but don't apologize.
The book of
Mormon and the
Bible don't teach
that.
Is that what
you're going to
say?
Because that's what
you're saying.
And I'm seeing
that applied in
my life.
And I don't
even want an
apology.
never
I'm just talking
about how concerned
I am by
what you're all
manifesting.
You're gonna you
want to go
on the record
saying that we
don't apologize?
Okay I don't
want that but
can you just
retract your lie?
Because your life's
hurting kids.
Every day every
day I deal
with it every
day because the
internet's a real
thing and it
goes and goes
and your lie
just spreads and
spreads and spreads
and and you
do nothing to
stop it.
And so those
of you who
who didn't who
weren't part of
this but watch
it happen why
aren't you doing
something?
Why aren't you
stepping forward?
making good on
your covenant to
wield the sword
of truth and
righteousness?
Oh we can't
stand because the
lawyers people keep
saying that the
lawyers I don't
understand that.
That's that's what
the Book of
Warmer Teads do
not do is
rely on the
lawyers they don't
generally resolve things
in the way
that God would
have you resolve
them.
You're gonna meet
your maker every
one of you
that knew about
this and had
done nothing for
three years you
know that and
a title isn't
gonna help you
it might condemn
you further for
the hypocrisy of
Do you understand
this?
And now,
you know,
you can clearly
don't feel for
your God,
you're a man,
but now you
should fear man
because of what
you're doing,
because man is
now getting upset.
The Ecuadorian saints,
these are their
children we're trying
to rescue.
It's their children.
And the press
will ask you
questions.
Again,
I gave you,
we're going on
three years now
to do the
right thing.
Why are you
incapable of living
your covenants,
of honesty,
of integrity?
I hate that
I have to
do this.
I don't like
to reveal things
that are disturbing,
but I'm living
the gospel of
Jesus Christ by
doing it ironically.
I know I
am,
because Jesus wants
me to rescue
these kids with
these tapes.
I'm living the
gospel by being
honest and rescuing
kids.
You're not living
the gospel.
You're in violation
of your covenants.
I don't get
it.
Like what?
What's the plan
for the meeting
of the maker
time?
What is the
plan?
The lawyer said
I couldn't do
it.
I've heard that
since so many
people,
oh,
I would have
said something to
him.
I would have
helped you,
but the lawyers.
That means you're
scared of
man and you're
not scared of
God.
A little later
I'm going to
get into Isaiah.
I talk a
lot about Isaiah
because Jesus told
us in 3
Nephi 231 this
a commandment I
give unto you
to search diligently
the words of
Isaiah and I
have a whole
scriptural analysis as
a bonus episode
but I'm gonna
talk about it
in a it's
all end times
Jesus didn't give
you that because
he wants you
learn history he's
telling you what's
going to happen
Isaiah's full of
things that have
never happened yet
the things that
are going to
happen Isaiah chapter
2 verse 2
says it's gonna
be the last
days it's all
last days you
know this so
you you're the
covenant people in
the last days
who is that
what what I
see happening and
all through seminary
I've always taught
these things probably
innocently but what
we do as
the what we'll
call us the
Mormon Gentiles okay
all the good
stuff we say
is us and
all the bad
stuff is someone
else it's not
still us you
can't have your
cake and eat
So
is the indictment
on the end
time covenant communities.
That's what it
is.
And he goes
right to the
temple.
And he's most
upset about this.
I'll talk later
about it,
but he's most
upset about this
because of the
false sense of
security that all
is well and
Zion because I
can go to
the temple.
But you're under
more condemnation if
you come outside
the temple and
do bad things,
like lying,
like hurting people.
Chapter 11,
verse 11 through
17 gets into
this.
by some you
get to 17
after he condemns
these people for
violating their covenants,
he tells you
one main thing
that you could
stop doing.
And it's hurting
kids.
He literally says
it in verse
17.
It's like he's
talking about us
right now.
And then later
on he says
you have blood
on your hands.
That always bug
me.
I'm like,
I don't think
that blood on
their hands.
That's kind of
extreme.
This is all
Isaiah
I thought no
I can see
what Isaiah is
saying because I
see these kids.
I see what's
happened to them.
This is irreparable
guys.
There's nothing you
can do for
countless children who
have been left
in it in
rape hell or
worse because of
the lie.
You think the
lie in and
of itself is
the sin.
It's all the
ripple effects that
came about from
that lie.
That is on
you.
It really is.
Why do you
keep doing this?
keep drinking condemnation
to your souls?
It blows my
mind.
Well Tim,
we didn't do
it but you
know about it.
You know about
it and you
have power to
stop it but
you don't because
you're afraid of
man.
Oh everybody here
in Ecuador knows
that they're going
to know the
government knows.
In every country
I go to
this happens.
I've warned you.
I don't know
how many times
I need to
do it.
But
going to stop
risking kids,
and I'm not
going to stop
telling the truth.
I'm not going
to do either
of those things.
You can live
in breach of
covenant if you
want,
if you want
to roll the
dice,
and see what
a hell you're
with your maker.
I wouldn't bet
on those odds.
I know it,
I'm living it.
I've seen it.
I've seen how
bad it is,
and if you
haven't tuned in
to how bad
it is,
I'm sure Jesus
will show you
the video of
how bad it
is.
But you should
know,
and he'll expect
you to know
at this point.
In writing,
I have this
from April 7th,
an email,
I have it.
In writing.
We're going to
embarrass Tim,
if he does
this.
Bring it on.
I don't know
how more you
can try to
embarrass me than
you already have.
How many lies?
Someone who's watching
this,
you should count
the lies.
By the time
we're not even
close to being
done yet,
the lies continue,
it gets a
lot worse before
it gets better.
What they're going
to do now,
and they already
are doing,
is they're going
to say,
oh,
this was a
need your reaction.
We didn't know.
No,
was,
when we're in
court,
you're going to
find out they
knew about this
for a long
time for months.
Okay.
They were coordinating
and in communication
with my enemies.
They were even,
I have evidence,
they were even
in coordination.
I have documented
evidence that they
are coordinating with
the Attorney General's
Office.
It was all
time,
right?
They were going
to put out
the lie to
run cover for
the enemies to
take me down.
So their lie
would never be
discovered later because
I would never
survive this.
We have it
all.
We have the
timelines.
We have everything.
So this was
very,
very much premeditated.
But they're going
to lie about
their lives because
it's the only
play,
apparently in their
playbook.
The other thing
they're going to
do,
because the State
President does it
all the time.
I know this
because people who
come and get
Matthew and Dean
compliant with me,
they'll go to
him.
I don't ask
them to,
but they'll go
to him.
They'll what are
you doing?
How did,
and you hear
what he says,
right?
I'll do exactly
what he does.
He says,
you know this
much,
and I know
this much.
That's what he
does.
This is a
fake news.
politicians
this is we
call this the
fake secret information
tactic right we
know stuff that
you don't know
really mr.
Tech President doesn't
know anything he
hasn't even heard
the first word
out of my
mouth because he
wouldn't let me
talk he wouldn't
let me bring
witnesses and he
wouldn't have a
counsel it was
all fake but
he knows this
much and everybody
else that's what
people in the
church administration office
you're gonna go
this true that's
what they're going
to do those
in the know
they're gonna say
well we know
we we have
information you don't
have I can't
wait to get
to court and
by the way
the whole world's
gonna be watching
this court when
when we when
we go to
court for this
the whole world
is gonna be
watching because their
children's lives are
gonna be at
stake and I
will make sure
that I expose
all the further
hypocrisy that will
come out in
court I will
make sure because
it's part of
my mission to
rescue God's children
that's what they're
gonna do it's
a trick is
it's it's all
the hills okay
we have been
for I know
I'm gonna have
they have the
text messages that
you heard about
the enemies that
gave these siloed
the
they didn't even
give you page
one,
which explains what
everything else is.
It explains the
operation,
it's going towards,
they didn't see
that.
They have snipped
off recordings,
I know they
have,
I have everything,
they have.
They don't know
that I have
that,
and I'm not
going to tell
them how I
know,
but I know.
And if I
was there,
if people were
Matthew and can
plan,
I could explain
to them that
those recordings actually
are sculpatory in
my favor.
But I don't
get a chance
to talk about
it,
because they don't
want to talk
to me.
That's what you
do when you're
lying.
If you're open,
you talk to
the people.
If you're lying,
why do you
have to lie
to somebody?
If I'm guilty,
have the counsel.
come talk to
me.
If I'm innocent
and you want
me to be
guilty,
that's when you
violate your covenant,
and violate the
words of Jesus,
Matthew 18 and
Matthew 5.
Dean C-102,
and on and
on and on
and on on.
Okay,
so the proofs
right in the
pudding for you,
just how they're
doing this.
So they're in
collusion with the
General's Office who
opens also up
and we'll get
into this another
video.
That investigation has
been closed completely
because for lack
of evidence.
But it didn't
matter.
They knew that
would be the
case.
It was all
for public perception
and to destroy
my reputation.
To destroy the
work that I
was doing.
I've seen certain
LDS podcasters roll
their eyes like
Greg Mattson,
rolls his eyes.
Oh Tim says
Rico,
you heard me
mention Rico conspiracy.
Let me explain
this to you.
This is very
serious.
Again,
we wouldn't be
at this point
if they had
just been Matthew
18 compliant.
Can you remember
Matthew 5,
Matthew 18,
Matthew 5 says
if you're not
at Matthew 18
compliant,
you can physically
go to prison.
That's why it
says it.
This is the
application.
This could have
been resolved but
they refuse to
talk to me.
So I can't
control certain things.
So in a
Rico conspiracy,
anyone who touches
the ball is
potentially liable and
there's civil statutes
attached to this
as well.
Anyone who touches
the ball,
if you go
to a letter
to a member
of the church
example
I'm doubling down
on this and
I'm going to,
I mean everybody
is,
can carry liability.
Anyone can.
But you should
understand how RICO
works,
okay?
It's conspiracy.
You didn't have
to know the
whole plan.
You just had
to do your
part of being
dishonest and,
and whatever else.
And a couple
of those statutes
include,
the statutory requirements
is witness tampering.
was there witness
tampering going on
here?
They knew I
was running for
Senate.
The Deseret News
article says they
knew,
they knew,
they knew before,
they knew three
weeks earlier,
so I had
said I was
going to run
on the Shant
Spicer Show.
They knew that.
The Senator is
the greatest witness
for the people.
And they knew
that what I
would be witness
witnessing for,
for Okay?
Is that witness
tampering?
I'm sure you
can address this.
Yes,
those are all
racketeering elements that
fit nicely into
RICO.
So if anyone
touched the ball
around this and
did,
and that's,
that's,
that's where we're
The other thing
that this representative
said to us
after we gave
them the March
2025 letter was
this was this
was one of
the hardest parts
I think for
a lot of
the faithful members
that I showed
this information to
you.
This was hard.
It's really hard.
Talk about throwing
covenants out the
window in Jesus.
We don't even
look at you.
We don't need
you.
They don't need,
I think a
lot of these
people really think
Jesus is in
their pocket and
then they just
do what they
want and he
justifies it.
It doesn't work
that way.
Yeah,
that's like I
don't know gospel
101.
But but this
representative for the
church came to
me and said
under the First
Amendment we are
protected.
We can excommunicate
you for anything
we want.
In other words
bad haircut or
whatever we can
do that.
Okay.
Two problems with
that.
One again Jesus
out the window.
How would Jesus
take that?
How would that
play in the
courts of Jesus?
Okay.
And I'm a
very strong proponent
of the First
I
your right to
be able to
make that argument
I would.
The problem is
you can't hide
beyond the First
Amendment in a
situation where Rico
and other crimes
are involved.
You can't hide
by the First
Amendment and say
well we went
200 million miles
outside of our
policy and lied
and violated scripture
and all this
stuff that's our
First Amendment right.
Well wait a
minute what if
it hurt people
people that wanted
all over the
world who wanted
their children rescued
because Santa Freedom
2 would have
rescued their children
because of his
lie in large
part it wasn't.
People who wanted
the Santa Freedom
Act to be
passed which was
derailed immediately.
The docu film
hidden more that
was supposed to
come out in
2022.
How many kids
would have been
rescued before now?
I had a
book publishing deal
with Simon and
Schuster already inked.
They took that
book all about
how to rescue
kids by the
way.
The most important
book I've ever
written it would
be out by
now.
the
September 15th,
the day after
these people in
the church defamed
me,
they took that
book away from
me.
How many kids
would have been
arrested?
Did you see
the ripple effects
of this?
Okay,
it wasn't to
me,
it was to
everybody.
How many kids
didn't get rescued
because of these
things?
But so now
the public has
an interest in
you going 200
million miles outside
your policy.
Now it's their
interest they could
look at this
now.
You can't say
first amendment.
Because if you're
doing something and
furtherance of potentially
committing a crime
against children,
especially all over
the world,
now they could
come look and
say,
wait a minute,
why did you
go 200 million
miles outside of
your scripture and
policy?
Now it's the
public's business.
I hope you
understand that.
have attorneys that
can explain this
to you.
That is how
it works.
don't think that
Greg Matsin has
a lot of
legal background to
justify his eye
role about when
he said,
oh there you
go.
This is serious.
This is why
I try to
come to you
quickly and resolve
this quickly.
And you can
resolve it quickly.
But you're not
going to do
that because you
don't apologize.
Because you don't
make mistakes,
apparently.
I think that's
what this was
down to,
the myth of
infallibility.
We can't admit
to a mistake
because they might
think other things
are mistakes.
you put so
much stock into
this myth of
infallibility.
And you think
that's what your
safety is?
No.
Your safety isn't
put to any
truth because now
here we are
exposing the myth
and exposing what
is possibly criminal.
So I don't
care so much
about that as
much as I
care about getting
this resolved.
I wish you
just retract it
and leave you
alone.
But now we're
too late.
It wasn't just
me that you
all betrayed.
It was the
countless children that
you betrayed.
But worse than
that,
you betrayed the
saints here in
Ecuador and around
the world.
Because they're stuck
with your lie
and what are
they going to
say?
The longer this
goes on,
the more I
have to tell
the truth.
Are you going
to ask them
to lie for
you and put
their souls in
jeopardy?
Like you allegedly
told the desert
news to lie
for
you?
Is that you're
going to continue
that?
I can't believe
I'm if I
can't believe I'm
saying this to
these people who
think that they
run it think
that they're the
voice of Jesus
the irony is
so hard for
me.
This is the
this is the
fact and it's
because I love
the saints here
and their children
and all the
children that I
have to say
this.
Please don't ask
them to lie
for you and
put their souls
in jeopardy like
you have I
think people with
desert news and
other
places stop lying
stop lying Isaiah
says you're lie
go read Isaiah
chapter 28 he
literally says that
you're gonna say
that lies or
a refuge but
God's not gonna
catch us we
hide our counsel
from the Lord
read Isaiah 28
and times covenant
leadership covenant people
and times I
can't believe how
fulfilling
We're watching it
happens.
It's beautiful and
horrible.
I guess that's
why it's called
the Great and
Terrible.
They have the
Lord.
It's terrible for
a lot of
people.
It's great for
others who keep
their covenants,
who don't lie.
He's going to
find out.
He already knows.
It's going to
be exposed.
I know he
wants me to
say this.
It breaks my
heart.
But make no
mistake,
everybody.
All of this
happened because a
group of men
wearing ties,
believing with all
their souls that
they are the
voice of Jesus
Christ,
sat in a
room in 2023
and deliberately decided
to lie to
the public,
to a tabloid
magazine saying that
Elder Ballard violated
his covenants and
commitments to Jesus
by cutting me
off and not
talking to me,
and that Timnier
would have projects
and on and
on.
That's a fact.
It's one of
the most tragic
things I've ever
seen.
I
if these people,
you people,
I'm talking to
you I guess
at this point.
Are you praying
to God that
He's going to
resolve this for
you?
Because the only
prayer that He
will listen to
at this point
is one of
repentance.
He's not going
to help you
out of this.
He's not going
to help you
lie better.
He doesn't do
that.
You would know
that if you
knew Him,
but you can't
know Him and
do what you
did in my
family and to
children.
The people that
voted on this,
I promise you
this,
you don't know
Jesus.
I know that
I know Him,
especially post what
you did to
me.
You don't know
Him.
You can never
even think about
doing what you
did to me
if you knew
Him.
But when you
decided,
when this group
of men wearing
ties and with
their titles,
and I can
only imagine just
emanating every characteristic
of pride,
I just,
the pride in
this is insane.
But Isaiah also
talks about this,
the anti-Previst
book of Mormon.
called
of the nations
for a reason.
The pride is
insane.
It takes a
lot of pride
to do this.
When you decided
to put your
trust in the
arm of the
flesh,
that's what you
do when you
decide to lie.
Jesus is not
part of this.
He's not going
to back you.
So you went
up against the,
you went into
this with a
lie,
arm of the
flesh,
and then that's
why we see
you lying about
your lies,
lying about those
lies,
lying about how
far,
I don't know
how long you're
going to go
with it,
but you keep
going.
As you'll see
later on in
the program,
I have more
examples.
So I don't
think that you
should be praying
to God to
help you get
out of this,
unless the prayer
is one of
repentance.
So now what
do we have?
We have the
arm of the
flesh going up
against the arm
of the Lord.
Because I promise
you that the
Lord is on
the side of
children being hurt,
and truth,
and honesty,
integrity,
that's covenant living.
So it's the
arm of the
flesh versus the
Lord.
While I have
your attention on
this legal stuff,
I'm gonna make
a kind request
to the strengthening
of the members
committee.
I think they've
name
We tried to.
This is a
group of former
law enforcement officers.
know they I
know you guys
been watching me
this whole time.
don't I don't
really Care other
than when we
go to court.
I need to
know what that
what I would
call a spy
file is on
me These are
former like FBI
former law enforcement.
I'm not quite
sure how they
do this job
I would quit
if I was
tasked on this
case but Anyway,
yeah,
that's a that's
a real thing.
That's a real
thing that exists
the The monitor
people like me
my team find
out more about
the mysterious strengthening
church members committee
After the church
to meet its
chief spokesman and
the mastermind behind
the I am
a Mormon campaign
Michael Purdy What's
the strengthening church
members committee and
does it so
exist?
I don't know,
and I'm not...
I guess that's
a question not
for me.
I couldn't tell
you that,
I don't know.
You're the head
of media relations
with the church.
Right.
And I'm spoken
to people,
ex-members of
the church,
who say the
strengthening church members
committee does exist.
Does it still
exist?
I've heard that,
yeah,
there is a
strengthening church members
committee,
but I couldn't
tell you the
details of how
that works,
but we'd be
happy to provide
someone they can.
It's sort of
in my confusion.
When I originally
asked,
you weren't sure.
Now,
you do know
that it exists,
and you will
give me somebody
who knows something
about it.
Absolutely.
So on the
strengthening church members
committee,
the spokesman for
the Mormon church
couldn't give me
a satisfactory answer.
Now,
the church has
come out,
others have come
out.
Mr.
Purti was less
than honest.
Pretending he didn't
know what existed,
but why are
you embarrassed about
it?
Should you be
doing things you're
embarrassed about?
Anyway,
but they do
say,
well,
it does exist
to get information
to provide to
local leaders so
the local leaders
then
to discipline people
like me,
right?
Another lie,
another policy,
another policy violation,
because when they
gave it to
my state president,
the spy packet
to a call,
they also gave
it to him
with instruction to
excommunicate me.
And the state
president lied to
me,
and his first
counselor would later
tell me about
the lie,
and said,
it's our decision,
did you tell
the state president
to lie?
I'm not using
the state president's
name because I
feel bad for
him.
He didn't have
courage,
which is sad,
he definitely violated
his covenants,
but you guys
told him to.
You instructed him
to violate the
scriptures,
to hurt people.
I'm gonna say
that again,
you instructed the
state president to
lie and violate
scriptures that would
hurt children.
You did that.
Don't destroy those
files,
please.
I'm asking you
very kindly,
but also legally
speaking,
we're at a
point where there's
witness tampering things
going on,
any
you do anything
to retaliate against
me or my
family,
I'm not talking
to the church,
I'm talking to
you people inside.
If you do
anything,
I'm just being
kind by saying
this.
I'm a witness.
We're going to
pass this,
but I'm a
witness.
And it will
be a witness
tampering.
It be looked
at as a
witness tampering a
talisman whistleblower.
I don't know.
When there's a
guy named Jason
Preston,
I'm not working
with him.
I can't vouch
for what he's
doing in terms
of the detailed
content.
But he's bringing
potential victims on
his show.
And these same
people that went
after me went
after him.
The whole world
didn't know what
they did.
They did the
same thing to
a guy named
Latter-day Chad.
OK,
that's his name.
They're trying to
help children by
exposing what they
think people might
be doing inside
the church to
cover up.
And so what
Similar
response to me.
They sent them
no trespass orders.
In other words,
they told them,
if you shop
to church,
we're gonna call
the police and
arrest you.
When I saw
that,
was just,
I mean,
not that I
had an art
experience,
similar things,
but at that
point,
my wife,
I was just
like,
they're just coming
out and saying,
we're the bad
guys.
just,
can you imagine,
you have to
go back to
like Salem Witchtrial
days and European
Witchtrials to get
to this,
to,
I don't know
how you get
to get to
this place.
And you think
that every,
well,
they think everything
they do is
backed by Jesus,
absolutely think.
But it's not.
It's not.
The prophecy says
it's not.
It's unbelievable to
that.
That's witness tampering
also.
whistleblower retaliation.
I'm just saying
very kindly,
I'm just telling
you what I'm
going to do.
Okay?
If you do
anything else to
my family,
if you take
my wife out
of the temple,
if you have
punished my kids
who are in
missions,
it will be
reviewed as retaliation
against a federal
witness.
Anything,
if you do
anything to me,
family
team and the
press will know
about it as
well.
I think Jason
Preston should have
that reviewed for
witness tampering as
well.
I've run nonprofits
before and if
somebody,
I can imagine
this.
If I saw
somebody,
my PR director
lying,
I would fire
him immediately and
fix this.
But no one
has done that.
And if somebody
in my organization
brought to my
attention that children
might be being
hurt by my
organization.
If I said,
I'm gonna call
the police if
you come to
the office,
I could be
arrested.
charged for retaliation
crimes.
Whistleblower statutes.
Again,
that's why I
say when you
did that,
it was just
like,
to me,
it was like,
we are just
gonna come out
and just say
it now.
We're the bad
guys.
Like,
it's so disappointing.
So sad I
love the church
so much.
I just still
love the church.
I won't wanna
cry.
so
So what Isaiah
is talking about
is the false
sense of security
that because I
have my ordinances,
like to go
to a temple,
I'm saved.
That's not true.
You're being watched
even more carefully
but for hypocrisy
and you potentially
more condemned.
But read Isaiah
chapter 11 through
17 is really,
really important.
Joseph Smith once
said,
if you're not
living your covenants
and receiving the
Holy Ghost,
which you can
only receive by
living your covenants
and being good
and not lying
about people and
hurting kids,
he says he
said it would
be as if
you had baptized
a bag of
sand.
And he's repeating
the themes of
Isaiah.
It means nothing,
except further condemnation
for hypocrisy.
And I really
hope that we
can learn to
repent better and
not lie better.
The person who
Kevin Pearson sent
excommunication
is a man
named Kevin Hamilton.
He wasn't in
the area authority
so they have
plausible deniability.
They sent him
down and I
believe he's the
one who instructed
the state president
that he is
allowed to override
the words of
Jesus that policy
that means man's
opinion can override
the words of
Jesus.
And I got
to thinking,
has Kevin Hamilton
ever expressed his
opinions about this?
That he really
does think that
policy
Trump's doctrine of
Jesus and that
perspective is simply
this.
Man's opinion can
override the doctrines
of Jesus.
So Kevin Hamilton,
he's the one
that Kevin Pearson
purportedly ordered to
come do the
hit job.
He's not exactly
in the area
authority he was
working in the
genealogy department I
believe.
So maybe plausible
deniability but he
comes down to
my wife.
Okay.
After he orders
the hit job
probably tells the
state president don't
worry about 102.
Don't
need
Yeah,
Joseph said that
and God said
it too.
It doesn't matter.
We are above
that.
We can do
what we want.
He goes to
my wife at
State Conference.
It was all
there in the
State Conference.
The very state
conference where the
state president was
recently called and
then his first
order of business
given after they
told me this.
After Kevin Hamilton
said him apart,
he said,
you know,
go do this
to Tim Ballard.
Then he goes
to my wife
so patronizing.
So disgusting.
He finds my
wife in the
congregation and Kevin
said he was
really nice,
once you know
the background,
kind of creepy.
He says,
you're going to
need the Savior
right now,
Sister Ballard.
Stay close to
the Savior.
It's going to
be a bumpy
ride.
A bumpy ride
why?
Because I did
something.
Oh no,
the courts have
proven that.
A bumpy ride
because he himself
had just ordered
the hijab and
then comes in
patronizing and really
in my opinion,
creepy now.
Stay close to
the Savior.
I'm not going
to say close
to the Savior
because I just
told him to
violate his words,
but you should
say close to
the Savior.
Do as we
say,
not as we
do,
rules for the
not for me.
That's the theme
entire
episode.
Can you imagine
if Kevin Hamilton's
words were applied
to recent headlines
you see in
the news?
Ubstitute the word
savior or Lord
or Jesus Christ
in place of
the church.
As in I
don't support the
Savior's policy on
you filling the
blank or I
don't agree with
the way Jesus
Christ does this
or that.
For me personally
that seems to
put a very
different perspective on
things.
Yes Elder Hamilton
certainly does give
a very different
perspective.
The perspective is
the very thing
Isaiah and the
book of Mormon
warns us about.
Following the precepts
of man or
the traditions of
our Father versus
Jesus Christ Himself.
It allows you.
It allows you
to tell people
delete the scripture.
Delete the scripture.
I
section number two
is one of
the most important
scriptures,
and it's one
of the most
easy to follow.
You know,
people love this
simple commandments like
tithing.
Even that's not
so simple.
Pre-tax,
post-tax.
This one's really
easy.
In all cases,
to avoid what?
Injury.
Do think Jesus
likes injury?
Especially to people
like my wife
and my children
and countless children
across the world.
I mean,
this scripture was
designed for this
moment,
and it was
just deleted because
the policies of
man equal or
are greater than
the words of
Jesus.
How do you
do it?
If Kevin Hamilton
is correct,
he's saying that
Jesus Christ ordered
a lie to
be sent to
a tabloid magazine
owned by George
Soros,
that Jesus Christ
ordered Tim Valor
to be excommunicated
while violating his
own words,
that Jesus Christ
conspired against the
rescue of children.
I will never
accept that,
and I know
that you won't
either.
On July 18th
of this year,
in
to what they
knew was gonna
be the fight
for my life.
So they made
sure that I
went in disadvantaged.
Who's gonna overcome
this?
And then it
gets worse after
that.
Now,
understand what's going
on.
I'm going into
court.
They have me
under criminal investigation.
So those investigations,
by the way,
have been shut
down and I
am suing all
these people.
And by the
way,
okay,
if I'm so
guilty,
look at the
Celeste Borers case.
Her case was
dismissed,
she was called
a liar.
I'll talk about
that later.
How come I'm
still suing her
and giving her
another opportunity to
come back if
I'm so guilty?
I'm suing her
and I won't
stop until we're
in court.
Why would I
do that if
I were guilty?
I would run
away and take
my winnings.
Who got over
that one?
No,
I'm saying come
to the courtroom.
All of you
come to the
courtroom.
This was all
done behind my
back.
Not one piece
of it was
done in the
light.
It was all
done in the
dark and I'm
bringing it to
the light.
But the PR
committee,
Doug Anderson,
Kevin Pearson,
all those involved
in this,
they knew one
thing.
Can you imagine
winning this thing?
law fair that
was coming,
they knew it
was coming.
So many people
are LDS and
Utah.
They tainted the
jury pools.
They knew they
were doing that.
They were tainted
the jury pools,
possibly the judges,
possibly law enforcement.
Luckily,
I have only
found integrity in
law enforcement and
in the courts
thus far.
And that's a
blessing and that's
a hats off
to use law
enforcement and the
court system.
But they knew
they were tainted
this because when
the church says
it,
I understand those
of you who
are outside of
Utah,
especially because of
the infallibility and
myth when the
church says it
and they know
this and they
use it.
Because the church
said it,
it's almost like
to a lot
of people,
God said it.
God declared him
guilty.
I'm telling you,
they can't believe
I survived.
They thought they
could lie all
they want because
I would die
with their defamation,
having tainted law
enforcement in their
minds,
having tainted the
jury pool.
And yet we
won.
I'm telling you,
the irony is
so thick,
we won.
I know why.
I know why
because I was
there.
I wouldn't have
Catherine
and because Jesus
Christ intervened.
He is more
upset than me.
I promise you,
his name being
used,
he is more
upset than I
am.
Because I won
in court.
The Judge Todd
Chahennancy ruled that
they're liars.
On page 56
of the 58
page report,
the judge specifically
said there was
nothing in the
stolen emails.
There was nothing
that would have
helped them anyway
to get Tim.
The only thing
in there that
was detrimental was
confidential reports from
Mexico,
from Dominican Republic
and other countries.
had to shut
cases down.
After I win
in court,
Deseret News,
who has already
done everything they
can to destroy
me,
defames me again,
puts out a
headline saying,
lawsuit against Tim
Ballad dropped after
key evidence ruled
invalid.
There was no
key evidence.
If they had
read the ruling,
they would know
there was no
key evidence.
There was no
evidence.
Deseret News lies.
when
News article came
out and we
saw that they
were going to
lie and keep
running cover for
the bosses,
okay,
the deep state,
apparently,
and just completely
lie in the
headline about there's
really key evidence.
You know what
they're doing.
Obviously,
Tim's still guilty.
No matter what,
he's still guilty.
You know,
lie,
no problem.
That is when,
after everything else
that happened,
my wife who's
got so much
patience and forgiveness,
and not that
she doesn't,
she's still forgives
her.
That's when Katherine
calmly turned to
me and said
after she read
the Deseret News
article,
because we're dealing
with a quasi
-mofia situation here.
Let's just face
it.
She turns to
me and says,
gloves off.
We glued back
fire.
And that's it.
I don't do
anything without Katherine.
She approves everything
that I'm saying.
That was it.
That was a
last straw.
It's all about
lying.
It's just like
the book of
Mormon.
It's just like
the Gadiantan system,
okay,
the Order of
Luke Horms.
It's lie.
When people start
lying,
that's when the
crash
that's when Katherine
turned me and
said it's over.
It's over.
We're moving forward.
Hey guys,
I'm sitting in
the editing bay.
This is another
surprise insert.
We're literally just
finishing backfire and
it's July 8th
and guess what
happened?
The church media
arm just defamed
me again.
It was bad
enough.
Remember Desiret tried
to slaughter me
in 2023 then
again.
We again KSL
for those who
don't know KSL
is also owned
by the church.
So I won
another court case
against Celeste Boris.
The judge dismissed
it and what
does KSL do?
same thing that
their sister agency
did when the
other dismissal was
announced.
A couple of
things.
First of all
they do the
same thing.
Evidence.
The evidence was
hidden.
Read the article.
The evidence was
hidden.
Oh Tim,
they have to
make you think
I'm still guilty.
Understand this.
Okay?
And so they
say that the
emails that Celeste
Boris stole,
that's where the
was.
still killed the
everybody.
can't let the
lootorms look bad.
Now you might
ask yourself,
why did Celeste,
these other lying
women and their
mafia attorneys steal
my emails if
there's nothing in
them?
I'll tell you
why,
because this is
all a public
perception hit so
they could take
the lawsuit and
expand it by,
I don't know
how many hundreds
of,
or thousands of
pages to make
it look bad,
sold at the
doops at places
like Deseret News
and KSL can
have a false
narrative to run
on,
to cover for
their puppet masters.
Again,
page 56,
out of the
50 page report,
it says nothing.
There was nothing
there,
what a clean
bill of health,
can you imagine?
A criminal?
Okay,
an alleged criminal.
So as Boris
Steel has access
to tens of
thousands of emails,
can't find one
thing in there
that hurts me.
That's a pretty
good clean bill
of health.
How many people
can even say
that?
some of them
actually said,
all their emails,
not one thing
they could find,
okay?
KSL,
you to believe
that,
but they did
something even worse.
Okay,
this guy,
Bridger Beale,
cut you out.
So Bridger Beale
reached out to
my attorney,
Mark Eisenhut yesterday,
and he says,
do you have
a statement?
Okay,
look at the
screenshot.
You won't believe
what this guy
does.
It's a trick.
At 3.58
p.m.,
Mark has a
response.
Mr.
Hi,
Bridger.
Our statement,
Mr.
Ballard has consistently
prevailed in the
multiple court proceedings,
initiated against him.
He and his
team are grateful
for this recent
victory.
He is prevailing
because the facts
around his side,
the evidence consistently
demonstrates his innocence.
3.58 p
.m.,
402,
check it out.
Bridger response,
thanks so much.
Mark thumbs up.
But the next
thing with three
comes out.
Guess what Bridger
says?
He lies.
Like all of
his puppet masters.
He lies and
says that we
didn't respond.
We didn't respond.
That's a trick.
Great.
of fake news.
They make it
look like,
oh,
Tim didn't want
to say anything
because he knows
he's guilty.
He responded immediately.
Now,
Bridger's gonna fix
this,
but it's gonna
be too late.
Yeah,
we know,
Bridger,
know you figured
out falsely that
you got caught
on an accidental
text that got
sent to you.
We know it
all come out
and court likely.
But it doesn't
matter,
it was too
late.
The damage was
done.
Again,
that's the thing.
The damage already
done.
It's like,
oops,
sorry.
By time you
fix it,
everybody saw it.
For those who
don't know,
Sheri Dew,
I love her.
think she's a
great person.
I don't know
what's going on.
I can't really
blame her.
know that her
Deseret Enterprise is
huge.
but I can't
believe she doesn't
know him by
now and if
she doesn't,
now she does.
So there's a
few who don't
know,
Sheri Dew is
the executive vice
president and chief
content officer for
Deseret Management Corporation,
which means she
is in charge
of the content
and runs KSL
and Deseret News
and many other
church-owned media
outlets.
Sheri Dew.
we're
Sheri,
we're friends,
right?
Tim,
don't talk to
me in public.
I'm sorry,
I have to.
I've tried to
go private.
You won't talk
to me,
no one will
talk to me.
You guys invited
the public to
this stage,
so here we
are.
What is going
on?
Like,
what are you
thinking?
How do you
think about this?
I wanna talk
about this.
This is serious.
So I don't
know if you
were part of
the decision to
repeat the Doug
Anderson line in
fall of 2023,
but certainly you
saw it.
It said I
didn't do projects
associated with the
church.
Do you know
whether I did
projects with the
church?
What did do?
I'm not mad,
I'm really asking
you,
because I'm worried
about you,
I'm worried about
everybody.
Did you know?
Of course you
knew.
I was in
your office,
and you told
me you read
the link on
hypothesis,
and you published
it,
three other books,
then I'll do
another book,
and sold two
other books.
You put me
on the stage.
Time out for
women,
I was on
the stage with
you.
remember you were
playing the piano
before we were
talking,
you're an amazing
piano player.
Yeah,
we were there
together.
know
me there,
are those projects
associated with the
church?
So you knew
that a lie
went out under
your agency.
And then they
do it again.
They defame me
again when I
went in court.
And then Old
Bridge are here,
just did it
again.
The statement also
said that I
was never endorsed
by the church.
You put me
on the front
cover of LDS
Living Magazine,
the church's magazine.
How do you
not endorse somebody
while promoting other
books in their
stage performances on
on on?
So my question
is,
what are you
thinking?
I have to
ask,
what are you
thinking?
What goes in
your head?
Is lying okay?
And I don't
want to just
take on Sheri,
everybody who's doing
this,
what are you
saying?
Tim,
we can't do
anything about this
because the attorneys
and the liability
and the PR,
the attorneys,
I'm not saying
everyone says,
when you meet
your maker,
everybody,
are you going
to say that
to Jesus?
Are you going
to call for
the attorneys to
come up in
the PR department?
He's
I don't care.
That's not one
of the requirements
or that's not
one of the
justifications or excuses
in the scriptures.
It's just lying
or not lying.
Jesus is black
and white.
You're gonna call
the attorneys up,
they're not gonna
come.
They might be
standing next to
you.
As you're being
judged,
I just,
I don't get
it.
Here's what,
here's what I
really don't get.
You think that
you can just,
and then you
took my books
off the shelf.
That was interesting
move.
So you say
I never did
product exposure to
the church.
Take my best
-selling books off
the shelf,
10 years best
-selling books.
And you think
the world's just
gonna not remember?
Millions of dollars
of books sold
and read.
They're just gonna
forget because this
didn't happen.
What?
That's a weird
move,
bad move.
what I'm more
concerned about is
the spiritual side
of this.
I don't understand.
Because probably there's
hundreds of references
to what happens
in
And it's really
bad.
Jesus hates lying.
Jehovah hates lying.
So you preside
over a lie,
all of you.
If didn't know
about it,
you did it
shortly thereafter.
And then that
lie goes to
her children.
And the one
thing Jesus loves,
it's like the
other side of
the spectrum,
he loves children.
So you are
presiding over a
lie that he
hates.
And it's hurting
children,
now countless children,
that he loves.
Do you see
how much trouble
you're in it?
So what does
the covenant mean?
That you talk
about covenants,
we've published does
our books published?
How many books
talks?
You've given so
many talks about
it?
Is that going
to make it
okay?
Or does that
make you worse?
Because with a
rubber hits the
road,
that's where it
matters.
You probably even
teach that also
in your teachings
and your books
and your speeches,
everybody.
It doesn't matter
if you're making
this covenant and
going to the
temple.
if
rubber hits the
road and it's
lies and kids
getting hurt and
you just let
those happen both
of them That's
a violation of
the covenant absolutely
absolutely So what
do you what
what goes on
in everybody's head
right now?
Oh Tim we
can't we better
let one man
perish Then that
the whole institution
goes down It's
not gonna go
down,
but you know
chaeff is said
the same thing
about Jesus I
don't mean to
compare myself to
Jesus other than
that example
Yeah,
he said the
same thing how
do you think
it went for
him?
I'm worried about
the saints and
the examples of
being set because
it's like if
as long as
you can answer
15 or 16
pretty easy questions
once every two
years You go
to the temple
you're fine and
we control the
ordinances and we
control your salvation
that is false
I think that's
the precepts of
man also frowned
upon by Jesus
That's just not
true read as
a 58 he
tells you you
you have to
do
Things you have
to manifest the
covenant it means
nothing these ordinances
mean nothing
If
breaking your covenants
outside of the
temple.
And in fact,
it's such a
big deal,
and it's so
prophesied of what
we're living right
now in the
kingdom,
that Isaiah talks
about it all
over.
He talks about
the liars.
You're lying,
lying,
Lies will be
your refuge.
Isaiah 28,
Isaiah 29,
Isaiah 56,
the watchmen are
blind.
They're just,
they're after their
own way.
They're like,
there's a good
set of watchmen
too.
They come out
of this,
okay.
Isaiah 1 and
the 66,
the first and
the last books,
they're very important.
I just want
to review them
real quick to
this point.
We're going to
the temple.
We're just fine.
I can't answer
five or six
questions,
whatever it is,
once every two
years.
And I'm fine.
You're not fine.
You're actually in
more trouble because
of the hypocrisy
of it.
It's frightening,
guys.
It's frightening.
Isaiah chapter one
is the indictment.
It's the indictment
he's putting on
the kingdom.
It's end times.
n
the book of
Mormon and times
and times books
and he actually
talks about this.
He says,
I'm tired.
I'm tired of
your offerings.
spread out your
arms and pray.
I don't even
hear it.
You trample my
courts.
He says,
read it because
you think you
have these ordinances
so you're saved.
You're not.
You actually,
with the rubber
hits the road,
like kids getting
hurt and lie,
lie,
lie.
You break your
covenant.
And then if
you read Isaiah
chapter 113-17,
he's mad because
you're going and
trying to secure
your salvation by
showing up at
the temple and
he says,
you're trampling my
courts.
I don't hear
your prayers anymore.
And then 17,
he ends it
by telling you,
so suited,
so fitted,
because you're not
taking care of
the widows and
the fatherless,
the children.
He literally calls
out the very
crime and sin
that I'm referring
to right now.
And then go
to 66.
That's kind of
the final judgment.
That's
book and the
last book.
The first book
is the indictment,
66.
The last book
is the final
judgment and he
says the same
thing.
He starts,
he picks up
where he left
off.
And he says,
you guys put
all this emphasis
on your temple
and that's wonderful
if you're living
the covenant.
False sense of
security.
Check the boxes.
Look what he
says.
The temple is
your body.
So what does
Isaiah say?
66,
the very first
verse.
He says,
the heaven is
my throne and
the earth,
my So where
is the house
that you build
into me?
Where is the
place for my
right?
What he's saying
is these houses
don't mean much
because the whole
earth is essentially
my temple.
And then in
the next verse,
he says,
I look to
him.
the man who's
poor,
contrite and stirred
and vigilant for
my word and
his spirit dwells
in that temple.
You see what
I'm saying?
And then he
goes on to
talk about again,
the same thing
from chapter one.
These and how
he's just tired
of thinking that
you have this
false sense of
security
ordinances.
talks about it
and I want
to just tell
you what that
means to me.
It means that
your body's the
temple if you're
not being obedient,
if you're violating
your covenants,
then you don't
have history in
here.
He's not seeking
you.
You're not vigilant
for his word.
In other words,
if your body
is not a
temple,
it doesn't matter
if your body
is in the
temple.
And then he
goes right into,
again,
what we're living,
it's a pure
fulfillment.
Isaiah 66,
5,
you're going to
persecute the innocent,
persecute the righteous,
exude unrighteous dominion
upon them and
he's tired.
And one,
he talks about
your monthly meetings,
your regular meetings,
your assemblies,
he says,
I can't look
at it anymore.
I'm tired.
But he wants
you to come
back.
He wants you
to repent.
Sheri, do you
know that I
did projects associated
with the church?
You know that.
and you're now
presiding over lives
that hurting kids.
How would you
reconcile this?
All of you.
How do you,
and you're still
doing it?
Talk to Mr.
Bridger.
Talk to him.
Let me give
you a piece
of advice.
You keep digging
a pit for
your brother.
Second,
you fight it.
28,
verse eight tells
you you're gonna
do it.
You're gonna lie
a little.
You're gonna dig
a pit for
your brother.
You're gonna say
all dwell in
Zion.
It's fine,
Zion prospereth.
Read second,
you fight 28.
He says you're
gonna do all
these things.
And you're gonna
dig a pit
for your brother
and think it's
okay.
And it's not
The worst possible
condemnation comes upon
you.
Read the rest
of the chapter.
A final bit
of advice for
this little insert.
Throw the shovel
away.
Because what you're
doing every time
you dig another
pit for me,
like in KSO,
like Desiret is,
you're gonna fall
into that pit.
I promise you,
I'm not falling
into it.
You keep digging
it deeper for
your own fall.
It's gonna be
harder for you
every time you
keep digging.
Throw the shovel
away.
Stop.
Just stop!
what we're talking
about KSL?
I guess something
else to tell
you.
Sound of Freedom
2 is coming
out.
And it tells
the story of
Celeste Boris,
the very person
you're running cover
for here.
And her mafia,
truly mafia attorneys,
they went down
and they committed,
allegedly committed multiple
crimes against Pedro
Flores.
Simba from Sound
of Freedom.
They tried to
get him to
sue me,
allegedly bribe him,
course,
chimped it,
horrible thing Celeste
was part of
it.
It's so fascinating
this story that's
put into a
Utah file lawsuit
by Pedro against
them.
It's horrifying.
They lost everything
because he wouldn't
do it.
And they sent
the mafia against
him,
the cartels,
and I had
to go rescue
him again.
It's an amazing
story.
It gets filed
in Utah courts.
It's so amazing
that Hollywood is
literally making a
movie about it.
But it's not
interesting enough for
KSL because I
know that that
filing,
the Pedro funding
was given to
KSL.
Didn't tell the
story.
My enemies get
all the airtime,
gave them all
of you,
Utah media.
But no one
wanted this story.
The fact that
you didn't want
this story is
not part of
the story.
Stop
digging the pit,
throw away the
shovel.
It's all coming
out.
It's not part
of the story.
When Hidden War
came out theatrically
last year,
we know the
censorship that was
going on.
I won't name
this person because
I think she's
a very good
person in KSL
reporter.
She reached out
to me through
my people and
said I want
to do a
story on the
censorship of Hidden
War in Utah.
What's going on?
The alleged censorship.
I said great.
I knew it
was going to
happen 24 hours
later.
She goes she
tells me my
bosses won't let
me do this
story.
And I sent
her a message
back kind of
with the Lafayette
emoji saying yeah
the same people
that I believe
are censoring me
are now censoring
you for trying
to uncover the
censorship.
It goes on
and on and
on.
Throw away the
shovel guys.
Covenants are real.
Stop playing church
and take this
seriously because Jesus
is coming.
It gives me
no pleasure to
say this but
this truly is
a woe until
all of you
forgot.
will
mocked.
All right,
back to Backfire.
The aftermath continues
to this day.
This state president,
he takes every
opportunity to bully
me from the
pulpit.
You should read
the book by
Bill O'Reilly,
killing the witches.
You'll find a
lot of similarities.
He gives it
from the pulpit,
and he starts
saying that there's
a difference between
doctrine and policy.
Policy is what
interprets doctrine.
And people will
be very disappointed
someday when they
find out that
that's the truth
of the kingdom.
Really?
Let's go back
again to D
&C 102.
What does D
&C 102 say?
all cases,
the member who's
accused to prevent
injury and insult
and damage to
the innocent,
he gets to
invoke the 12
member council in
all cases.
So he's doubling
down on his
sin.
Well,
I'm codifying my
sin.
And I'm calling
it policy.
policy
is that how
it works?
Policy can take
doctrine and put
it on its
head,
inverted completely.
Is that what
we're saying?
That's a dangerous
precedent.
Where does that
end?
Understand what he's
doing here.
He's literally speaking
these words.
From the pulpit
at stake conference,
teaching the very
doctrine that Isaiah
and the Borgorn
warn the leaders
of the covenant
community not to
teach that the
presips of man
trump the words
of Jesus.
And he says,
Jesus says they're
going to do
it at the
end times.
And he's doing
it.
I'm watching him,
you know,
say this.
It's a gospel
one to the
judge of Israel,
not to Jesus.
And I'm watching
him.
How are you
doing this?
saying this?
That policy interpret
scripture in this
particular case that
he's referring to,
that his policy
literally interprets out
of existence.
The scripture's not
even close.
Not even
close
close interpretation,
it's just gone
delete.
And I might
win back,
I have a
photographic memory,
God's a blissful
with that thing
goodness.
And I remember
back a year
or more before,
when we sat
in that kingdom
court,
I remember he
sat like this,
and he like
this,
and he turns
to the side,
looking to the
wall as if
pontificating.
My wife is
crying after he
just yelled at
her for nothing
more than her
asking very legitimate
questions.
He yelled,
he looked like
yells at her.
Everyone in the
room saw him,
like,
who is this
guy?
So he's sitting
pontificating like this,
look at the
wall,
and he quotes
Dr.
Incovidence 131,
it says,
the Lord cannot
look upon sin
with any tolerance.
And I'm just
kind of this,
but you're committing
sin right now,
and I thought,
well,
that's why he
can say this
a year later,
this priesthood's gone.
I literally watched
the priesthood leave
his body during
the kingdom court.
Remember what DNC
-121 says?
Unrighteous dominion leads
to a man
to the priesthood,
you sever yourself
from the ordinances
of God's house.
You,
he calls you
to servants
of
sin yourself for
doing this and
then for good
measure even throws
in from Luke
17,
the millstone prophecy
that if kids
get hurt in
the process,
can you know
this?
And I'm literally
watching all the
spirit,
all the authority
leave his body
as he's pontificating
on the scriptures
about my sins
while he is
deep and sin
literally committing the
sin in the
moment that he's
accusing falsely accusing
me of it
having denied me
any opportunity to
even try to
respond.
So I'm thinking
in the kangaroo
court sitting there
like how are
you going to
get around D
&T 121?
You you you
were literally committing
one of the
worst sins the
scriptures tell you
about you lose
the priesthood you
lose everything you
lose your covenant
how's he going
to get around
this and then
hit me in
the name of
the judge of
Israel he'll just
override doctrine covenant
121 so we
can keep his
priesthood that's how
we can do
that that's how
we can get
on the stand
without the priesthood
without the spirit
and start teaching
doctrines of the
devil
That's what the
scriptures say,
this not me,
doctors are the
devil.
And I think
I'll play a
reverse uno card
right now,
and also quote
from Dr.
and Covenant Section
1,
but a little
further up the
page,
okay?
Take that one
off of BNC
-131 and go
to DNC-131.
And what does
it say?
It says,
and the rebellious
shall be pierced
with much sorrow.
For their iniquities
shall be spoken
upon the house,
upon the rooftops,
and their secret
acts shall be
revealed.
Prophecy,
pheasant.
A third element
of the framework
is that personal
revelation will be
in harmony with
the commandments of
God,
and the covenants
we've made with
Him.
When we ask
for revelation about
something God has
already given clear
direction,
we open ourselves
up to misinterpreting
our feelings and
hearing what we
want to hear.
So I can
say I'm your
judge in Israel
and I can
define anything You
are sitting in
the throne of
Jesus if you
do such a
thing But he's
doubling down my
wife refuses To
not go to
church because we
believe The foundation
is good the
revelations are real
I can't leave
either but I
can't go to
the temple my
wife goes in
crunchy works in
the temple
I go with
her and I
sit in the
waiting room and
I renew my
covenants and God
does Another example
he gets up
at word conference
and he talks
about Joshua has
his great mission
to liberate in
the Old Testament
Deliberate the promise
land But Joshua
broke his covenant
and his great
mission was diverted.
I knew he
was talking to
me.
I told my
bishop That's persecution.
can't stop so
at this word
conference when he's
you know
Comparing me to
Joshua.
I know what
he's doing He's
he's trying to
persuade his guilt
because if he
unlawful,
unethical,
unscriptural,
truly evil thing.
And that resulted
in children being
hurt.
That's exactly what
happened.
Period,
and he will
answer to Jesus
for that.
The guy above
him,
his past is
on the head
and says,
you can go
to the temple.
That means nothing,
guys.
Jesus is actually
real.
I don't know
that.
Like,
he actually comes.
He actually judges.
Like,
the guy that
sits above you
and's patch you
on the head,
it doesn't mean
anything,
because that's the
same guy running
cover for the
guy above him.
They're the guys
protecting the lie.
You stand on
your own,
guys.
go to the
veil by yourself.
I'm sorry to
say it.
It is true.
There's lots of
repentance that needs
to happen.
None of us
know our end
really.
Well,
what hand will
guide us there?
A king may
move a man.
A father may
claim a son.
That man can
also move himself.
And only then
is that man
truly begin his
own game.
Remember that also,
ever you are
played or by
whom your soul
is and you're
keeping alone.
Even though those
who presume to
play will be
kings or men
of power,
when you stand
for God you
cannot say,
but I was
told by others
to do thus,
or that virtue
was not convenient
at the time,
this will not
suffice.
Remember that.
The State President
has a contend
with that,
that I was
somehow violating my
covenant during that
whole time,
and yet God
was blessing me.
And what was
he blessing the
State President with?
Pictures of Jesus
falling off,
shaking a control
bee,
having to be
escorted home that
night.
They literally had
to cancel his
appointments and escort
him to his
house.
That is not
the fruits of
the Spirit.
The work that
my team and
I have done,
those are the
fruits of the
Spirit.
So I guess
that's all we
have.
When people lie,
all you have,
Jesus tells us
is the fruits
of the Spirit.
Look at the
fruits.
fruits of this
whole thing.
Well you're going
to find out
what Joshua was
doing in 2022.
when
allegedly having sex
with the whole
world.
You'll find out
in Hidden War.
The police are
coming!
no,
no!
It just so
happens,
again,
the right hook
from Jesus.
Half of my
life,
at least,
was documented in
2022.
And the whole
world is gonna
watch it.
So as you're
watching Hidden War,
ask yourself,
as you're seeing
portals literally open
from Ukraine,
to Western Europe,
to Mexico,
to Ecuador,
you're watching Heaven's
Hand guide me
as the leader
of the operation.
You tell me
if it's possible
to accomplish this
divine mission while
at the same
time having sex
with all these
women like to
take president and
insist that I
was doing.
You be the
judge.
What was Joshua
doing in 2022?
You'll find out
when you see
the film.
Streaming on Angel
Studios.
Now,
the catch-out
of the bag.
You can run
all around.
You
not going to
win this.
And of course,
these events that
make up the
aftermath of all
the mess that
started this then
began the cover
-ups.
Kevin Pearson is
still on the
throne.
But then something
happened.
He orders a
hit on an
innocent woman who
used to work
for me in
Provo.
She wasn't an
operator.
She was just
someone who stood
up for me
because she knew
the women were
lying.
So she got
ripped up in
the press.
And he orders
a hit on
her to be
disciplined.
The state president
that was told
to do this
is a true
watch right on
the tower.
The name is
a f***.
He knows this
woman.
He calls Raining
you're
I'm not gonna
do anything,
but he tells
her,
functionally,
got to kind
of pretend you've
been excommunicated,
otherwise the guys
up top are
gonna keep putting
pressure on me.
Oh,
have way too
much to cover
up.
Even though I
was innocent,
it desert news,
we used to
champion me.
I thought they
wanted to save
kids,
honestly.
I think someone
did,
for sure.
But I realized
now I was
just part of
a different whitewash
campaign,
back then.
When things were
good for me
and I wasn't
being accused,
I was their
champion.
The men I
get accused cast
them to the
side.
Another pint,
another court of
whitewash on the
wall.
You understand?
These are conspiring
men.
The mental gymnastics
these guys have
to do to
keep themselves sane,
but I don't
think they are
sane.
I think they
have trouble sleeping.
I've reason to
believe that.
One of the
counselors who was
emotional came to
me.
Apparently,
had a coming
to Jesus of
some sort,
came to me
in the hallway
crying.
Bishop Mark Stott
was with me
in the hallway,
trembling lower lip.
And he said,
we lied to
you.
We didn't have
the choice.
a choice.
And I looked
at him and
said,
well,
you must be
living under same
plan too,
because I'm not.
You always have
a choice.
You chose very
poorly.
And now you
too have used
the name of
Jesus Christ to
work evil upon
countless children.
He wouldn't even
talk to me
after that.
He was trembling
so much.
I've witnesses.
He turned around
and I grabbed
him.
I tell him
I love him.
I do love
him.
And I said,
what are you
doing?
You're supposed to
be my shepherd.
And you're not,
you're being this
shepherd for corruption.
It's so obvious.
You just told
me you lied.
And the cover
-ups continued.
Worst ball just
happened about two
months ago.
Because of Doug
Anderson and those
who supported the
lie to the
tabloid magazine and
the defamation of
me and Elder
Ballard,
children are getting
raped every single
day.
In February of
2025,
I was working
with the police
in Argentina and
we rescued 20
children for five
years old.
The subject of
child rape videos.
online
online and through
the evidence we
collected the digital
evidence that there
was about 200
other kids.
I saw them.
The videos of
them,
but they didn't
have the proper
hardware to process
the digital evidence
fast enough.
So I went
back to the
US as fast
as could to
acquire it for
free and bring
it back.
But in that
time period,
I wasn't ever
able to go
back because the
Doug Anderson lie
from the PR
committee and beyond.
Was being used
by the godless,
leftist devils.
We control the
media in Argentina.
That lie of
Doug Anderson,
that cloud,
born and bred
and proliferated by
the Church of
Jesus Christ of
Latter-day Saints,
is hurting children.
I'm begging with
authorities.
tracked the statement.
We tracked the
statement.
I can't miss
your kids.
Argentina is the
prime example.
There's 200 kids.
I saw them.
And someday in
this life or
the next,
the state president
and Doug Anderson
and Kevin Pearson
will have to
see those videos.
I declare to
you in the
name of Jesus
they will.
see
and they will
see the children
who never will
be liberated because
of that lie.
Just months after
I was shut
down from returning
to Argentina because
of the Doug
Anderson lie,
Elder Cook leads
an enormous delegation
with the Mormon
Tabernacle Choir into
Argentina.
And before the
news in KSL,
Puppeted the statement
that said it's
no small thing
to be recognized
by the country
of Argentina.
Now,
at best,
that's misleading.
When you bring
the most famous
choir in the
world to a
country,
it's not hard
to get them
to recognize you.
It's a piece
of paper.
so what do
they have to
do?
Now begins the
next phase of
the White Wash.
The other the
other quarts of
tossed
the disease too.
So we prove
that the Doug
Anderson,
the peer face,
is willing to
lie.
He's willing to
It's proof beyond
a reasonable doubt.
So what that
tells you is
whoever's in charge
of putting Doug
Anderson in place
want to put
a man willing
to lie in
that position.
That should concern
everybody in this
entire church.
They want a
liar for facing.
Of course they
do.
Look what I'm
doing.
They need a
liar.
So no matter
what he says
about this or
anything is a
lie.
Guys,
this is bad.
This is this
is luquormism at
its height.
What they've done
to me because
it wasn't to
me.
It looks like
the children of
the world.
Oh,
it's no small
thing.
Is that the
it was that
the answer to
the fact that
they knew that
200 kids were
being raped right
now because of
their lie?
I don't know.
But my team
in Argentina sure
thinks so.
How about just
retract the statement?
consult the sun
beam manual and
see what Jesus
thinks about integrity
and honesty,
especially when the
lack of it
or of leads
to the rape
of children?
Is that the
easier answer?
that the Jesus
answer?
Or are you
above Jesus?
You can just
take people's temper
recommends because they
disagree with you.
Is that how
which one is
it?
What do I
do here?
Notwithstanding all of
this wickedness that
was carried out
in the name
of Jesus Christ
and by His
church,
there is hope.
I want to
tell you about
a righteous watchman
on the tower.
I've never met
this person.
He's never said
a word to
me.
But I'm very
observant.
I
closely the movements
going on in
the corporation around
me and around
my mission.
And they're the
man named Jack
Thurard.
It was serving
at the time
these critical decisions
were being made
as the executive
director of the
church communication department,
which means his
voice would have
been listened to.
And in this
case,
clearly was rejected.
He's a man
of integrity,
all his colleagues
say that that's
what he's known
for integrity.
And because he's
a PR genius,
he was put
in as the
PR director.
And so I
assume he was
in that capacity
or something like
that,
when the decisions
were being made
as to whether
we should destroy
Tim Bauer's life
with a lie
or not.
I only could
imagine that he
fought for me,
not so much
for me,
for Jesus.
Fought for the
integrity of his
church.
Fought the people
who would rather
follow the ideologies
of Luke Orman
used the name
of Jesus to
hurt the Ballard
family,
to destroy them.
They knew this
would destroy my
chances at the
Senate.
He knew that
and he would
have stood up
for me I
think he did
and why do
I think that
well for two
reasons shortly after
the decision was
made to destroy
my life through
a tabloid magazine
He got mysteriously
Swept away to
Europe,
it's like the
Chateau de Eiff
And the kind
of monochrist of
those who were
ashamed of I
Show you I
am innocent I
really do know
You mocked me
No,
my dear Dante's
I know perfectly
well that you
are innocent Why
else would you
be here If
you were truly
guilty there are
a hundred prisons
in France where
they would lock
you away But
Chateau de Eiff
is where they
put the ones
that were shamed
off Like Kevin
Pearson for bad
or Jack Girard
for good.
I guess that's
where you go
But
a left hook
from Jesus comes
around in April
of 2024,
just months after
the decision was
made,
and who is
giving the conference
talk?
Jack Jarrar.
Now I don't
know what his
intent was,
but we'll find
out through discovery.
Because his talk
was very interesting.
It's called integrity,
a Christlike attribute.
And you know
what he said
in that talk?
If you listen
carefully and you
know the story
that I'm looking
at through the
lens of mine,
he is talking
to the church.
And he says
a lot of
interesting things,
that integrity is
not something that
you can compromise.
And he says
this.
As a covenant
people and as
leaders of his
church,
we must be
beyond reproach and
align with the
standards the Lord
has said,
acting with integrity
builds faith and
trust,
and reassures others
that we seek
only to do
the will of
the Lord.
as the church
comes out of
obscurity and darkness.
We must rise
above the worldly
expectations and become
the face of
the true and
living God.
Our focus is
on the Savior.
And we are
careful to avoid
actions that may
be perceived as
serving our own
interests or favoring
someone at the
expense of another.
We go out
of our way
to avoid any
perception that our
actions may be
influenced by the
honors of men.
Some organizations train
employees to consider
what their decisions
or decision-making
process would look
like if published
online or on
the front page
of a major
newspaper.
He says,
the decisions you
make and the
process you use
to make a
decision assume that
someday that will
be headline.
And will you
be embarrassed?
I think he's
talking about what
happened just months
earlier.
And I would
say he's prophetic,
except he got
one thing wrong.
It's not just
going to be
headlines.
It's going to
be Sound of
Freedom 2.
It's going to
be a docuseries,
a lion's gate.
It's going to
be an international
bestselling book.
This is a
news cycle that
never ends.
But you know
what Deseret Book
did?
Because there's good
people in there
and I love
them.
Without me asking,
within a month
of the excommunication,
they gave me
back my IP
for all my
books.
Why would you
give the IP
back to a
man who's been
denounced by the
church?
Who used the
name of a
prophet to do
immoral things?
I can tell
you that authors,
even in good
standing,
don't get their
IP back.
That's the business
decision.
It makes sense.
they gave my
back to me
because they knew
that the was
the lie was
the lie.
They knew.
So why don't
I leave?
That's the question.
Believe me.
I know how
Lafayr works.
They can't believe
that I figured
this out.
They can't believe
I survived.
I was supposed
to be able
kill myself.
Run off to
Alaska and start
a charter fishing
company or Trinit
into a John
Dullin type figure
and become an
anti-thusakian discredit
me.
I didn't do
any of those
things.
I believe.
I believe in
the foundation.
the revelations.
I believe in
the scriptures of
the Restoration.
I would die
first before rejecting
that testimony.
These are another
three reasons why
I can't leave.
I'm republishing these
books.
Thank you Deseret
book for giving
back my IP
so I can
republish these.
But I'm changing
the title to
something like Why
Abraham Lincoln won't
let me leave
the church?
Why George Washington
won't let me
leave the church?
Why the pilgrims?
won't
leave the church.
That's why I'm
not gonna leave
the church.
Do not leave
the vineyard.
Stay.
Get more recruits
to come in.
Forth-filled,
beautiful prophecy.
We need servants.
We need the
residue of the
watchmen,
the good ones,
to work with
the servants.
And we need
to get the
lukewarms out.
Here's the good
news.
Even if you
are following the
ideology of lukewarm,
today,
tomorrow,
you can be
a servant.
I know the
gospel is true.
I stand by
everything I wrote.
And because I
know it's true,
I have become
the worst nightmare
to those who
follow the order
of the lukewarms.
I didn't follow
the script.
I survived.
And I lived
to tell the
story.
So we have
come to the
end of this
epic journey,
this series.
And I want
to say something
and people will
say,
I'm not being
honest.
I am being
honest when I
say this.
This is not
about me.
I've known this
information for two
years.
If this was
about me,
would have come
out swinging a
long time ago.
This is about
children.
This is a
war.
It's a cultural,
legal,
mostly spiritual war
against children.
You have to
choose.
I know you're
pitted up against
an enemy.
You never thought
you'd be pitted
up against.
But you've got
to choose.
The only voice
on the side
against children that
I can see
that's coming out
regularly is the
state president.
Is really his
last week.
He is going
to have to
tell you,
and that's what
he's implying and
even saying,
that all this
was done in
the name of
Jesus Christ.
Was it?
Let's go through
it.
Did Jesus Christ
order the PR
committee that Matt
Holland sits on?
I know.
I'll find out
who else is
on it.
Did he order
Matt Holland and
the others on
the PR committee
to say,
let's lie about
Elder Ballard?
Let's make the
world believe that
Elder Ballard could
be so devilish.
He would cut
off the Ballard
family,
his best friends,
children he adores,
my wife,
who he loves,
and he would
cut us off
without saying a
peep to us.
How he did
not.
He did not.
Did Jesus order
the PR committee
and Doug Anderson
to then send
it to a
tabloid magazine,
vice news.
Vice news who's
traditionally been anti
-Morman,
anti-Christian,
anti-pro-Penofilia,
even go ahead.
The state president
also said to
many people,
we have a
record that the
statement itself,
that the famed
other baller defamed
me,
said I never
did project associated
with the church.
He said the
prophet wrote that.
He said it,
he can't deny
it.
said it many
people.
prophet wrote it.
Wow,
what a defamation
to the prophet.
Unless it's true.
Maybe the state
president's telling the
truth.
You can decide.
Did it come
from the prophet?
I make decisions
thinking about the
meeting with my
maker.
Will you come
out and hashtag
retract?
Or is it
groupthink and the
deep state gets
to decide?
Did Jesus Christ
order the PR
committee to keep
Derek Westra out
of the decision?
The guy who's
in charge of
PR crisis?
Why leave him
out?
Without ordered by
Jesus,
let's go down
to September 25th.
Did Jesus order
the state president
to give me
30 minutes?
He gave me
30 minutes.
I have the
letter.
He has 30
minutes to respond
to what?
He didn't give
me a name
of the women
I had sex
with.
He didn't give
me where I
had sex with
him.
I had sex
with him.
Why?
Because the prophet
wrote the statement
that's clearly the
family.
I don't think
you want to
pin on the
prophet,
but he did.
And because he's
my judge in
Israel,
he made sure
I knew that.
When he sat
like this,
I'm your judge
in Israel.
He did.
He's at my
wife and she's
crying.
Did Jesus order
him to do
that?
Was that done
in the name
of Jesus Christ?
Did Jesus order
him to take
a policy in
the name of
the judge of
Israel that completely
inverts and completely
contradicts what doctrine
Cummins 102 says
to all accused
in all cases.
Get to call
the 12.
And if it's
too complex,
only those 12
can decide if
it's too complex
or not complex
enough to have
a hearing.
They didn't get
a chance to
do that.
So in the
name of Jesus
Christ do policies
get to be
inverted where does
that end?
Listen to the
whole thing I
slate more voices.
There's more there.
Was that Beaselbub?
Or that from
Jesus you have
to you have
to decide I'm
talking about the
those of the
order the Luke
warms who you
Jesus name Was
that him talking
or an angel
talking?
Or was it
Beaselbub?
It's clearly not
anyone in the
room.
He only speaks
Listen to the
video he speaks
a couple other
times.
think there's a
woman at the
end and they're
just affirming and
then right before
I talk about
Revelation 36 and
the Luke warms.
He says a
sentence.
That there's hot
and there's cold.
You can decide
by your future
something else.
Then what was
I doing in
Israel?
Tim Ballard a
Christian witness who
just came back
from deep within
Syria He's seen
the evil up
close and is
mission
to save suffering
children and to
tell the truth.
What do you
want?
In Shumatry.
I'm going to
the other Nobody's
going to have
that.
You want to
go back home?
Come and go
back home.
Um...
Go ahead.
You can ahead.
Come on.
I would invite
the State President.
Any video he
does I'll put
on here.
Let him say
that this was
all in the
name of Jesus
Christ.
Did Jesus Christ
order the State
President to take
away the High
Councilman's temple recommend?
Simply because he
was pointing out
that you're contradicting
the words of
Jesus in Section
102.
Was that Jesus
order?
Did Jesus order
that the State
President do this
on the day
of Atomit,
his day,
the sacred day,
where it's forbidden
by biblical law
to excommunicate people?
that Jesus' order?
Did Jesus order
the picture of
him to fall
down on the
State President's floor?
Time
Yes,
that one Jesus
did order.
I attest.
He did order
the picture to
fall.
When the high
councilman said fine,
take my temple
recommend.
It's one of
the other guys.
The state president
says it's all,
it's all the
name of Jesus.
He's right.
He's the only
voice I hear,
so where are
the other voices?
Are you going
to come out
and say,
hashtag retract?
Retract the statement?
Now let me
talk about hashtag
retract.
What's going on?
They have entered
the battlefield.
Okay?
The spiritual,
cultural,
legal battlefield.
I didn't want
them to enter
it.
They entered it.
I had to
go in,
not to defend
myself.
I would have
done that two
years ago.
To defend children.
It's like what
Argentina.
In February of
this year,
I went to
Argentina.
We rescued 20
kids with the
brave,
law enforcement of
Argentina.
The youngest was
four or five
years old.
He was a
child,
six studio.
They were making
it with this
stuff.
That's the first
house we hit
in La Plata.
They didn't have
process
all the videos
we saying,
saw up to
200 videos,
little children in
Argentina being raped,
okay?
I didn't get
to come back
with the hardware.
I went home
back to Utah
get the hardware
for free to
bring it back
so they could
process this quicker
and we could
triangulate and find
the other kids,
then we're going
to come back.
Why?
Because the godless
pro pedophilia,
pro-trafficer media
got a hold
of Doug Anderson's
lie and said,
well,
if the Mormon
church denounced him,
then he must
be a bad
guy.
Well,
that was the
point.
That's what they
wanted.
Obviously they knew
that was the
result of this.
And so those
200 children are
still being raped,
thanks to Doug
Anderson and whoever's
part of that
cabal.
The cloud that
was created by
the cabal of
Doug Anderson and
the PR committee
runs cover for
trafficers.
You understand this?
I wasn't able
to go back
and help rescues
200 kids because
of that cloud
and it follows
me everywhere I
go.
I hope God
will forgive me
for waiting two
years to do
this.
I just had
faith in the
watchman.
Any day they're
going to come
and say,
hey,
we screwed up.
We're going to
retract this statement.
I have done
everything to be
a Matthew 18
compliant,
at least five
attempts,
more than that.
Through through general
authorities,
talk to me,
talk to me.
I ask for
a meeting with
other bedner and
other bedner,
can I trust
them?
I believe they're
true,
watch my other
tower.
They're friends of
mine.
Silence time,
I don't know
what they got
the message.
I did everything,
guys.
D&C 101
says go to
the judge,
go to the
governor,
president.
I've done all
those things as
it would apply
to church governance.
I've gone to
the state president,
the middle guys,
I've gone to
the top guys,
through lawyers,
through direct contact,
crickets,
crickets.
I don't know
who knows what.
I got the
information on the
desk of president
Nelson,
I don't think
he got it.
But of course,
the state president
says he wrote
the statement,
wrote it a
fanatory statement against
me and had
it ordered to
a tabloid magazine.
He has to
stand by that,
or he can
deny it,
repent and say
that's not true,
but he hasn't.
Did Jesus Christ
order the state
president?
I had a
fabulous witness who
was gonna come
in,
he was in
the parking lot
on September 25th,
the day of
the tournament.
He was gonna
come in and
say,
Christa Casey told
me yesterday.
that
gonna come in
and lie to
you,
that Tim hadn't
done anything.
She wanted money.
Her five minutes
of fame,
her New York
Times article she
got.
Her life's not
gonna end well,
I promise you
that.
Two jurisdictions are
criminally investigating her
for the destruction
of justice,
and for being
an accomplished teletrapher.
Is she gonna
be one of
those who comes
out and barishes
me?
Bring it on.
Let's see how
this goes.
Christa Casey went
from hero to
zero.
She actually rescued
a lot of
children and because
she exposed through
her false lawsuits,
details of ongoing
rescue operations,
those operations have
been closed down,
which is why
she will likely
be charged in
at least two
countries for being
an accomplished teletrapher
and obstruction of
justice.
And this is
the witness that
these people in
the church are
gonna use to
try to embarrass
me.
We are leaving
Cancun,
work in Cancun,
via Cousin de
Mell,
Subdams,
several targets,
and for part
time,
I'm Christo Casey
playing my girlfriend
and we had
very serious rules
as always.
No kissing on
the lips,
no touching private
parts outside or
inside including.
And I attest
that we kept
those rules,
we didn't do
any of these
things to each
other.
Absolutely,
I'm also from
that too.
And we were
very respectful to
one another.
She treated,
she was a
lady the whole
time.
I agree.
I'm to put
both of his
eyes together.
totally respectful.
Yes.
Absolutely.
Okay,
rules.
Alright.
We're the record.
This is my
acknowledgement.
I'm Christo Casey
and I went
down to BVI
during that time
and in Cosmell
from May 25th
to June 8th
of 2021.
In Cosmell and
in BVI played
as part of
the couple rules
with Tim and
just wanted to
recapped
of the boundaries
there,
and I will
read them no
kissing on the
lips,
touching or exposing
private parts,
including breasts and
dine genitalia,
and any other
thing you can
imagine.
We kept really
strict boundaries.
that's my acknowledgement.
You all want
to play Russian
Relate with Jesus.
You want to
cross the veil
and see what
he says about
all this?
This was done
in his name,
guys.
His name.
The church told
Governor Cox that
it did come
from him,
even though they
lied to their
people on the
switchboard and say
it didn't come
from us.
What's that?
Did Jesus order
that?
Do be his
messaging?
Earlier this week,
Governor Cox read
the story from
Vice.
The church issued
a strong condemnation
of Ballard,
saying his behavior
was morally unacceptable.
I reached out
to the church
personally,
and I was
assured that that
did come from
the church,
that it had
been vetted through
all the normal
church processes.
This is Christ
of Latter-day,
thanks.
hasn't
official statement right
as of yet.
This place to
check is the
Church newsroom website.
Whenever any statements
made that are
official from the
hub,
they will be
posted there.
The Church has
not made any
official statement.
You have reached
the Church Communication
Department of the
Church of Jesus
Christ of Latter
-day Saints.
The Church of
Jesus Christ of
Latter-day Saints,
how can I
help you?
Aside now about
the article,
unfortunately,
the Church does
not have an
official statement.
In September of
2023,
I was with
Tim in Plymouth,
Massachusetts,
when we learned
about the Church
statement device news.
Tim and I
have dealt with
vice news for
years,
were used to
their misinformation campaigns,
and frankly,
they're a disgusting
magazine.
I wouldn't think
that the Church
would even want
to cooperate with
an article published
in Viscenium.
So I had
no time reasons
to doubt this
statement.
couple
later,
we were then
in Washington,
D.C.
at the Lincoln
Summer Cottage.
This is where
Abraham Lincoln and
his family would
spend time away
from the White
House.
It's where he
actually penned the
emancipation,
proclamation.
It was there
that I decided
that I would
call the church
to the New
Kaisen Department,
just to verify.
I thought it
could be no
harm in that.
When I called,
I asked for
Doug Anderson.
I got through
to him.
He hung up
when I told
him who I
was and what
I was calling
about.
I called back.
They said they
could put me
in touch with
Tom Owens,
who worked with
Doug in the
Kaisen Department.
Tom told me
what I was
expecting here,
which is it
wasn't a statement
from the church.
He said the
church doesn't make
anonymous statements.
Whether or not
that's true,
I don't know
that
game that he
was playing with
me or he
was maybe just
misinformed himself.
But he certainly
confirmed what I
thought,
which it wasn't
an authentic statement.
I thought this
was important to
combat the misinformation
put out by
Faisalun.
So I decided
to record it.
I called back.
I couldn't have
long to get
through to him.
But other people
working within the
department confirmed the
same thing,
which you heard
in the course
of this film,
where they denied
that it was
a statement from
the church.
We did learn
that it is
a statement from
the church.
I don't know
why they were
playing a game
with us that
day.
It seems like
if it were
such a good
statement,
everything about it
was so good
and approved,
according to protocols
and so forth.
Why they would
need to backtrack
or deny in
the first place.
Or maybe,
you know,
it wasn't a
statement that had
been run through
all the channels
and protocols.
it's possible they
were just misinformed
themselves because their
department heads had
not briefed them
on the authenticity
of that statement.
I guess we'll
find out through
depositions.
You know,
that's a course
that Tim and
his attorneys can
pursue.
I think there
are other reasons
that I had
to believe this
was an authentic
statement from the
church.
One is just
full of falsehoods
that just seem
incongruent with what
I believe the
department of the
church I belong
to would do.
You know,
Tim never did.
projects,
indoors of society
with the church.
mean that's where
a lot of
projects unfortunately the
references to those
projects are mostly
deleted as reporting
by the Salt
Lake Tribune and
others made.
The Tim Hughes
Elder Ballard's name
not or for
a personal game.
I've been with
Tim since 2013
really.
Tim has never
misused Elder Ballard's
name not for
in moral purposes
and not for
a personal game.
know where is
the proof?
You know we've
been through litigation
now for three
years and I've
seen a lot
of the back
and
forth at no
point is anyone
produced any proof
that Tim had
misused Elder Ballard's
name.
So I don't
know unless you
some
rather than that,
that you'll pull
out.
I don't see
how you can
eat around that
one.
How do you
talk about integrity
in conference?
How do you
do it?
It breaks my
children's hearts.
Wait a minute.
They're not showing
integrity.
They're not even
coming to the
table.
What do they
want?
They're going to
wait for the
arm of God,
guess,
to come out.
That's my position.
We'll see who's
right.
And my question
to all of
you.
Are you stuck
by the deep
state?
At the end
of the day,
you're on the
to the veil
alone.
What if you
put up a
hashtag,
retract?
Retract,
retract the statement,
retract the cover.
This is horrible
that I have
to say this,
but it's true.
When I go
into a country,
my enemies are
Doug Anderson,
Lai,
Cabal,
and the traffickers,
because they're working
together.
You see what
I'm saying.
But this is
their war to
fight and they
pick me as
their enemy.
So we're on
the battlefield,
guys.
We're on the
battlefield and here's
what I'm going
to do after
two years.
Hidden War is
a docu film
that is an
amazing operation.
We blow through
six countries studying
in the war
in Ukraine.
And three continents
ends in Latin
America.
The whole world's
going to watch
it.
I think it
could be as
big as it
out to freedom
or bigger.
I remember you're
thinking,
is this possible?
People do this?
You consider the
fact that human
trafficking is $150
billion in your
business.
The question people
to think about
it and go
to is,
how are you
getting that many
kids?
How do you
find that many
kids and people
to sell?
This is how.
And I'm going
to start in
mid-October,
a tour throughout
all these countries.
And I promise
you that every
country I go
into,
we're going be
planning operations in
conjunction.
And everywhere I
go,
the Doug Anderson
Cabal lie will
follow me.
So I will
attack it everywhere
I go.
Every,
I promise you
I'm going to
do this.
This is going
to be a
major part of
my campaign because
that lie equals
traffickers because they're
using it to
run cover for
pedophiles and traffickers.
It's lunches to
Argentina
still being raped.
It's all over
the world.
This lie has
gone everywhere.
Why can't you
retract?
Oh,
I remember you,
we don't apologize.
Now,
who is they?
Who am I
talking about?
I'm not talking
about the church
in general.
I'm talking about
a deep state.
people who follow
the order of
the lukewarm.
Now,
I will say
this because I'm
Matthew 18,
compliant.
don't see the
churches in my
enemy.
I've shown them
everything.
I'm trying to
be honest.
They know what
I know that
I'm not yet
revealing.
I know whose
fingerprints are on
this thing.
I know how
high up it
goes.
If they escalate,
I'll escalate.
I'm not afraid
of the puny
arm of men.
I'm not afraid
of those who
follow the order
of the lukewarm.
I'm not.
I will die
on this hill.
Will they die
on this hill?
on the hill
saying that Jesus
told me to
give Tim 30
minutes and not
even tell him
what he did?
That Jesus told
me to keep
the witnesses from
coming in.
We are at
war to protect
children.
They invited the
war,
not me.
I sat quietly
for two years
trying to be
Matthew 18,
compliant.
Consider
title liberty moment
right now.
I'm staking it
in ground for
children for families
for wife my
wife and my
children Who were
the initial collateral
damage they knew
that all of
the PR committee
knew that They
knew I'd lose
my job.
They knew I'd
leave my reputation
They're shocked that
I'm alive right
now.
They were supposed
to bury me
along with the
lie Well,
they didn't count
on Jesus Christ
and they didn't
count on my
wife I just
want to say
that at the
end of the
day you go
through the veil
by yourself
And you will
have to answer
to the Lord
for what you
did Did you
drink bonhoeffer found
himself in that
place?
During World War
II and you
already said about
this.
said silence in
the face of
evil is evil
itself God will
not hold us
guiltless not to
speak is to
speak not to
act is to
act and as
William Liverpool said
You can no
longer say you
didn't know so
now you know
the battle lines
have been drawn
and I choose
to be like
Captain Moroni from
Alma 44
gives their Hamina
every chance you
can take.
Give their Hamina
every possibility to
repent and stop
hurting children and
families.
Tyler Liberty,
Zairahem to continue
to let the
cloud go,
lies go.
He continued to
fight children.
So I will
end this episode.
I will end
this series by
invoking the words
of Captain Moroni.
We are now
in a cultural,
spiritual,
legal war.
We are in
it,
and I,
like Captain Moroni,
say to you,
be hold.
We shall end
this conflict.
There's a man
going round taking
names.
And he decides
who to free
and who to
blame.
Everybody
Everybody won't be
treated all the
same.
There'll be a
golden letter reaching
down.
Thank
the
comes around.
The hairs on
your arm will
stand up at
the terror in
each sip and
in each sip.
For you partake
of that last
offer cup or
disillusioned to the
potter's ground.
When the man
who comes around.
Hear the trumpets
hear the fibers.
100 million angels
singing.
Multitudes are marching
to the big
cuddle drum.
Voice is calling,
voice is crying.
Some are born
and some are
dying.
It's our final
mega's king and
come.
the
in the thorn
tree.
The virgins are
all trimming their
wicks.
The whirlwind is
in the thorn
tree.
It's hard for
thee to kick
against the bricks.
Till Armageddon,
no shalom,
no shalom.
Then the father
hen will call
his chickens home.
The wise men
will bow down
before the throne.
And at his
feet they'll cast
their golden crowns.
When the man
comes around,
whoever is unjust,
let him be
unjust.
And I heard
a voice in
the midst of
the four beasts.
And I looked
and behold a
pale horse.
And his name
is said on
him was death.